do you believe the robots are going to
你认为机器人会……
raise our kids because it feels like a
我们养育孩子，因为这感觉就像……
slippery slope well it's not too far
滑坡效应，其实离我们还不远。
away from us and we never evolve to want
远离我们，我们永远不会进化到想要
children look the fertility rates are
孩子们看起来生育率很高
going way down a lot of countries are
很多国家都在大幅下滑
going to be literally half their size by
到那时，体型将只有现在的一半。
the year 2100 because they're shrinking
到2100年，因为它们正在萎缩。
so fast and the list is really long
速度太快了，而且清单很长。
about how hard it is to raise the child
关于养育孩子有多么艰难
into today's world so you want to make
进入当今世界，所以你想……
having kids to be as much of the plus as
生孩子应该是一件好事，就像……
it possibly can be and with the perfect
这或许可以做到，而且堪称完美。
robot Nanny you would never worry at all
有了机器人保姆，你再也不用担心了。
interesting Dr William Von hipple is the
有趣的是，威廉·冯·希普尔博士是
world-renowned evolutionary psychologist
世界知名的进化心理学家
who has spent decades studying and
他花费数十年时间研究和
finding the answers to how instincts
寻找本能的答案
that once helped our ancestors survive
这曾经帮助我们的祖先生存下来。
still drive us today often in ways we
时至今日，它仍然以各种方式驱动着我们
don't even realize as a species what are
作为一个物种，我们甚至都没有意识到什么是……
we getting wrong well young people
我们年轻人做错了
having less sex than they were 20 years
性生活频率比20年前低了。
ago marriage are steadily going down and
过去的结婚率一直在稳步下降，
our lives are so much better but we're
我们的生活好多了，但是我们
not any happier and part of the problem
并没有更快乐，而且也是问题的一部分。
is that we're constantly choosing to do
那就是我们不断地选择去做某事。
our own thing rather than connect so
我们自己的事情，而不是联系，所以
here's the data in 18501 in 100 of
以下是 18501 年 100% 的数据
Americans lived alone now it's 1 in
美国人现在独居的比例为1/10。
seven in the 1970s one in three people
20世纪70年代，每三个人中就有七个人患有这种疾病。
spent time with their neighbors now
现在他们花时间和邻居们在一起。
that's completely reversed now let's
现在情况完全相反了，我们来……
dive a little deeper 50% of humanity now
再深入一点，现在人类的50%
lives in the city then they're about 25%
居住在城市里的大约占25%。
wealthier than people who live in the
比住在……的人更富有
country and yet the data shows people in
国家，然而数据显示，人们在
the country are happier because cities
全国人民更幸福，因为城市
are all about I want to do what I want
一切都围绕着“我想做什么就做什么”展开。
and the problem is that we can't
问题是我们不能
introduce social connection into our
将社交联系融入我们的生活中
life willy-nilly or we won't keep it up
生活要随心所欲，否则我们就坚持不下去。
so what do we do about that two things
那么，我们该如何处理这两件事呢？
one and then what does evolution tell us
首先，进化论告诉我们什么？
about how to attract the opposite sex
关于如何吸引异性
you want honest signals of quality and
你想要的是真实可靠的质量信号，
bizar Le one of the clearest honest
古怪的Le是最清晰诚实的人之一
signals for men to demonstrate for women
向男性发出示威的信号
as
作为
I have been forced into a bet with my
我被迫和我打赌
team we're about to hit 10 million
团队，我们即将突破1000万大关！
subscribers on YouTube which is our
我们在 YouTube 上的订阅者，这是我们的
biggest Milestone ever thanks to all of
感谢大家，这是我们迄今为止取得的最大里程碑！
you and we want to have a massive party
你和我们都想举办一场盛大的派对。
for the people that have worked on this
致所有参与这项工作的人们
show for years behind the scenes so they
多年来一直在幕后工作，所以他们
said to me Steve for every new
史蒂夫对我说，每一个新的
subscriber we get in the next 30 days
我们将在未来 30 天内获得订阅用户
can $1 be given to our celebration fund
能否捐赠1美元给我们的庆祝基金？
for the entire team and I've agreed to
为了整个团队，我已经同意了。
the bet so if you want to say thank you
所以，如果你想表达感谢，就打个赌吧
to the team behind the scenes at di of
致幕后团队
here all you've got to do is hit the
你只需要点击
Subscribe button so actually this this
订阅按钮，所以实际上是这个
is the first time I'm going to tell you
这是我第一次告诉你
not to subscribe because it might end up
不要订阅，因为它最终可能会……
costing me an
让我损失了
[Applause]
[掌声]
[Music]
[音乐]
awful Dr William Von
可怕的威廉·冯博士
hipple what have you spent the last four
希普尔，你过去四个月都花了些什么？
Decades of your life doing oh mostly in
你生命中的几十年都在做着……哦，大部分时间都在……
the lab trying to figure out why humans
实验室试图弄清为什么人类
do what they do what do you mean by what
做他们做的事，你这话是什么意思？
we why we do what we do well I'm super
我们为什么能做好我们所做的事情，我超级棒
interested in not just what we do but
不仅对我们做的事情感兴趣，而且
what the underlying cause might be you
根本原因可能是什么？
know why does um having a nice dinner
知道为什么他要享用一顿美味的晚餐吗？
with your friends make you happy it just
和朋友在一起会让你快乐，就是这样
seems inherently obvious well of course
这似乎显而易见，当然
it does but there's got to be a reason
确实如此，但这其中肯定有原因。
for that and there's got to be a reason
这样做肯定有原因。
that it's very different if it's not
如果不是这样，那就大不相同了。
with your friends or if it's different
和朋友一起，或者如果情况不同的话。
kinds of foods or you know the list goes
食物种类，或者你知道，清单很长
on it could be anything and so what I
它可以是任何东西，那又怎样？
try to do is I I look into our
我尝试做的就是调查我们的
evolutionary history I say how did we
进化史，我说我们是如何……
get here what were the factors that made
来到这里的原因是什么？
us success and the things that made us
我们的成功以及成就我们的因素
successful are likely to as a species
成功的物种很可能
are likely to be the things that make us
这些很可能就是让我们成为这样的人的原因。
happy because happiness is one of the
感到快乐，因为快乐是其中之一
tools that Evolution uses to guide us in
进化论用来指导我们的工具
the direction that it wants us to go you
它想让我们朝哪个方向走？
know Evolution has no foresight but
要知道进化论没有预见性，但是
evolution um shapes us the way we are
进化塑造了我们现在的样子
and the things that make us successful
以及那些让我们成功的事情
those ancestors who enjoy doing those
那些喜欢做这些事的祖先
things are going to be the ancestors who
事情将会由祖先们来决定。
have more kids then the ancestors who
比祖先生的孩子更多
enjoyed doing things that were bad for
喜欢做那些对他人有害的事情
them what is evolution so evolution is
他们问：什么是进化？所以进化是
as mind this process and all it is is if
请注意这个过程，而这一切的关键在于……
if it's the case that not everybody has
如果并非每个人都拥有
the exact same number of kids and if
孩子数量完全相同，而且如果
it's the case that not everybody's kids
并非所有人的孩子都是如此
survive at the exact same rates now we
现在我们以完全相同的速率生存下来
have the room for evolution because
有发展的空间，因为
there's variability something about me
我身上有一种变化性。
caused me to have lots of children that
导致我生了很多孩子
survived in the Next Generation and
在下一代中幸存下来
something about this other guy caused
关于另一个人的某些事情引起了
him not to have any maybe and so
他可能没有任何顾虑，所以
whatever there is about me that's
我身上无论有什么特质，那就是
heritable will will be well represented
遗嘱将得到充分体现。
in the Next Generation and about him
在下一代以及关于他的
poor guy even if he's wonderful those
可怜的家伙，即使他很棒
are gone and so Evolution just works
它们已经消失了，所以进化论才得以奏效。
with whatever's there and the things
用那里的一切以及那些东西
that make you a success either because
那会让你获得成功，要么是因为……
they're just useful in that environment
它们在那种环境下就很有用。
or they are a new mutation that turns
或者它们是一种新的突变，会发生变化
out to have great value they becoming
事实证明，它们具有巨大的价值
they become over represented in the gene
它们在基因中过度表达
pool and so Evolution can create things
池，因此进化可以创造事物
that are species typical all of our
这些都是我们所有物种的典型特征。
species have that we all have two eyes
物种共有两只眼睛，而我们所有人都有两只眼睛。
you know that's just part and parcel of
你知道，这只是其中的一部分
Being Human and then it can make
身为人类，然后它就能……
variability within humans and there's
人类内部存在差异，而且还有……
tons of variability in our size our
我们的尺寸存在很大的差异
stature all sorts of things about us and
地位，关于我们的一切，以及
why should we we look at Evolution for
我们为什么要研究进化论呢？
answers on human happiness and success
关于人类幸福和成功的答案
and as a sort of of a guiding compass
就像一个指路明灯
for what we should be doing with our
我们应该如何利用我们的
Lives why is evolution the place to look
为什么进化是寻找生命的地方？
there's lots of tiny answers to that
这个问题有很多细小的答案。
question but they don't necessarily link
问题是，但它们之间不一定存在联系。
together very well so people say You'
你们相处得很好，所以人们说你们
probably heard oh Express gratitude
可能听到了哦，表达感激之情
that'll make you happy if you Express
如果你表达出来，你会很高兴的。
gratitude why why should that make you
感恩，为什么？为什么这会让你心生感激？
happy if if there's a good reason for it
如果理由正当，我会很高兴。
then it makes sense that we should do it
那么我们就有理由这样做了。
and it should have some kind of a
它应该具有某种……
lasting effect and so every single thing
持久的影响，以及每一件事
that people tell you this will make you
人们告诉你这样做会让你……
happy there has to been a reason it must
很高兴这件事肯定有原因。
have done something for our ancestors or
为我们的祖先做过某事，或者
it's what um my colleague Robert triers
这就是我的同事罗伯特·特里尔斯
calls a phenotypic Indulgence which
称之为表型放纵
means it mimics something that was good
这意味着它模仿了某种美好的东西。
for our ancestors so for example you
例如，对于我们的祖先来说，你
know video games are pretty novel right
你知道电子游戏是很新颖的东西吧？
they may mimic things that were super
它们可能会模仿那些曾经非常强大的事物。
important for our ancestors and and give
这对我们的祖先来说很重要，并且给予
us the same endorphin rush or whatever
我们都会经历同样的内啡肽激增或其他什么感觉。
even though they're not actually
即使它们实际上并非如此
necessarily good for us anymore junk
对我们来说，这不再是垃圾，也未必是好事了。
food is the same it's loaded fat salt
食物都一样，都是高脂肪、高盐的。
sugar those are the kinds of things that
糖之类的东西
are ancestors s it all the time uh we
祖先一直都是这样，呃，我们
don't need them anymore but but they
不再需要它们了，但是它们
were super important back then and so it
它们在当时非常重要，所以
makes us happy when we eat those things
吃这些东西会让我们感到快乐。
as a evolutionary psychologist and
作为一名进化心理学家和
someone who understands where we've come
一个了解我们一路走来的人
from and therefore are sort of innate
因此，它们是某种程度上的内在属性。
behaviors and needs and desires and so
行为、需求、欲望等等
on what are the things that we're
关于我们正在做的事情
getting wrong as a species at the moment
目前我们人类这个物种正在犯错。
from your view so the big thing that I
从你的角度来看，最重要的一点是……
think we're getting wrong is the balance
我觉得我们做错的地方在于平衡。
that we maintain between autonomy and
我们在自主性和
connection and the we can can talk about
联系以及我们可以谈论
why this is but the big thing that we've
为什么会这样，但最重要的是我们已经……
got wrong right now is doing what I want
现在做错事了，但我正在做我想做的事
to do right now rather than connecting
现在就做，而不是连接
autonomy is all about self-governance
自治的本质在于自我管理。
what do I feel like doing right now and
我现在想做什么？
everybody's going off in their own
每个人都各自散去
Direction and this is not good for us
方向对我们不利。
it's not good for our happiness it's not
这不利于我们的幸福，这不好
going to for us in a host of different
对我们来说，这将在许多方面都不同。
ways that mistake is particularly
这种错误的方式尤其如此
problematic if you live in the west if
如果你住在西部，那就麻烦了。
you're well educated and if you live in
你受过良好的教育，如果你住在
cities and if you're wealthy so if
城市，如果你很富有，那么如果
you're Western wealthy urbanite well
你是西方富裕的都市人，嗯
educated you've got that problem in
受过教育的人也会遇到这个问题
Spades and by autonomy you mean the sort
黑桃，你说的自主权是指那种
of individualism where I don't need
我不需要个人主义。
anybody anymore it's about me it's about
现在跟任何人无关了，一切都与我有关，一切都与我有关。
my gratification what I want now versus
我的满足感与我现在想要的东西之间的对比
others and a community a tribe that's
其他人以及一个社区，一个部落，
right and it doesn't even need to feel
没错，甚至不需要感觉。
like a big thing it's just let's say you
就像一件大事，比如说你
and I are buddies and we're going to go
我和他是好朋友，我们要去
to a movie and you say I really want to
去看电影，你说你真的很想
hit a romc com and I'm like I really
看了部浪漫喜剧，我就想我真的
want to see an action movie we go okay
想看动作片，我们就去。
I'll see if the movie's over we just go
我看看电影是不是结束了，如果结束了我们就走。
our own ways and so it could be trivial
我们各行其是，所以这可能微不足道。
little things but it's across our lives
虽是小事，却贯穿我们的生活。
we're continually setting aside our
我们不断地把我们的
connections to do what we want and what
建立联系以实现我们的目标和目的
are the some of the sort of stats that
这些是一些统计数据的类型……
illuminate this problem from that make
从这个角度阐明这个问题
it clear that this is actually happening
很明显，这种情况确实正在发生。
in your view so there's a number of them
在你看来，所以有很多这样的例子。
um you can look at the propensity of
嗯，你可以看看这种倾向
Americans to live alone we've got good
美国人独居，我们有很好的
data in the States but the picture is
美国的数据，但情况是
the same in every industrialized country
每个工业化国家都是如此
in 1850 1% of Americans lived alone now
1850年，1%的美国人独居；现在
it's so one in 100 now it's one in seven
以前是百分之一，现在是七分之一了。
so you know here we are 170 years L 175
所以你知道，我们现在是170周年，L 175
years later and it used to be crazy rare
多年以后，这种情况曾经极其罕见。
and now it's one in seven is pretty darn
现在七分之一的比例已经相当高了。
common if you look in in the 1970s when
如果你回顾20世纪70年代，就会发现这很常见。
I was a kid um about 30% of people saw
我小时候，大约有30%的人看到过。
their neighbors got together with their
他们的邻居们聚在一起
neighbors not visually seeing them but
邻居们虽然看不见他们，但
got together with their neighbors um at
和邻居们聚在一起
least a few times a week and only one in
至少每周几次，而且只有一次
five pretty much never saw their
五个人几乎从未见过他们
neighbors at all now that's completely
现在完全没有邻居了
reversed now only one and five are
现在反过来了，只剩下1和5了。
seeing their neighbors regularly used to
经常见到邻居
be one and three and now one and three
曾经是1和3，现在是1和3
never get together with their neighbors
从不和邻居聚会
at all so we're we're moving away from
完全如此，所以我们正在远离
each other in a host of different ways
以多种不同的方式相互影响
even married couples are spending less
即使是已婚夫妇的开支也在减少。
time together they're it's weird we
他们在一起的时间很奇怪，我们
don't understand what they're doing but
不明白他们在做什么，但是
what I suspect is happening is that
我怀疑正在发生的事情是……
let's say that you both want to exercise
假设你们俩都想锻炼
and she kind of likes to jog and you
她挺喜欢慢跑的，而你
kind of like to lift weights we used to
有点像我们以前举重那样
sort of do those together off for a jog
把这些事情一起做完，然后去慢跑。
and then a little weightlifting but now
然后又练了一会儿举重，但现在
with 10 zillion options you go to your
面对十亿种选择，你走向你的
gym and she goes to hers and you just
她去健身房，你也去健身房。
don't see each other as much as you used
不像以前那样经常见面了。
to so across our lives we're spending
因此，在我们的一生中，我们花费大量时间
far more time alone and if look at
更多独处的时间，如果看看
marriage and
婚姻和
cohabitation in some parts of the world
世界某些地区的同居生活
they haven't changed at all but in the
他们一点都没变，但是在……
wealthy Parts United States western
美国西部富裕地区
Europe they're steadily going down so
欧洲的情况正在稳步恶化，所以
it's not just well people aren't getting
不仅仅是人们没有得到
married because they're living together
他们因为同居而结婚。
outside of marriage if you lump all
婚外情，如果你把所有……都归为一类的话
those together they're steadily going
他们一起稳步前进
down over the last 50 years and why does
过去50年里，这种趋势一直在下降，原因何在？
that matter well the question is first
那件事，嗯，问题是……首先
on the one hand it's not a problem at
一方面，这并不是问题。
all you vote with your feet do what you
你们用脚投票，做你们该做的
want of course right but on the other
当然想要是对的，但另一方面
hand what if it's making you unhappy
如果它让你不开心怎么办？
what if you think you're doing this this
如果你认为你正在做这件事呢？
because it's going to make you happy but
因为它会让你快乐，但是
in fact you're wrong and you keep making
事实上你错了，而且你还在继续犯错。
decisions over and over again that make
反复做出的决定
you increasingly less happy and that's
你越来越不快乐，这就是……
what I think is happening here I think
我认为这里发生的事情是这样的……
every one of those decisions is an error
这些决定每一个都是错误。
and are are there any stats or data that
是否有任何统计数据或资料可以佐证？
proves
证明
that we're getting this wrong in terms
我们在这点上理解错了
of Happiness are there other tribes or
幸福之外还有其他部落吗？
communities or people in history that
历史上那些社群或人物
were doing it differently and had higher
他们的做法不同，而且收入更高。
rates of Happiness so the best example
幸福指数，最好的例子
in my mind is if you look at unto
在我看来，如果你仔细观察……
gathers and so uh there's a team that
聚集在一起，所以，呃，有一个团队
went to the hodza people who live
去了居住在那里的霍扎人那里。
outside would live Kenya and Tanzania
外面的人会住在肯尼亚和坦桑尼亚。
they're as close as we know to what our
它们与我们所知的最接近的就是
ancestors would look like and in my mind
在我看来，祖先们大概就是这个样子。
they're perfect because they're also
它们之所以完美，是因为它们也是
where it all happened the hza still
一切发生的地方，hza 仍然
lived where Humanity evolved so of
生活在人类进化如此迅速的地方
course it could have been different a
当然，情况也可能有所不同。
quar to million years ago but it could
数千年至数百万年前，但它可能
have been exactly like they live today
他们过去的生活状态和现在一模一样。
and so when you look at the hza this
所以当你查看 hza 时，这个
particular team ask them over the last
某个团队在过去一段时间里问过他们这个问题。
week have you been happy sometimes happy
这周你有没有感到快乐过？有时候快乐？
and sometimes sad sad over 90% of the
有时令人悲伤，超过90%的人
hza said happy that was their answer
hza说很高兴那是他们的答案。
answer when you ask westerners that same
当你问西方人同样的问题时，他们会给出同样的答案。
question you get about 50% will say
你被问到的问题中，大约有 50% 的人会说
happy over the last week and so the data
过去一周我很开心，数据也是如此。
suggests the hodza are literally happier
这表明霍扎人确实更快乐。
than we are now they they bury almost
比我们现在所处的环境更糟，他们几乎把我们都埋葬了。
half their children they they live a
他们一半的孩子住在……
life where they've got no savings
他们过着没有积蓄的生活
whatsoever they've got nothing in the
无论如何，他们什么都没有。
bank they don't know what tomorrow's
银行方面，他们不知道明天会发生什么。
going to bring they don't know if
打算带他们来，他们不知道是否
tomorrow's Hunt's going to be successful
明天的狩猎活动将会成功。
they have so many cultural rules that
他们有很多文化规则，
they have to abide by that requires them
他们必须遵守那项规定。
to be constantly connected with each
与每个人保持持续联系
other because they rely on each other
因为他们彼此依赖。
like an insurance policy and yet they
就像一份保险单，然而它们
they look a lot happier than we are now
他们现在看起来比我们快乐多了。
we can see those same stats in in
我们可以在其他位置看到同样的统计数据。
different modern contexts but in my mind
不同的现代语境，但在我看来
that's the stat that blows me away and
这项数据让我震惊不已。
why do you think they are happier than
你认为他们为什么比别人更快乐
us you think it's because they're living
你认为这是因为他们生活的地方吗？
in tribes and groups or is it something
在部落和群体中，或者还有其他什么？
else well I think it's the balance that
否则，我认为关键在于平衡。
they've struck and I think it's that
他们发动了袭击，我认为就是这样。
balance between connection and autonomy
连接与自主之间的平衡
and so that's really the focus of this
所以这才是重点所在。
of my second book is so I'll tell you
我的第二本书是这样的，所以我会告诉你。
how I got there how's that so I'm
我是怎么到那儿的？怎么样？所以我是
visiting a friend of mine also named
去拜访我的一位也叫
Stephen and uh he struck it rich and he
斯蒂芬，呃，他发了财，他
invites me over I'm like this is going
他邀请我过去，我心想这下可糟了。
to be cool I'm gonna see how the Super
为了耍酷，我要看看超级
Rich Live and it was over the top you
Rich Live，真是太棒了！
know this monumentally huge apartment
了解一下这套规模庞大的公寓
beautiful view Cooks over there Maids
景色优美，厨师在那边，女佣们也在那里。
over there Etc and so I turned him I'm
那边等等，所以我把他转过来，我是
like Steve man your life is over the top
史蒂夫，你的生活简直太精彩了！
and he's like yeah it seems that way but
他回答说，是啊，看起来是这样，但是
it's just not and I'm like seriously and
根本不是这样，我真的觉得很无语。
he goes yeah I'm no happier than I used
他说：“是啊，我并不比以前更快乐。”
to be and he starts listing off all the
他开始列举所有的
problems that he's facing and I'm like
他面临的问题，我当时就想：
how could this person not appreciate
这个人怎么可能不懂得欣赏呢？
these amazing benefit that he has how
他所拥有的这些惊人的好处是如何
how is it even possible that a person
这怎么可能呢？一个人
could have so much and not just feel
可以拥有很多，而不仅仅是感觉。
happy about it every day and I have to
每天都为此感到高兴，我必须如此。
admit I felt the sense of superiority I
我承认我当时感到了一种优越感。
thought to myself if I were crazy rich
我心想，如果我是个超级富豪的话。
like you were I'd be happy every day I
如果像你一样，我每天都会很开心。
would appreciate this lifestyle that ID
会欣赏这种生活方式的ID
earned rather than just taking it for
靠自己努力争取，而不是仅仅索取。
granted so then fast forward a few years
好吧，那就快进几年。
this is a decade or so ago fast forward
这是大约十年前的事了，快进到
a few years and I'm reading Frank
几年后，我在读弗兰克的作品。
Marlo's wonderful book on the hza and
马洛关于hza的精彩著作
I'm reading about their lives and and
我正在阅读关于他们生活和
and how content they are and I'm like
他们有多满意，我就想
holy cow I'm just like my friend Steve
我的天哪，我简直跟我朋友史蒂夫一模一样！
compared to them I'm a multi-millionaire
跟他们比起来，我可是个千万富翁。
I don't my when my kids get sick I'm off
我不介意孩子生病时我请假。
to the doctor immediately I don't have
我没有立即去看医生的资格。
this horrible life for a bury Mo own
这种可怕的生活，只为埋葬莫。
children I have savings I don't have to
我有积蓄，不必为孩子操心
worry about tomorrow I get up and get
担心明天的事，我起床后就……
something out of the fridge I'm
我从冰箱里拿出点东西来
comfortable when it's hot I'm
天气热的时候我很舒服
comfortable when it's cold the list goes
寒冷天气里感到舒适，清单如下
on compared to them I'm a zillionaire
跟他们比起来，我简直就是个亿万富翁。
and yet they're probably happier than we
然而，他们可能比我们更快乐。
are and so I realized it's not just
是，所以我意识到这不仅仅是
Steve it's all of us you know we're
史蒂夫，你知道，是我们所有人。
failing to appreciate this amazing
未能欣赏到这令人惊叹的
modern world we live in and you know
我们生活在现代世界，你知道
even if we look back hundred years I'm
即使我们回顾一百年前，我仍然
years ago a quarter of the children died
多年前，四分之一的儿童死亡
by the 150 years ago a quarter of the
150年前，四分之一的
children died by the time they turned
孩子们在他们长大成人之前就已经去世了。
five you know that you you got a the flu
五，你知道你得了流感
or you got you know typhus there was
或者你得了斑疹伤寒，你知道的。
zillion diseases that just killed us
无数种疾病夺走了我们的生命。
when we were young um women died in
当我们年轻的时候，嗯，女性去世了
child birth at rates way skyro compared
与 Skyro 相比，分娩率
to today so it's not just looking back
直到今天，这不仅仅是回顾过去。
at un togethers but even looking back
虽然我们在一起，但即使回首往事
recently our lives are so much better
最近我们的生活好多了
but we're not any happier if anything I
但我们并没有更快乐，反而更不快乐了。
think we're maybe a little less happy
感觉我们可能没那么快乐了。
and is that just because we don't take a
难道仅仅是因为我们不接受
moment to be grateful or is there
有值得感恩的时刻吗？或者还有其他什么时刻吗？
something fundamental about the way
方式的某些根本性问题
we're pursuing happiness look I think
我们追求的是幸福，你看，我认为
it's multicausal whenever you get a big
每当出现大问题时，它都是多因果关系的。
effect like that like if you take those
就像服用那些药物后会产生那种效果一样
data seriously that I told you about the
我认真地告诉过你关于数据的事情
hodza they're basically twice as happy
hodza 他们基本上快乐程度翻了一番。
as we are now that's such a big effect
就目前的情况来看，这会产生如此大的影响。
it has to be multia has to be a lot
它必须是多面的，必须很多。
going on there and of course these
那里正在发生什么，当然还有这些
changes happen over Generations they
变化是几代人共同作用的结果。
don't happen overnight if they happen
即使发生，也不会一夜之间发生。
overnight I think it'd be super obvious
我觉得一夜之间就会变得非常明显。
to us what have gone wrong but I think
对我们来说，到底出了什么问题？但我认为
what what it returns us to is this
它最终带给我们的，是这个。
problem that we were talking about
我们刚才讨论的问题
before about autonomy in connection and
在联系中关于自主性之前
so let's take City living as a for
所以，让我们以城市生活为例……
example remember earlier I said that
例如，还记得我之前说过吗？
cities are about 5,000 years old so
城市大约有5000年的历史了。
human beings have been moving to cities
人类一直在向城市迁移
for 5,000 years by 1960 you had one
五千年后，到1960年，你只有一个
people out of every three living in
每三个居住在
cities in in the world and by 2007 was
世界上的城市，到2007年是
the year we crossed over 50% of humanity
那一年，人类人口增长了50%以上。
now lives in the city so people have
现在住在城里，所以人们有
been voting with their feet for a long
他们长期以来一直用脚投票。
time but by long time I mean hundred so
时间，但我说的“很长一段时间”是指几百年。
years and mass moving to cities now
多年来，大规模人口迁移到城市
there's lots of reasons for it we can
有很多原因可以解释这一点。
talk about it but one of the costs is
谈论它，但其中一项成本是
happiness if you look at happiness and
如果你审视幸福，你会发现幸福是……
you divide people up by whether they
你根据他们是否……将人们分成两类。
live into in cities um communities over
居住在城市或社区中
a quarter million or in the country
二十五万或在该国
communities less than 2 200 people
人口少于2200人的社区
they're happier in the country than they
他们住在乡下比住在城里更快乐
are in the city which is a remarkable
位于这座非凡的城市
fact remarkable fact in part because
事实之所以引人注目，部分原因是
they're also poorer in the country
他们在该国也更贫穷。
people who live in cities in the United
居住在美国城市的人们
States for example are about 25%
例如，各州约占25%。
wealthier than people who live in the
比住在……的人更富有
country now some of that it's burned on
现在这个国家的一些地方已经被烧毁了。
comp on expensive city living but far
比较昂贵的城市生活，但距离远
from all of it and so they you're
从这一切中，所以他们你
literally poorer in the country but
该国实际贫困程度更高，但
happier and that's this graph here that
更快乐，这就是这张图表所显示的。
from your book um percentage of
从你的书中来看，嗯，百分比
Americans who are very happy are not too
非常快乐的美国人并不太……
happy in urban and rural communities
在城市和乡村社区都感到快乐
that's right and it shows that people
没错，这表明人们
are pretty significantly happier in R
使用 R 语言会明显更快乐。
rural areas and report to having less
农村地区，且报告称患病率较低
unhappiness in rural areas which is
农村地区的不幸福感是
remarkable because there's so many
之所以引人注目，是因为数量如此之多。
opportunities in cities people have been
城市里人们的机会一直存在
voting with their feet for over 100
他们用脚投票超过100次
years and arguably for 5,000 years
数年，甚至可以说是五千年。
moving to cities and yet it's making
搬到城市里，但这却造成了
them less happy and so in my mind this
他们不太快乐，所以在我看来……
is another symptom of the same exact
这是同一病症的另一个症状。
problem we've been talking about which
我们一直在讨论的问题是哪个
is cities are all about autonomy cities
城市就是自治之城
are about opportunity if I go to City I
如果我去I市，那就是关于机会。
can get any kind of education I want I
我可以接受任何我想要的教育。
can have any kind of job that I want and
我可以从事任何我想要的工作，
so people are drawn to cities and of in
所以人们被城市和……所吸引。
fact I'll make more money the data are
事实上，我会赚更多钱，数据是……
very clear but I'm going to pay a price
很清楚，但我要付出代价。
and people don't even realize the price
人们甚至没有意识到价格。
they're paying what is the price that we
他们付出的代价是什么？
pay we become more isolated yeah
是的，我们因此变得更加孤立。
bizarrely we become more isolated
奇怪的是，我们反而变得更加孤立了。
because in the city you got a thousand
因为在城市里你有成千上万个
people right next to you right you're
你旁边的人，你现在就在
you're cheek by gal with your neighbor
你和邻居女孩脸贴着脸
you're in an apartment building and
你身处一栋公寓楼里，
there's somebody on your left somebody
你左边有人，某人
on your right somebody above you
你右边，你上方有人。
somebody below you but what are your
你之下的人，但是你的
chances you even know that person so if
你甚至有可能认识那个人，所以如果
you ask people there's a couple ways you
你问别人，有几种方法……
can ask the question if you say do you
如果你说“你愿意”，他就可以问这个问题了。
know someone well enough that you trust
对某人足够了解，所以你信任他。
them with your house keys you're more
你用家里的钥匙给他们看，你更……
likely to give that answer a yes in the
很可能给出肯定的答案。
country than you are in the city even
即使身处城市，你也感觉自己身处乡村而非城市。
though in the country probably your
虽然在该国可能你的
nearest neighbor is a long way down the
最近的邻居也在很远的地方
road whereas in the city your nearest
道路，而在城市里，你最近的
neighbor is 5T away that person 5T away
邻居距离那个人5T
in principle you ought to be good
原则上你应该没问题。
buddies with or if they you don't like
和他们做朋友，或者如果你不喜欢他们的话
that person there's somebody else in
那个人，还有另一个人
your building you ought to be good
你的建筑应该没问题。
buddies with but we're just not whereas
我们是好朋友，但我们不是，而
in the country we connect with each
在这个国家，我们与每个人联系在一起。
other similarly if you say how satisfied
类似地，如果你说你有多满意，其他人也会这样说。
are you with your friendships people are
你和你的朋友们相处得怎么样？
more satisfied with their friendships in
对他们的友谊更满意
the country than they are in the city
他们在乡村比在城市里更受欢迎。
there was a graph that I saw I think it
我看到过一张图表，我想是这样的
was in your book the percentage of
你书中提到的百分比是多少？
Americans who spend evenings with
和美国人一起度过夜晚
Neighbors at different frequencies by
邻居以不同频率
income and it basically shows that the
收入，这基本上表明了
more money you have the less time you
你拥有的钱越多，你的时间就越少。
spend with your neighbors yeah which is
和邻居们一起度过时光，是的。
amazing right and so the thing is that
对吧，真是太棒了，所以关键是……
the problem is that if you're rich you
问题在于，如果你很富有……
don't need your neighbors you know if
你知道，你不需要你的邻居
I'm I'm out of coffee beans I want to
我的咖啡豆用完了，我想
borrow some I can just drone them in or
借一些，我就可以把它们念出来或者
whatever I I can I can call instacart or
无论我能做什么，我都可以打电话给Instacart或
whatever whoever your your favorite
无论你最喜欢谁
deliveries um program is but if you're
配送服务嗯，这个程序是，但是如果你是
poor you can't afford to do that and so
穷，你负担不起那样的费用，所以
poor people literally need each other
穷人之间确实需要彼此。
they live in these neighborhoods in
他们居住在这些社区里
these complex webs of interdependence
这些错综复杂的相互依存网络
where they borrow each other's tools
他们互相借用工具
they look out for each other's kids they
他们会互相照顾对方的孩子。
look out for each other's pets because
互相照看彼此的宠物，因为
they can't afford to Outsource any of
他们负担不起任何外包费用。
that and that's it's actually how humans
就是这样，而这实际上就是人类的运作方式。
evolved we evolved to need each other
我们进化到彼此需要。
all the time and so ironically although
一直以来，所以具有讽刺意味的是，尽管
rich people are happier than poor people
富人比穷人更快乐
so it's not giving away all your
所以它并没有泄露你所有的秘密
material Goods will not make you happy
物质的东西并不能让你快乐。
nonetheless poor people are happier with
然而，穷人反而更快乐
their friendships they're more likely to
他们之间的友谊，他们更有可能
get together their neighbors and we see
他们和邻居们聚在一起，我们看到
the exact same effect with education as
教育也会产生完全相同的效果。
well the more educated you are the less
受教育程度越高，就越不会
you get together with your neighbors but
你和邻居们聚在一起，但是
of course wealth and education tend to
当然，财富和教育往往……
go hand inand in our society so money
在我们的社会中，金钱与生活息息相关。
does make you happy it's funny thing so
这确实会让人开心，真是件有趣的事。
money makes you a lot happier in real
金钱确实能让你现实生活中更快乐。
time so if you start to make more money
所以，如果你开始赚更多钱，时间就会改变。
you get happier and the more important
你会变得更快乐，而且这更重要
money is to you the bigger that effect
金钱对你的影响越大，这种影响就越大。
is and it keeps going well past where we
是的，而且它一直持续到远远超过我们所在的地方。
thought it did we used to think it
我们以前也这么认为。
sealing at around $100,000 a year it
每年密封费用约为 10 万美元
doesn't past 600,000 a year money still
年收入不超过60万美元
makes you happier it's it's remarkable
它让你更快乐，这真是太棒了。
it makes a difference but there's this
这确实有区别，但还有这一点。
thing known as the easterland Paradox
被称为东境悖论的现象
and that is that as Society gets richer
随着社会变得越来越富裕，情况也是如此。
people get no happier so if you look at
人们并不会因此变得更快乐，所以如果你看看
the United States going back to around
美国可以追溯到大约
1940 people earned about a third what
1940年人们的收入大约是现在的三分之一
they earn today in real terms so we're
他们今天实际收入是多少，所以我们……
three times richer than we used to be
比以前富有三倍
and we've been measuring um happiness in
我们一直在衡量幸福感
the United States since 1940s on
自 1940 年代以来的美国
representative samples so we know that
具有代表性的样本，因此我们知道
that holds true for the whole country we
这一点适用于我们整个国家。
know what the country looks like it
了解这个国家的样子
hasn't moved an inch so real terms money
实际货币价值丝毫未变。
gone way up happiness exactly flat so
幸福感一路飙升，却完全停滞不前。
what is the per perfect combination to
最完美的组合是什么？
achieve happiness in that regard then
然后在这方面获得幸福
wealth does matter but something else
财富固然重要，但还有其他因素。
matters as well well which we tend to
以及其他我们倾向于处理的事情
abandon when we get wealth well the
当我们获得财富时，就应该放弃它。
problem is this there's a couple of
问题是，这里有几个
things first we can come back to the big
首先，我们可以回到大问题上来。
issue which I think is this balance
我认为问题在于这种平衡。
that's the underlying issue why why I
这就是问题的根本原因，为什么我
think H gathers are happier than we are
我觉得H组的人比我们更快乐
is this balance that they maintain
他们维持的就是这种平衡。
between autonomy and connection which we
在自主性和联系之间，我们
can return to but in direct answer to
可以返回，但直接回答
your question part of the problem with
你的问题本身就是问题的一部分
humans is that we're this wonderful
人类的奇妙之处在于我们如此美好。
species in many ways that we can avoid
物种在许多方面都存在我们可以避免的情况
this Zero Sum gain that is life and by
这种零和博弈的收益就是生活，而且是通过
Zero Sum gain I mean that my gain is
零和收益，我的意思是，我的收益是
your loss like there's only so many
你的损失似乎只有那么几个。
Goods out there and for me to have more
市面上有很多好东西，我希望拥有更多。
means you have to have less and in the
这意味着你必须拥有更少的东西，并且在
animal world lots of the world works
动物世界，世界上的许多作品
that way and they're able to cooperate
这样一来，他们就能合作了。
with each other when they can create
当他们能够彼此创造时
positive some relationships so for
积极的一些关系
example vampire bats they go out and
例如，吸血蝙蝠会外出……
they try to get blood from large animals
他们试图从大型动物身上获取血液。
like land on their back bite them a
就像摔倒在地，反咬一口。
little bit and leave drink a little bit
喝一点，然后留下一点
of their blood if they don't get any
如果他们得不到任何血液，就会流血。
food at all at night they're at risk of
晚上完全不吃东西，他们就有风险
starvation within just a few nights and
短短几晚之内便饿死了
so if I come home if I've come back and
所以如果我回家，如果我已经回来了，
I got nothing and you were successful
我一无所获，而你却成功了。
I'll beg to you and if we're friends
我会求你，如果我们是朋友的话
you'll regurgitate a little bit of the
你会反刍出一点
blood for me now if if you weren't
如果你不是，现在就给我鲜血吧
successful even if we're best mates
即使我们是最好的朋友，也能成功
there's nothing you can do for me now if
现在你也帮不了我了。
you think about the way humans give
你想想人类给予的方式
things to each other it's sometimes
彼此之间的事情有时
Goods but we're this different animal
商品，但我们是另一种动物
we're this cognitive animal we're an
我们是这种认知动物，我们是……
animal where information has enormous
动物信息量巨大
value and information I can give it to
我可以提供的价值和信息
you without losing any of it myself and
你我都没损失任何东西，而且
so we create these these relationships
所以我们建立了这些关系
with each other where we don't even need
我们彼此之间，甚至不需要
to worry about reciprocation we can do
担心互惠问题我们可以这样做
things for each other all the time
他们总是互相付出
they're crazy easy to do because they
它们做起来极其简单，因为它们
don't require me to give you anything I
不要要求我给你任何东西
still have the information I told you so
我仍然保留着我之前告诉你的信息。
we already have this advantage over the
我们已经拥有了这种优势。
animal
动物
kingdom but we're still animals and one
王国，但我们仍然是动物，而且只有一个
of the ways that we're still animals is
我们仍然是动物的其中一种方式是
that we're still zerm in the sense of
我们仍然是 zerm，从这个意义上来说
what about our status who's going to get
我们的地位会怎样？谁会得到？
picked for the mating relationships
被选中用于交配关系
who's going to get picked to be on the
谁会被选中参加？
teams and there it always comes down to
团队，最终总是取决于
well who's at the top of the local Heap
那么，本地排行榜的榜首是谁呢？
and who's at the bottom of the local
谁是当地最底层的人？
Heap and so in our ancestral communities
在我们的祖先社区里，堆肥等等
that would be a very small group of 100
那将是一个非常小的群体，只有100人。
gathers all I had to do was be valuable
我所要做的就是展现自己的价值。
or better than you guys in something in
或者在某些方面比你们做得更好
our world today it's awfully hard to be
在当今世界，生存变得异常艰难。
better than everybody and money is one
比所有人都强，金钱就是其中之一。
of the easiest most straightforward ways
最简单直接的方法
to do it because everyone can see it and
这样做是因为每个人都能看到。
so even though money doesn't make us
所以即使金钱并不能使我们……
happy as the whole country is three
全国上下都高兴得像三个人一样
times richer we're no happier if I'm
即使我比以前富有数倍，我们也不会更快乐
richer than you I am happier than you
我比你富有，也比你快乐。
because that's one way that I can be
因为这是我可以成为的其中一种方式
higher than in status and so then maybe
地位高于其他人，所以也许
I can steal your girlfriend or maybe the
我可以偷走你的女朋友，或者也许
guys who are in your group who I really
你们组里我真正喜欢的那些人
want to be in my group are gonna say hey
想加入我团队的人会说“嘿”。
Bill's cooler than Stephen I'm going
比尔比斯蒂芬酷多了，我要走了
with him and so status matters it's a
对他来说，地位很重要，这是一种
process of sexual selection whereby both
性选择过程，其中两者
sexes are always trying to CH get the
性别总是试图获得CH
best partner they can of the opposite
他们能找到的最佳伴侣，与相反的
sex and so they're competing with each
性，所以他们彼此竞争。
other men compete with men to try to
其他男人则与男人竞争，试图
have women choose them women compete
让女性选择她们，让女性竞争
with women to try to men choose them and
让女性试图让男性选择她们
that's a zero sum status game and what
那是一个零和博弈，而这又意味着什么呢？
does evolution tell us about that that
进化论告诉我们这一点吗？
competitive sort of Dating Game what
竞争性的约会游戏是什么
does it tell us if I'm trying to be
它能告诉我们我是否试图成为
attractive as a man what I need to be
作为一名男性，我需要具备怎样的吸引力
demonstrating in order to attract the
展示以吸引
opposite sex as a human yeah so what
异性作为人类，是啊，那又怎样？
what you want are what we call Honest
你想要的，我们称之为诚实。
signals of quality and the thing is that
质量信号，关键在于……
we've all evolved to look through fake
我们都进化出了识破虚假的能力。
signals and so lots of animals will
发出信号，因此很多动物都会
pretend to be things that they aren't um
假装成他们不是的东西
they puff up their chest or raise up
他们挺胸抬头
their shackles or do something to look
他们的镣铐或做些事情来观察
big and intimidating we all we have
我们都很大，很吓人。
human ways of doing that too but in
人类也有这样做的方式，但在
humans
人类
bizarrely well in in all animals
奇怪的是，它在所有动物中都表现得很好。
actually one of the clearest on signals
实际上，这是信号最清晰的信号之一。
for men to demonstrate for women is what
男人为女人做示范是……
is risk-taking now that seems bizarre
现在这算冒险吗？这听起来很奇怪。
why would taking a risk attract females
为什么冒险行为会吸引女性？
well it it attracts females because
它之所以能吸引女性，是因为
there's two outcomes when you take a
当你采取以下行动时，会出现两种结果：
risk you either succeed showing just how
风险在于，你要么成功，要么证明你是如何做到的。
skilled you are at whatever the domain
无论你擅长哪个领域，你都具备相应的技能。
is or you fail and either turn into a r
要么成功，要么失败，然后变成一个r
rash and therefore You' removed yourself
鲁莽行事，因此你离开了。
from the gene pool or you bounce right
从基因库中，或者你向右反弹
back up because you're such a robust
后备，因为你太强壮了
organism in either case you're
无论哪种情况，你都是一个生物体。
demonstrating that's an honest signal of
这表明这是一个诚实的信号
quality when we follow the data over
当我们跟踪数据时，质量会得到提升。
time we see that high testosterone men
我们看到，高睾酮男性
are more likely to pair up they take
他们更有可能结伴而行
these risks women find them attractive
这些风险对女性来说很有吸引力。
at some level even if they don't
即使他们没有，在某种程度上也是如此。
personally feel like it's attractive at
我个人觉得它很有吸引力。
the moment but something about that is
那一刻，但其中有些东西是
attracted to them and it may only be
被他们吸引，这可能只是
getting other men to back off when I
当我让其他男人退缩时
take these big risks you may say well
你可能会说，承担这些巨大的风险是可以的。
all right I'm not going to try to crowd
好吧，我不会试图挤占别人的空间。
in on Bill scene he's too tough we don't
在比尔那边，他太强悍了，我们不行。
know with certainty but they take these
他们明明知道，但他们还是接受了这些
risks and then once they partner up then
风险，以及一旦他们合作之后的风险
their testosterone levels go back down
他们的睾酮水平会下降
and they because once you have a family
而且他们是因为一旦你有了家庭
taking risks are is foolish you want to
冒险是愚蠢的，你想……
take risk to get in the Mating Game but
冒着风险参与求偶游戏，但
you don't want to keep taking taking
你不想一直服用
risk once you got people depending on
一旦有人依赖你，风险就很大。
you so I've got honest signals of did
所以，我收到了一些诚实的信号，表明我确实这么做了。
you say quality yeah honest signals of
你说质量，是的，诚实的信号
quality as being attractive as as a man
男性魅力等品质
I've got risk-taking what else things
我还有冒险精神，还有什么呢？
like physical size is an honest signal
比如，体型大小就是一个诚实的信号
of quality things like wealth if you
如果你拥有财富等优质事物，
earned all that money you know there's
你知道，你挣了那么多钱，有那么多……
inherited wealth we live in this kind of
我们生活在这样一种继承财富的时代。
funny world but it still gives you all
世界真奇妙，但它依然能给你一切
the advantages of wealth if you earned
如果你赚到了财富，那么财富的优势是什么？
it yourself there's uh ambition things
你自己身上也有野心之类的东西。
like that people look for ambition
人们就是这样追求雄心壮志。
because it's if you are out there
因为如果你身处其中，情况就不同了。
working hard the time it's an honest
努力工作，这是诚实的。
signal that you're going to probably
发出你可能要去的信号
continue to do that provide for somebody
继续这样做，为他人提供经济支持。
Etc I often think about like personality
等等，我经常思考性格之类的问题。
and why is humor a attractive quality in
为什么幽默是一种吸引人的品质？
men that's a great example humor is an
男人，这是一个很好的例子，幽默是一种……
honest signal of quality now it's funny
现在这成了质量的真实信号，真是滑稽。
because you could think well you could
因为你可以这样想，你可以
just be funny by memorizing jokes but if
仅仅靠背笑话来搞笑是不行的，但是如果
you think of your friends who are funny
你会想起你那些幽默的朋友。
they don't you don't sit down they go
他们不让你坐下，他们会走。
hey did I tell you the one about Pat and
嘿，我跟你说过帕特的那个故事吗？
Mike that's not how people are funny you
迈克，人们不是那样搞笑的。
know unless they're paid to do that up
除非有人付钱让他们这么做，否则他们不会知道。
on stage people are funny by making
在舞台上，人们通过表演来制造笑料。
connections that you hadn't thought of
你未曾想到的联系
by twisting the world 90° and linking
通过将世界旋转 90° 并连接起来
things together and that takes an agile
把所有事情整合起来，这需要敏捷性。
mind and you know there's more genetic
记住，还有更多基因方面的原因。
expression in our brain than anywhere
我们大脑中的表达比任何地方都更强烈
else in our body so it's a sign of good
身体其他部位也是如此，所以这是个好兆头。
genes and also we're a cognitive species
基因，而且我们也是认知物种。
being smart is super important for men
对男人来说，聪明非常重要。
and women that's how you succeed but as
女性就是这样才能成功的，但是作为
humans we also care an enormous amount
人类，我们也极其在乎。
about kindness and if that person who
关于善良，以及如果那个人
has nothing else going for them is kind
他们除了善良之外一无是处。
that person's going to do well in life
那个人将来一定会过得很好。
because kindness ends up trumping
因为善良最终会战胜一切
everything just because there's a host
仅仅因为有主持人，一切就都变了。
of reasons for that one of which is that
原因之一是……
if you're a kind person you're a great
如果你是个善良的人，你就很棒
partner to me even if you've got almost
即使你几乎已经拥有了一切，也请你成为我的伙伴
no other good qualities you need some
你不需要其他任何优点。
minimal levels of competence but once
最低限度的能力水平，但一旦
you cross minimal competence kindness
你跨越了最低限度的能力和善意
means you're going to look out for me
这意味着你会照顾我。
and that matters a lot do nice guys
这对好人来说非常重要
finish last in the evolutionary World
在进化世界中垫底
they don't actually so the the good
他们实际上并没有，所以这是好事。
thing about being in a nice guys they
想想成为好男人会是什么样子
they tend to finish first and so when we
他们往往能第一个到达终点，所以当我们
look at Hunter gather communities and we
看看狩猎采集社会，我们
look at people choosing their Partners
看看人们是如何选择伴侣的。
to go out on hunts in the morning they
他们早上出去打猎
actually choose the nice guys over the
实际上，我更倾向于选择好人而不是坏人。
better Hunters now again you need a
现在你需要更好的猎人
minimal level of competence now
现在最低限度的能力水平
they pay a big price to finish burst
他们付出了巨大的代价才完成爆发
because lots of people take advantage of
因为很多人都利用了这一点
them and so I share with you and you
所以，我把它们分享给你，你
never share back with me but if I'm a
永远不要跟我分享，但如果我是一个
nice guy I'm like that's okay you know
他人挺好的，我就想，没关系，你知道的。
Steven will come around someday he'll
史蒂文总有一天会想通的。
learn to share with me too or if he
也请他学会与我分享，或者如果他
doesn't that's okay he's a good guy and
没关系，他是个好人。
I like to give him half my rabbit that I
我喜欢把我的兔子的一半给他。
caught so they they they're in Economist
被抓住了，所以他们上了《经济学人》
terms they're suckers a lot they give a
他们经常被当成冤大头，给了……
lot more than they get but as far as
比他们得到的要多得多，但就目前而言
winning in the world everybody wants to
在每个人都想赢得的世界里
be with them what about for women in
和她们在一起，那么女性呢？
terms of
条款
Attraction if you you were to design a
如果你要设计一个吸引力，
perfectly attractive woman from an
来自一位完美迷人的女性
evolutionary basis what would that woman
进化论基础会如何影响那个女人
be like the different the the factors
就像不同的因素一样
that matter for women are different for
对女性而言，那件事的意义有所不同。
men because men are fertile throughout
男性，因为男性终生都具有生育能力。
their whole lives and it's so easy to be
他们的一生都如此，而且很容易成为
fertile you're you you're making 100
你很肥沃，你正在产下100个孩子
million sperm a day whatever that number
每天一百万个精子，不管这个数字是多少。
is they're tiny little cells you can
它们是你可以的微小细胞。
just do it even if you're old and
即使你年纪大了，也要去做。
desiccated fertility is crazy hard for a
生育能力下降对一个人来说非常困难
woman you need to be um under the age of
女士，你需要未满……
40 basically once our ancestral females
基本上，40 曾经是我们的祖先女性
hit 40 they almost never reprodu anymore
到了40岁，他们几乎不再生育了。
and we could talk about why that is it's
我们可以讨论一下为什么会这样。
an interesting evolutionary solution to
一个有趣的进化解决方案
a problem but then during that time you
问题在于，但在那段时间里你
have to be wellfed and you have to be
必须吃饱，而且你必须
healthy because it's super hard to
健康是因为它非常难
maintain a pregnancy that's you know
维持妊娠，你知道的。
nine months where if you're not getting
九个月的时间里，如果你没有得到
enough food it's hard to feed that fetus
食物充足，但很难喂饱那个胎儿。
so for women they need fat on their
所以女性需要脂肪。
bodies which was hard in our ancestral
在我们祖先的时代，身体是坚硬的
world that meant they're wellfed they
这意味着他们吃得很好。
need to be healthy and they need to be
他们需要保持健康，他们需要……
young and so when you have those
年轻的时候，所以当你拥有那些
qualities that's more important than
比……更重要的品质
anything else for men because when it
对男人来说，还有其他选择，因为当……
comes down to it
归根结底就是这样。
living forever is nice but evolution
永生固然美好，但进化
doesn't care about it if you don't
如果你不在乎，他也不会在意。
reproduce reproduction is the currency
复制就是货币
of evolution and so what men are looking
进化论以及人类正在寻找什么
for in a partner is somebody who's
伴侣就是……
reproductive who's fertile so is
有生育能力的人就是有生育能力的人。
attraction an evolutionary thing in your
吸引力是一种进化现象
view versus like a social thing it's
观点与社交行为的区别在于
well it's always both right you know
嗯，你知道，两者总是都对的。
humans are are wildly malleable and you
人类具有极强的可塑性，而你
can move things around in crazy ways you
你可以以疯狂的方式移动物体
know what look at what what people found
知道看看人们发现了什么
attractive just 50 years ago compared to
与50年前相比，现在看来很有吸引力
today but there's a lot of Basics that
今天有很多基础知识需要学习。
underly it and so for example
在其底层，例如
if you look at the actual shape of women
如果你观察女性的实际体型。
and their hip to- waist ratio whether
以及他们的腰臀比
the bum is big or not big in the current
屁股在当前情况下是大还是不大？
climate the hip to waist ratio doesn't
气候因素与腰臀比无关
change and that's because that hip to
改变，那是因为那种时髦
waist ratio is correlated with fertility
腰围比与生育能力相关
but the size of your bum not so much and
但你的臀部大小倒没那么重要。
in fact when women deposit fats Prem
事实上，当女性沉积脂肪时，Prem
menopause they deposit them on their
更年期她们会把它们沉积在她们身上
thighs and their bum which is where
大腿和臀部，也就是……
those fats are really good for the baby
这些脂肪对宝宝真的很好。
they help neural development you know
它们有助于神经发育，你知道吗？
your brain is loaded with fat when
当你的大脑充满脂肪时
you're in utero you need your mother to
你还在子宫里，你需要你的母亲
have lots of fat ideally on her bum and
最好臀部有很多脂肪，
thigh because that's going to help feed
大腿，因为那有助于喂养
your growing brain so there's like a
你的大脑正在发育，所以就像……
perfect hip to weight ratio yeah yeah
完美的臀重比例，耶！
and it rarely changes so there's
而且它很少改变，所以……
analyses of like every Playboy bunny
对每一位《花花公子》兔女郎的分析
from 1950 to whenever I don't know if
从1950年到我不知道的任何时候
Playboy even exists anymore but and and
《花花公子》杂志如今已不复存在，但是……
they always had the exact same ratio
它们的比例始终完全相同。
even though the actual weight of the
即使实际重量
model would have changed dramatically
模型将会发生巨大变化。
they went from pretty heavy in Marilyn
他们从玛丽莲·梦露时期就变得非常重。
Mon Rose day to really really skinny for
Mon Rose 那天真的非常非常瘦
a while and then back to heavier again
过了一会儿，又恢复到之前的沉重状态。
do men typically care for woman's Rich
男人通常会关心女人的财富吗？
from an evolutionary perspective does it
从进化论的角度来看，确实如此。
matter in principle it doesn't matter
原则上无关紧要
much I mean remember but there's there's
我的意思是，我记得很多，但是，还有一些。
your phenotype you're you're you want to
你的表型，你是，你是，你想
be well taken care of but but as far as
会得到很好的照顾，但是，就目前而言
what you're actually attracted to um
你真正被什么吸引呢？嗯
women so so we call it sexual plasticity
女性，所以我们称之为性可塑性
that women have evolved to basically be
女性已经进化成基本上是
able to find almost any guy attractive
几乎任何男人都能让他觉得有魅力。
because the qualities that are going to
因为这些品质将会
make men successful are often on the
让男人成功的关键因素往往在于……
inside because remember I told you all
心里想着，因为我告诉过你们所有人
men are fertile even when they get
男性即使在患病期间也具有生育能力
really old so a skinny guy a fat guy a
年纪真的很大，所以一个瘦子和一个胖子
strong guy a weak guy they're all
强壮的人，弱小的人，他们都是
fertile you don't have to worry about
生育能力强，你无需担心
that but what you do have to worry about
但你真正需要担心的是……
is raising kids is really hard you want
养孩子真的很难吗？
help so you want somebody who's going to
所以你想找个愿意帮忙的人
be successful and hunting you want
祝你狩猎成功，愿你狩猎顺利
somebody who's going to look out for you
会照顾你的人
and your kids these are the variables
而你的孩子，这些都是变量。
that really matter and and so women look
这真的很重要，所以女性看起来
for that and that means they need to be
为此，他们需要是
able to fall in love with you know the
能够爱上你知道的
Bill Gates of the world who aren't these
世界上像比尔·盖茨这样的人，他们不是这些人。
big Macho guys but can really take care
身材魁梧，看起来很强壮，但真的很会照顾人。
of you and so women have a lot more of
你，所以女性拥有更多
what we call sexual plasticity than men
我们称之为性可塑性比男性更强
men have a particular shape they're
男性的体型有其特殊之处。
looking for and a particular appearance
寻找和某种特定的外貌
on average because that correlates with
平均而言，因为这与
fertility now if you then have a choice
如果你现在有选择权，那就考虑生育能力吧。
oh here's one who's poor and here's the
哦，这里有一个穷孩子，还有这个……
one who's rich you're going to go with
你会和有钱人一起走
the one who's rich right but if you look
有钱人，对吧？但如果你仔细看……
at male rock stars and and and male
男性摇滚明星和男性
businessmen people who are really rich
商人，那些真正富有的人。
and famous the the women that they um
以及那些著名的女性
date and marry go are entirely across
约会和结婚完全是两回事。
the social class Spectrum some are super
社会阶层光谱中，有些人超级超级
rich some are super poor a waitress has
有些人很富有，有些人却非常贫穷，一位女服务员……
a great chance with MC Jagger um and so
和 MC Jagger 合作是个绝佳的机会，嗯，就是这样。
does some high society Elite person
一些上流社会精英人士
but if you turn around the other way a
但如果你反方向转身……
waiter doesn't have much chance with
服务员没什么机会
this Rich female or rock star sometimes
这位富有的女性或摇滚明星有时
but way less likely and that's because
但可能性要小得多，这是因为
women are looking for features of status
女性追求的是地位的象征。
and dominance in men and men don't care
男人的支配地位，以及男人不在乎
about that as much in women what is the
关于这一点，在女性身上也是如此，那是什么呢？
basis for homosexual relationships and
同性恋关系的基础
evolution so homosexuality is a really
进化论认为同性恋真的是一种……
interesting question we see it across
有趣的问题，我们看到它贯穿始终。
the Animal Kingdom so we know that we're
动物王国，所以我们知道我们是
not the only species who does it but we
虽然并非唯一这样做的物种，但我们
we don't often see exclusive
我们很少看到独家报道。
homosexuality in the animal kingdom that
动物王国中的同性恋
seems to be much more common in humans
这种情况在人类中似乎更为常见。
nobody's 100% sure sure why it is but
没人能百分之百确定原因，但是
the best evidence I've ever seen the
我见过的最佳证据
best evolutionary evidence comes out of
最佳进化证据来自
this lab of a colleague of mine an ex-
这是我一位同事的实验室，他以前是……
colleague of mine brandan Z and what he
我的同事布兰登·Z和他
shows is that most human behaviors are
这表明大多数人类行为都是
driven by a number of genes not just one
由多个基因驱动，而不仅仅是一个基因。
we call them polygenic a whole bunch of
我们称它们为多基因的一大堆
genes contribute to a particular
基因对特定情况有贡献。
behavior and especially a complex
行为，尤其是一种复杂的行为
Behavior like so homosexuality and so
诸如同性恋之类的行为
there's going to be a polygenic score
将会有一个多基因评分。
for homosexuality and the more of those
对于同性恋以及更多此类情况
the higher your polygenic score is the
多基因得分越高越好
more likely you are to be attracted to
你更有可能被……
same sex um and it works a ton bit
同性，嗯，而且效果非常好。
different than men and women but
与男性和女性不同，但
basically the same and what Brendan
基本上一样，还有布兰登
argued and has now demonstrated is that
已经论证并证明的是：
as you gain more gay genes genes that
随着你获得更多同性恋基因，这些基因
make you more attracted to the opposite
让你更容易被异性吸引。
sex but you're not completely homosexual
有性生活，但你并不完全是同性恋
yet you're more attractive to the
然而，你对……更有吸引力
opposite sex you're more attractive yeah
异性你更有吸引力，是的。
so men who have more gay genes but are
所以，那些拥有更多同性恋基因的男性，
still straight have more sexual partners
仍然保持异性恋身份的人拥有更多性伴侣
than men who have fewer gay genes and
比那些同性恋基因较少的男性要好得多
are also straight so being a little bit
他们也是直的，所以有点
gay is super attractive to women being
同性恋对女性来说极具吸引力
too gay maybe they're attracted to you
太gay了，也许他们喜欢你呢
but you don't care anymore because now
但你现在不在乎了。
you're only attracted to men and so from
你只对男人感兴趣，所以
an evolutionary perspective it's this
从进化论的角度来看，就是这样。
Balancing Act you want to give men
你想给男人的平衡之道
enough gay genes so that women are
足够的同性恋基因使得女性
attracted to them but not so many that
被它们吸引，但人数不多。
they don't care about
他们不在乎
women
女性
okay which kind of feels like a bit of a
好吧，这感觉有点像……
contradiction to the idea that
这与以下观点相矛盾：
testosterone and risk taking and being
睾酮、冒险精神和存在
brwn and being well mascul some gay men
棕色皮肤，而且很有男子气概，一些男同性恋者
are feminine but some gay men are very
虽然有些男同性恋者很女性化，但他们也很女性化。
masculine they're hyper masculine so
他们很有男子气概，而且是极度阳刚，所以
there's both
两者兼有
types you can be gay and be wildly
你可以是同性恋，而且非常狂野
masculine or you can be gay and be quite
你可以很有男子气概，或者你也可以是同性恋，而且相当安静。
feminine so what is it what is it about
女性特质，那它是什么？它关乎什么？
the being a little bit gay like what are
有点同性恋倾向就像……
the features what are the what are the
这些特性是什么？
features of being a little bit gay we
有点同性恋的特征
know the genes um this C this paper was
了解基因，嗯，这篇论文是
published in um science if I remember
如果我没记错的话，应该是发表在《科学》杂志上。
right a few years ago and laid out the
就在几年前，并制定了……
genes and they don't make sense some of
基因，但它们有些毫无意义
them relate to your sense of smell there
它们与你的嗅觉有关。
we don't understand these polygenic
我们不了解这些多基因
scores very well yet but if I had to
目前为止得分很高，但如果非要我说的话
guess um you know if you think of
猜猜看，嗯，你知道，如果你想到……
extreme straight males versus gay Mal
极端异性恋男性与同性恋男性
gay males are much cleaner they look
男同性恋者看起来更干净整洁。
after their themselves their bodies much
他们之后，他们的身体……
better their their hygiene's much better
他们的卫生状况好多了。
they take you know they're their sense
他们让你知道他们有他们的感觉
of Aesthetics is much better and so
美学方面要好得多，因此
maybe being a little bit gay means
或许有点同性恋倾向意味着
you're metrosexual and now you've got
你是都市型男，现在你拥有
these qualities where where you're not
这些品质在你不具备的地方
so downright disgusting to
简直令人作呕
women one of the one of the things that
女性是其中之一，也是其中之一
kind of Dove tells into this is some of
鸽子会告诉你，这是其中的一些事情。
the stats that I was reading about
我正在阅读的统计数据
education these days um this one stat
如今的教育，嗯，这个统计数据
here says that 58% of college graduates
这里说，58%的大学毕业生
in the most recent cohorts were women
在最近几批人群中，女性占多数。
with women on campus with one women on
校园里有女性，其中一位女性
campus for every two
每两个校园
men and with this scenario where there's
男人，以及在这种情况下……
more women becoming college educated
越来越多的女性接受大学教育
than men at increasing numbers you're
比男性人数更多，你是
going to get a bit of a mismatch in
可能会出现一些不匹配的情况
terms of women looking for those men who
女性寻找那些男性的条件
are up and to the right economically but
经济形势向好向坏，但
there's fewer men there yeah it's a real
那里的男人确实比较少。
problem and so you know we we talk about
问题，所以你知道，我们谈论的是
for example that women are
例如，女性是
underrepresented in some Fields like
在某些领域代表性不足，例如
they're underrepresented in the sciences
他们在科学领域人数不足。
and people worry about that a lot but
人们对此非常担忧，但
there's a much much bigger problem than
还有一个比这大得多的问题。
we're facing and in fact I'm not even
我们正面临着，事实上我甚至都不在场。
convinced the other one is a problem and
确信对方是个问题，
we can come back to that if you'd like
如果你愿意，我们可以稍后再讨论这个问题。
because I I do think there's reasons for
因为我确实认为这其中有原因。
that that might have to do with
那可能与……有关
preferences and not being held out but
偏好和不被冷落
setting that issue aside if we look at
暂且把这个问题放在一边，如果我们看一下……
uh the rates of going to University my
呃，上大学的比率
Birth Cohort I was born in 1963 is the
我出生于1963年，属于出生队列。
first year where women attended College
第一年，女生们开始在学院学习。
University at equal rates to men in the
大学男女同龄人入学率相同
United States and and that those lines
美国以及那些线
crossed and they never gone back and so
他们过了河，就再也没回去过。
now the the stat you were talking about
现在说说你刚才提到的那个统计数据
is there's basically uh the it's 6040
基本上就是……呃，它是6040
basically um female to male that means
基本上，嗯，女性变男性，这意味着
there's three women on campus for every
校园里每三个女生
two men and so in principle that first
两个人，因此原则上首先
of all makes it harder to date on campus
所有这些都让在校园里谈恋爱变得更加困难。
if you're female because there's not as
如果你是女性，因为机会不多……
many men on campus as there are women
校园里男生和女生一样多。
and so the competition is fierce but
因此竞争非常激烈，但
setting just dating on campus aside on
暂且不谈校园约会
average women are looking for who are as
普通女性都在寻找像他们一样的人。
as educated as themselves or more and
和他们一样受过良好教育，甚至更高。
men are looking for women who are as
男人们在寻找像他们一样的女性。
educated themselves or less and so we're
他们接受的教育程度不高，所以我们是
creating a problem because women are
造成问题，因为女性
getting really well educated and then
接受良好的教育，然后
there's not as many educated Men
受过良好教育的男性并不多。
available for them to partner up with
可供他们合作的对象
and so what you end up with is lots more
所以最终你会得到更多。
people living singal single now remember
现在单身的人都记得
we talked about that before couples are
我们之前讨论过这个问题，夫妻双方
less likely to get together on the one
不太可能在同一天聚在一起
hand this is not necessarily a bad thing
然而，这未必是件坏事。
because women going to college making a
因为女性上大学会……
lot of money means they can afford to
很多钱意味着他们有能力
live as a single person which they
他们像单身人士一样生活。
literally could not do up until 1960 if
如果直到1960年才真正实现，那是不可能的。
you're a female in most countries you
在大多数国家，你都是女性。
you couldn't have a job really and so
你根本没法真正找到工作，所以
you the way to be an economic success is
你获得经济成功的途径是
to marry those days are gone but it does
结婚的时代已经过去了，但确实如此。
mean that it's harder for women to find
这意味着女性更难找到工作。
Partners when they're on average more
合作伙伴平均而言更
likely to be educated than men and we
女性受教育程度可能高于男性，而我们
don't know why men are attending college
不知道为什么男人要上大学
at lower rates than women but I suspect
男性的患病率低于女性，但我怀疑
that school itself is just doesn't suit
那所学校本身就不适合我。
boys as well as it suits girls and so
它既适合男孩也适合女孩，所以
it's harder for boys to hold still it's
男孩更难保持静止不动。
boys are less likely to want to please
男孩不太愿意取悦别人。
their teachers now the list is long it's
他们的老师们，现在名单很长。
hard to raise Boys in those kinds of
在那种环境下很难养育男孩。
ways and and uneducated unpartnered men
方式和未受过教育的单身男性
are the biggest problem in every society
是每个社会面临的最大问题
you know if you've got men with poor
你知道，如果你手下有穷男人的话。
prospects who can't find good jobs and
找不到好工作的求职者
who don't have a partner they're the
没有伴侣的人就是
guys running around with high tea who
一群端着下午茶到处跑的人
are committing all the crimes so as a
他们犯下了所有罪行，因此……
society you want to be very invested in
你想深度参与的社会
men partnering up with women because
男人与女人结成伴侣
that tames them and you want to be very
这样就能驯服它们，而你想非常
invested in men being viable partners
致力于让男性成为合格的伴侣
for women which means whatever we're
对女性而言，这意味着无论我们是什么
doing wrong in schools that's pushing
学校里做错事正在推动……
men out we need to un do if women are
男人都出去了，如果女人……我们需要扭转局面。
looking for men that have more resources
寻找更有资源的男性
than them on average which is what I
平均而言，我比他们高。
read in some of the studies that I think
我在一些研究中读到过一些观点，我认为
it was roughly 70% of women say they
大约70%的女性表示她们
want a man that has equal or more money
想要一个经济条件与我相当或更好的男人
than they do
比他们实际的要多
um there's a mismatch there isn't there
嗯，这里存在不匹配，不是吗？
because as both become sort of more
因为随着两者都变得更加……
equalized if there's still a desire for
如果仍然有这种愿望，那就相等。
the for the man to have more and provide
为了让男人拥有更多并提供帮助
more there's again it doesn't the
还有更多，但它并没有。
numbers don't the numbers don't match
数字不匹配，数字不相符。
it's a really unfortunate problem and so
这是一个非常不幸的问题，因此
the easiest way to look at that problem
解决这个问题的最简单方法
is to basically look at Tinder or one of
基本上就是看看 Tinder 或其他类似的软件。
these um dating apps and there you can
这些约会应用，你可以在那里……
see that basically 20% of the guys on
基本上有 20% 的男性
Tinder get 80% of the swipes what that
Tinder 获得了 80% 的滑动点击量，这是什么意思？
means is that 80% of the men basically
意思是说，基本上80%的男性
largely get ignored on the app and 20%
在应用程序上，用户大多被忽略，占比高达 20%。
are fawned upon in contrast women about
相比之下，女性则受到奉承。
80% of them are getting swiped by people
其中80%都被人偷走了
on a regular basis they're just not
他们经常不是这样。
getting swiped by the guys that they're
被那些家伙抢走了
interested in it's set up so that both
我对它的设置很感兴趣，这样两者……
sexes want the same thing you men look
男女想要的是一样的，你们男人都这样想
for the same thing in women and women
对女性和男人来说也是如此。
look for the same thing in men
在男性身上也要寻找同样的品质。
um and there's just a lot more
嗯，还有很多其他的。
competition among the men to get women
男人之间为了赢得女人而展开的竞争
and so it's a smaller subset of men who
因此，这只是男性群体中较小的一个子集。
are women are interested in interesting
女性对有趣的事物感兴趣吗？
on an individual level I guess if you're
就个人而言，我想如果你是
a man you really do need to focus on
一个你真正需要关注的男人
your career if you want to have a chance
如果你想拥有机会，你的职业生涯
of well focusing on your career is
专注于你的职业生涯是
definitely an easy way to do it but look
这确实是一种简单的方法，但看看
not everybody's a career person and so
并非每个人都适合事业型生活，所以
you have to decide where your best
你必须决定你的最佳状态在哪里。
prospects are and that comes back to
前景如何，这又回到了……
like why do we have autonomy well we've
比如，我们为什么拥有自主权？嗯，我们有
evolved that because there's lots of
之所以会发展成这样，是因为有很多
ways to skin a cat and so basically
剥猫皮的方法等等
autonomy means I'm going to pick my path
自主意味着我可以自己选择道路。
in life where I think I have the best
生活中，我认为我拥有最好的。
prospects usually that means career but
前景通常指的是职业生涯，但
there's also ways of being you know just
还有其他一些存在方式，你知道的。
a really kind person the person who's
一个非常善良的人，那个人
always going to look out for you the
我会一直照顾你的。
person who's going to be great helping
这个人会非常乐于助人
with the kids lots of men don't meet
很多男人带着孩子都不愿意见面。
those criteria and so that's a perfectly
这些标准，所以这是一个完美的
successful way you just got to find
成功的方法你只需要找到
you're not going to get swiped right on
你不会被右滑的。
Tinder that's not going to be your way
Tinder 不适合你。
of find if that's you if you're the kind
如果你是那种人，那就看看你是不是那种人。
reliable but you don't have a great
可靠，但你没有很棒的
career you don't have those other things
你的职业生涯中没有那些其他的东西。
then the apps aren't the right place for
那么这些应用程序就不是合适的地方了。
you but but people who meet you are
你，但是，但是遇见你的人是
going to really like you and women are
你会非常喜欢你，而且女人也喜欢你
going to want to be with you because
会想和你在一起，因为
they're going to realize oh they may not
他们会意识到，哦，他们可能不会
want to be with you when they're younger
他们年幼时就想和你在一起
but as they get a little older and
但随着他们年龄渐长，
they've been through a few of the guys
他们已经换过几个家伙了。
who everybody else is chasing they're
其他人都在追逐他们。
going to say boy I could really use
要说的是，我真的需要
somebody like you speaking of the apps
像你这样的人在谈论应用程序
and swiping we talked about how men on
我们讨论了滑动屏幕时男人是如何做的
those apps if they're not in that sort
如果那些应用不属于那种类型的话。
of top Echelon of demonstrating
最高层级的示威者
authentic quality on the surface so like
表面上看起来很有质感，所以就像
Rich muscly whatever then only their
富有的肌肉男，无论什么，都只是他们的
chance of getting swiped on are very
被刷屏的几率非常高
very low what about for women cuz a lot
非常低，那女性呢？因为很多
of my female friends say that they hate
我的女性朋友中有人说她们讨厌
the dating apps they have no luck then
他们用的约会软件都没成功
they're only getting bad swipes yeah
他们只会收到糟糕的滑动记录，没错。
that's that's the difference they're
这就是它们的区别。
getting bad swipes meaning they don't
获得糟糕的滑动次数意味着他们没有
like the guys who swipe them the guys
就像那些把她们抢走的家伙一样
who have no Locker getting no swipes
没有储物柜的人无法刷卡。
this is true because actually when I
这是真的，因为实际上当我
think about the particular friend I was
想想我曾经的那个朋友
thinking of I asked to see her Tinder or
我想着我当时是不是问她要不要看看她的 Tinder 账号或者其他什么软件。
whatever app it was many years ago and I
不管那是什么应用，那是很多年前的事了，我
was like oh my God I jesus I wish I had
当时我就想，我的天哪，我真希望我……
this many swipes yeah cuz as a guy I
这么多次滑动是啊，因为作为一个男人，我
mean what I had must have had Tinder for
我的意思是，我肯定用过 Tinder。
about a month back in 2000 when I was 20
大约一个月前，也就是2000年，当时我20岁。
I'm going to say 23 24 I couldn't get
我猜是23、24，我没能得到。
swipes yeah and if I got some listen it
滑动，是的，如果我有一些，听着。
wasn't anything to write home about it
没什么值得一提的。
was like and it was very very rare but
就像那样，而且非常非常罕见，但是
when I looked at her Tinder that she was
当我查看她的 Tinder 个人资料时，我发现她
complaining about she had hundreds of
抱怨说她有数百个
men yeah but she just didn't like any of
男人嘛，她都不喜欢。
them exactly that's the difference and
正是如此，这就是区别所在。
so the thing is that throughout our
所以关键在于，在整个我们的过程中
evolutionary history men have often been
进化史中的男性常常是
left out of the out of The Mating Game
被排除在《求偶游戏》之外
entirely and we know this if we look at
完全如此，如果我们仔细观察，就会知道这一点。
the variability on our y l chromosomes
我们Y染色体上的变异性
you only inherit yl genes from your
你只会从你的父母那里继承yl基因
father because women don't have a y
父亲，因为女人没有
chromosome for for women you can look at
对于女性来说，你可以查看染色体。
mitochondrial DNA which you only inherit
你只能继承线粒体DNA。
from your mother and if you look at the
从你母亲那里，如果你看看
mitochondrial DNA and the variability
线粒体DNA及其变异性
there you can see that we have about
在那里你可以看到我们有大约
twice as many moms as dads yeah that's
妈妈的数量是爸爸的两倍，没错。
weird because it takes two to tango but
这很奇怪，因为跳探戈需要两个人，但是
what it means is that some of the dads
这意味着有些爸爸
were getting lots of women and some lots
我们吸引了很多女性，还有一些……
of lots of potential that as we're
我们拥有巨大的潜力
getting no women at all and so in our
完全找不到女人，所以在我们的
ancestral past there's lots of men who
祖先的过去有很多男人
nobody swiped right they couldn't find a
没人右滑，他们找不到。
partner and there's lots of men who
伴侣，而且有很多男人
women were very interested in they
女性们对她们非常感兴趣
probably had multiple partners and so we
可能有多位伴侣，所以我们
still live in that exact same world so
仍然生活在同一个世界里，所以
what do they have to do lower their
他们必须做什么才能降低他们的
standards well they you could say lower
标准，嗯，可以说较低。
their standards but you could also say
他们的标准，但你也可以说
you know you're not liking him for all
你知道你其实并不喜欢他。
the wrong reasons you know yeah so what
你知道，都是错误的原因，那又怎样？
he doesn't drive a Ferrari and so what
他又不开法拉利，那又怎样？
he doesn't look super cool or whatever
他看起来并不特别酷什么的
but he could be a great guy the problem
但他可能是一个很棒的人，问题是……
is apps aren't well suited for that and
应用程序并不适合这种情况，而且
so you know when when we were all just
所以你知道，当我们都还只是
people who met in person you would
与你面对面交流的人
realize oh this guy's ass salt to the
意识到哦，这家伙的屁股真咸。
Earth he'd be a perfect partner for me
地球上，他会是我完美的伴侣。
for my life I know he's kind of ugly or
就我所知，他长得有点丑。
he's kind of whatever but who cares
他这个人也就那样，不过谁在乎呢。
right he's going to be a perfect life
没错，他会过上完美的生活。
partner very hard to see that on an
很难在伴侣身上看到这一点
app okay so I was thinking about the the
应用程序还可以，所以我在想……
attraction um features of a woman that
女性的吸引力特征
we talked about earlier I know that if
我们之前谈过，我知道如果
I'm a guy and I'm trying to have more
我是个男的，我想多赚点钱。
success on the apps on social media what
社交媒体应用上的成功是什么？
I need to do is I need to pull up in my
我需要做的就是开车过来。
Lamborghini I need to hit the gym I need
兰博基尼，我需要去健身房，我需要
need to Signal my quality and authentic
需要表明我的品质和真实性
way that can't be disproven and if I'm a
一种无法被反驳的方法，如果我是一个
woman therefore I need to be showing my
因此，作为一名女性，我需要展现我的
hip ratio well I I want to look
臀比，嗯，我想看看
attractive and I want to look healthy
我希望自己有吸引力，并且看起来健康。
and I want to look young okay but
我想看起来年轻，好吗？
keeping in
保持
mind I could be none of the above and
请注意，我可能以上都不是。
I'm still going to get swiped right how
我还是会被右滑的。
does pornography confound all of this
色情作品是否会混淆这一切？
stuff yeah pornography is a funny
是啊，色情片真搞笑
business it it allows us to vicariously
商业让我们能够间接地……
engage in sex without actually doing it
参与性行为但不实际发生性行为
right and so we evolved in a world where
没错，所以我们进化成一个这样的世界：
there was no pornography we certainly
我们当然没有看到任何色情内容。
evolved in a world where there's
进化于一个充满……的世界
masturbation um but we evolved in a
自慰，嗯，但我们进化成……
world that didn't have pornography and
一个没有色情的世界
so it's kind of hijacking our system a
所以它有点像是在劫持我们的系统。
little bit it feels like you're having
感觉有点像你在……
sex when you know you're on only fans or
当你明知自己在OnlyFans上做爱时，或者
whatever those sites are that interest
无论那些网站是什么，只要它们吸引你。
you it it mimics a lot of the features
它模仿了很多功能
and so you know I become interested in
所以你知道，我对……产生了兴趣。
the social media world we live in and
我们生活的社交媒体世界以及
this possibility that social media Mak
社交媒体可能对
so many things so easy that you stop
太多事情如此简单，以至于你停了下来
going out you stop you know because you
出去玩的时候，你会停下来，你知道，因为你
can connect with your friends on social
可以在社交媒体上与朋友联系
media why go through the snow and go
媒体为什么要冒着雪去
across town and maybe not know anybody
在城另一头，也许根本不认识任何人
at the party Etc and and I think what's
在派对上等等，我想什么是
happened is that as we get lazy and we
事情的结果是，当我们变得懒惰时，我们
we we start putting our life online you
我们开始把我们的生活放到网上。
know our social life we even start to
了解我们的社交生活，我们甚至开始
put more you know our sexual life online
把更多关于我们性生活的信息放到网上
and so there's even evid I the evidence
所以甚至有证据表明
is very tentative as to what it might
对于它可能是什么，他非常犹豫不决。
mean but recently in the United States
意思是，但最近在美国
at least if you look at young single
至少如果你看看年轻单身人士的话。
people their actual sexual behavior is
人们的实际性行为是
going down they're having less sex than
他们的性生活频率比以前低了。
they were 20 years ago and if you if
那是20年前的事了，如果你……
you'd asked me 20 years ago when Tinder
你20年前问我这个问题的时候，Tinder还存在呢。
whenever those things got invented I
每当那些东西被发明出来的时候
would say oh sex is going to go way up
会说哦，性生活将会大幅增长
this is going to be you know this is
你知道，这将是……
going to be the best thing for hooking
这将是钓鱼的最佳选择
up ever in actual fact although it went
事实上，它甚至一度上升，尽管它
up for a little bit it went back down
上涨了一会儿后又回落了。
and instead of what's going up is
而上升的却是……
pornography watching and so it maybe the
观看色情片，所以这可能是
pornography is getting better tailored
色情内容正变得越来越有针对性
to what people want maybe people are
人们想要什么，也许人们是
just getting lazy and they instead of
他们只是变得懒惰了，而不是
going to the party and maybe meeting
去参加聚会，也许会遇到
somebody who they would have sex with
他们会和谁发生性关系
they just pick it up and watch it on TV
他们就拿起来在电视上看。
I don't know because I'm thinking about
我不知道，因为我正在思考……
this graph that was in your book which
你书里的这张图表
shows how much sex we're having and how
这显示了我们性生活的频率以及如何
much porn we're watching yeah and very
是的，我们看了很多色情片，而且很多。
simply it shows that we're having less
简单来说，这表明我们拥有的更少了。
sex and we're watching more porn and
性生活，而且我们看的色情片越来越多。
it's quite a considerable drop between
两者之间下降幅度相当大。
2006 and 2012 it said a percentage of 18
报告称，2006年和2012年各占18%。
to 25 year olds who had had sex or
对25岁有过性行为的人或
watched porn within the last year yeah
是的，过去一年里看过色情片。
and about
以及关于
80% of 18 to 25y olds had had sex in the
18至25岁人群中，80%有过性行为。
last year and now it's getting down
去年是这样，现在情况正在恶化。
nearer to 60 five 70% which is
更接近 60% 到 70%，也就是
remarkable these are young single people
令人惊讶的是，这些都是年轻的单身人士。
you know this is when we are most likely
你知道，这是我们最有可能的时候。
to have sex with you know partners of
和你知道的伴侣发生性关系
random hookups or whatever so they're at
随机约炮之类的，所以他们就在那里
the peak of their sexuality and
他们性欲的巅峰时期
nonetheless 20 years later they're less
然而，20年后，他们却减少了
likely to have sex and more likely to be
更有可能发生性行为，也更有可能……
watching porn and it looks like
看色情片，看起来像
pornography consumption is almost like
色情消费几乎就像
tripled yeah in that time period it's
是的，那段时间增长了三倍。
it's always it's been accessible over
它一直都是可以访问的。
that en time entire time period but
那段时间，整个时间段，但是
basically what what I think those dat I
基本上，我认为那些数据是什么？
I I refer to this I know it's a absurd
我指的是这件事，我知道这很荒谬。
acronym I refer to this as
我称之为缩写词
smiling social media induced laziness in
微笑社交媒体引发的懒惰
our social habits I know it's it'll
我们的社交习惯，我知道它会
never catch on but I think that what
我一直没搞明白，但我认为……
they're doing is sming they they they've
他们正在做的就是……他们……他们……他们……
got friends we at a party it's across
和朋友们在派对上，就在对面
town it's kind of a pain to get there
去那个镇子有点麻烦。
it'll cost you Subway and everything
这会让你花掉赛百味和其他所有东西。
else and you're not sure if you're going
否则，你不确定自己是否要去。
to have fun when you get there and so
到了那里要玩得开心，所以
you go screw it I'm not going to go now
你去吧，算了，我现在不走了。
what you didn't know is that would have
你不知道的是，那本来会……
that's the party where you would have
那就是你会参加的派对。
met that person who you would have end
遇到了那个你本该结束的人
up hooking up with either as short-term
与其中任何一人进行短期性关系
or long-term partner but you didn't go
或者长期伴侣，但你没有去。
and instead what you did is you stay at
相反，你却待在了……
home and so there's a decent chance you
回家，所以很有可能
watchh porn and so we're we're letting
看色情片，所以我们才允许
these fake substitutes take over in
这些假冒替代品占据了主导地位
place of our actual real socializing
我们真正的社交场所
which I think is hugely problematic and
我认为这非常成问题，而且
does this explain in part when we're
这是否部分解释了我们何时
thinking about the pornography rise why
思考色情内容兴起的原因
there is declining fertility rates we're
生育率正在下降。
having less and less kids than ever in
生育的孩子越来越少
the western world and some people are
西方世界和一些人是
concerned about population collapse well
对人口崩溃感到担忧
I I actually think it's separate from
我其实认为它是独立的。
pornography because right now we've
色情作品，因为我们现在有
already separated our sexual activity
我们已经分开了性生活
from our reproduction right can just use
从我们的复制权来看，我们可以直接使用
be on the pill use a condom use whatever
服用避孕药，使用避孕套，或者其他任何方法。
you want which our ancestors couldn't do
你想要的东西，我们的祖先做不到。
and other animals can't do and so the
其他动物做不到这一点，所以……
amount of sex that we have is completely
我们性生活的频率完全
uncorrelated with how many kids we
这与我们有多少个孩子无关
decide to have and so if you set
决定拥有，所以如果你设定
pornography aside fertility rates are
撇开色情内容不谈，生育率是
going way down and I think that's simply
一路下滑，我认为这仅仅是
because we never evolved to want
因为我们从未进化出想要这种东西的本能。
children we evolve to want sex and so if
孩子们，我们进化出性欲，所以如果
you want sex if you enjoy sex and then
如果你享受性爱，你就想要性爱。
you've also evolved to be nurturant to
你也进化出了照顾他人的能力。
whatever child comes along from that
无论将来生下什么孩子
Bingo you're a mom or a dad but if you
恭喜你，你是一位妈妈或爸爸，但如果你
evolv to want kids you go back a little
当你想要孩子的时候，你得稍微回顾一下过去。
ways you would have no idea how to
你根本不知道该怎么做
achieve that you wouldn't have known
达到你原本不会知道的程度
what to do we evolv to want to have sex
我们进化到想要性生活该怎么办
and in a world without the pill that
在一个没有避孕药的世界里，
automatically resulted in children and
自动导致子女的产生
then all you have to do is evolve to be
那么你所要做的就是进化成……
nurturing to them because they're so
因为他们如此……所以要好好照顾他们。
dependent in humans when they're born
人类出生时就依赖于此
which is what happens when you had your
这就是你拥有……时发生的事情
baby recently you have this huge sort of
最近你生了个宝宝，你最近有这么大的一个
magnetic pull to the child and I I
对孩子和我都有磁力
wasn't Keen to have more kids my I have
我并不想再生孩子，但我已经有了
some children who grown to adulthood I
有些孩子长大成人了
felt like I don't need any more kids but
感觉我不需要更多孩子了，但是
then I have another kid and I I'm I'm
然后我又生了一个孩子，我……
just in love with her right you can't
你就爱上她了，对吧？你不能
help yourself so we've intervened in
自助，所以我们介入了。
Nature's natural we've intervened and
我们干预了自然规律，而自然规律是自然规律。
that intervention is what's potentially
这种干预措施可能产生影响。
going to lead to there to be no more
这将导致不再有
humans so if you look at the current
所以，如果你看看现在的人类
population of the globe it's meant to
它旨在覆盖全球人口
Peak somewhere between say 2070 and 2090
峰值可能在2070年至2090年之间。
um probably around 8 billion and some
嗯，大概在80亿多一点吧。
change and then it start to go down and
发生变化，然后开始下降，
then it may continue to go down forever
那么它可能会永远持续下降。
now it may be that if what what causes
现在，这可能是因为什么原因造成的。
you to want to have kids is very
你想生孩子是很正常的。
societal it's very well my apartment's
社会方面，我的公寓非常好。
small and I don't want to SHP them
它们太小了，我不想把它们寄出去。
around it's hard work you could imagine
你可以想象，这需要付出多么艰辛的努力。
a world where now robots are everywhere
如今，机器人无处不在。
and where you've got all the space in
以及你拥有所有空间的地方
the world because there's not that many
世界上没有那么多人。
humans or we've moved to the country and
人类，或者我们已经搬到了乡村，
EC commute or whatever maybe suddenly
EC通勤或其他什么可能突然发生
we'll want to have six or eight of them
我们想要六到八个。
again because our robot's the one who
再次因为我们的机器人是那个
gets up in the middle of the night with
半夜起来
him and we don't have to but right now
他，我们不必那样做，但现在
if you think about having kids it's hard
如果你想要孩子，那就很难了。
yards and so lots and lots of people say
院子，所以很多人都这么说。
well I just don't want to do that and
我就是不想那样做。
the consequence is that in every single
结果是，在每一个
country that's indu industrialized and
工业化国家
Rich the reproduction the reproductive
丰富的繁殖 生殖的
rate of females is less than 2.1 per
女性的比例低于2.1%。
female which is what you need in order
女性，这正是你需要的。
to maintain population at the current
为了维持目前的人口规模
level and so every single country on
因此，每个国家都处于同一水平。
earth is shrinking but for
地球正在缩小，但对于
immigration and so right now you know we
移民问题，所以现在你知道我们
have all these fights about immigration
围绕移民问题，争论不休。
it's going to be I promise you in 50
我保证50年后就会是这样。
years that argument is going to be the
多年来，这场争论将一直持续下去。
exact opposite how can we convince
恰恰相反，我们该如何说服别人？
people of country X to come into our
X国人民进入我们
country because we're going to shrink
因为我们将缩小国家规模
and disappear there's a a lot of
然后就消失了，有很多
countries that are going to be literally
那些即将成为字面意义上的国家
half their size by the year 00 because
到公元00年，它们的规模缩小了一半，因为
they're shrinking so fast really half of
它们缩小得太快了，真的只有一半了。
East Asia um half of Western Europe
东亚，也就是西欧的一半
they're just shrinking Crazy Fast
它们正在以惊人的速度缩小。
they're demolishing houses Japan is
他们正在拆毁房屋，日本是
demolishing houses there's nobody to buy
拆掉房子，却没人买。
them because the women are having less
因为女性生育率下降了。
than that 2.1 yeah the average child
比那2.1，是的，平均孩子
rate in in a lot of these countries is
在许多这些国家，利率是
around 1.5 to 1.7 very very low you
大约1.5到1.7，非常非常低。
don't think it's possible that we're
我不认为我们有可能
going to make ourselves extinct because
我们会因为……而走向灭绝
we're not having [__] sex are we well
我们没他妈的做爱吧？
we'd still be having sex we just
我们还是会做爱的，只是
wouldn't be having kids right but we are
我们本来不会要孩子的，但我们现在要了。
having less as well aren't we well that
拥有的也更少，不是吗？
varies yeah lots and lots of us having
是的，情况各不相同，我们很多人都有。
less sex there there's reasons for that
那里的性生活较少，这是有原因的。
that probably have more to do with
这可能与以下方面关系更大：
ecotoxicology than with psychology
生态毒理学比心理学更适合
there's so many hormone mimics in our
我们体内有很多激素类似物。
environment in Plastics and and various
塑料及其他环境
pollutants that um that change our
那些改变我们生活的污染物
endocrine system that that reduce sperm
减少精子的内分泌系统
counts I we think that's what's going on
我觉得事情就是这样。
and redu sperm count often is associated
精子数量减少通常与此相关
with reduced sex drive Etc so if you
性欲减退等等，所以如果你
were prime minister or president of the
曾任总理或总统
world and it was your job to get us
世界，而你的任务就是带我们去那里。
having children again based on what you
根据你的意愿再次生育
know about evolutionary psychology and
了解进化心理学和
human incentives what would what would
人类的激励机制会是什么？
you do well the the main thing is that
你做得很好，最重要的是……
because humans didn't evolve to want
因为人类进化并非为了渴望
children you can't just play on their
你不能随便在孩子们身上玩耍
don't you really want children because
你真的不想生孩子吗？
the answer is often no um what you want
答案通常是“不”，嗯，你想要什么？
to do is you want to make having kids to
你想做的就是让生孩子这件事变得容易
be as much of the plus as it possibly
尽可能发挥其积极作用
can be and as little of the minus so if
可以，而且负数越少越好，所以如果
you look at kids that they're really
你看看那些孩子，他们真的很
interesting this is some wonderful work
很有意思，这是很棒的作品。
by Danny Conan who won the Nobel Prize
由诺贝尔奖得主丹尼·科南创作
and he he asks you in the moment what
他会立刻问你什么
are you doing and how much fun it is is
你在做什么？感觉有多好玩？
it and what he finds is no surprise if
如果真是这样，那么他所发现的一切也就不足为奇了。
you're having sex when you got the
当你做爱的时候，你得到了
request and now you probably waited till
提出请求后，您可能已经等了很久了。
you were done before you answered your
你回答问题之前就已经完成了
Bieber but you you said oh I'm having a
比伯，但你说哦，我正在经历
great time and as it goes with TV was
度过了美好的时光，就像电视节目一样……
actually in second place watching TV is
实际上，排名第二的是看电视。
good fun in the moment and then a little
当时玩得很开心，然后有点
way down the list is like doing the
列表末尾的内容就像在做
dishes doing the laundry if you if
如果你洗碗、洗衣服……
you're with your kids you're on average
你和你的孩子在一起，你平均而言
about doing the dishes or doing the
关于洗碗或做其他事。
laundry that's how much fun your kids
洗衣服，这就是你孩子有多喜欢你的原因
are but if you ask people what gives you
确实如此，但如果你问人们是什么让你……
great satisfaction in life what makes
生活中最大的满足感是什么？
you happy nobody says I'm crazy happy
你很开心，没人说我高兴得要疯了
because I've watched a ton of TV that's
因为我看过很多电视节目。
just not an answer anyone's everever
但这绝不是任何人的答案。
given or because I folded my laundry
因为我叠了衣服而得到或因为我叠了衣服
really well what they do say though is
他们确实说了些很好的话。
oh my kids give me enormous Joy so how
哦，我的孩子们给我带来了巨大的快乐，真是太好了！
could it be both how could it be that on
难道两者兼而有之？怎么可能呢？
average your kids are as much fun as the
平均而言，你的孩子和你一样有趣
laundry but when you look back on your
洗衣，但当你回头看你的
life they're they're the key thing and
生活，它们是关键所在，
what we think the answer is is that they
我们认为答案是：他们
provide these Peak moments that laundry
洗衣的这些高峰时刻，提供了洗衣的乐趣。
simply doesn't right no matter how well
无论做得多么好，这都不对。
you fold your clothes it's not exciting
你叠衣服，这没什么意思。
but your kids have these amazing moments
但你的孩子会经历这些美好的时刻。
in their lives that that you get to be
在他们的生活中，你有机会成为
part of as you see the world through new
当你以全新的视角看待世界时，这便是其中的一部分。
eyes again and so and for a good
再次睁开眼睛，就这样，为了好
evolutionary reasons where you get your
从进化角度来看，你是如何获得你的
whole mind and body and identity caught
整个身心和身份都陷入其中
up in them and so kids end up being a h
孩子们都陷在里面，所以他们最终成了……
huge source of satisfaction so what that
这是巨大的满足感来源，那又怎样呢？
means is if you want to get people to
意思是，如果你想让人们
start having kids again try to get rid
再次开始生孩子，试图摆脱
of The Drudge side of it you know look
你知道，从 Drudge 那边来看
at daycare is crazy hard it's crazy
在托儿所工作简直太难了，太难了。
expensive women want to be able to go
昂贵的女性希望能够去
back to work the list is really long
回去工作，清单真的很长。
about how hard it is in so many
关于在很多方面有多么困难
different ways you just remove those
移除这些物品的方法有很多种。
barriers
障碍
you especially once we're in this Robot
尤其是当我们进入这个机器人之后。
World which I don't think is far away
我认为那个世界离我们并不遥远
from us where I don't have to get up in
从我们这里，我不用起床。
the middle of the night and do that
半夜去做这件事
unless I want to I can if I want my
除非我愿意，否则我可以……如果我想要我的
robot's not going to stop me from
机器人阻止不了我
getting up and feeding them and changing
起床喂他们，给他们换尿布
their nappy but aren't we going to raise
他们的尿布，但我们难道不应该抚养他们吗？
loads of messed up kids in such a while
这么短的时间内出现了这么多问题儿童。
I don't I I you know robot has infinite
我不知道，你知道机器人有无限的
patience if you design it nice and soft
耐心点，设计得漂亮又柔软。
and fluffy it's going to be more cuddly
而且毛茸茸的，会更可爱。
than we are um the kids might like the
比我们更……嗯，孩子们可能会喜欢
robots more than they like us last night
昨晚机器人比我们更喜欢它们
I was with a with my girlfriend and I
我当时和我的女朋友在一起，我
was joking cuz I read this article that
我开玩笑的，因为我读过这篇文章。
Tesla's Optimus robots are now going
特斯拉的Optimus机器人现在正在
into production and they're hiring the
投入生产，他们正在招聘
team which are these sort of humanoid
团队由这类人形生物组成
robots that will be in your house and
将会出现在你家里的机器人
help with the chores and dishes and
帮忙做家务和洗碗
stuff and as a joke I turned to my
东西，然后我开玩笑地转向我的
partner I was like we'll get two of
我当时跟我的搭档说，我们会得到两个。
those and um like one of them will like
那些，嗯，就像其中一个会喜欢
like raise the kids and then the other
比如先养育孩子，然后再做其他事。
one would like take the kid to school
有人想送孩子去学校
and stuff cuz I knew her it was a joke I
还有其他一些事，因为我认识她，那只是个玩笑。
knew her reaction would be pretty
我知道她的反应会相当
negative negative and she was horrified
绝对否定，她感到非常害怕。
she goes can you imagine a world where a
她接着说，你能想象一个世界吗？
robot would the kid would turn to the
机器人会让孩子转向
robot and call it Daddy and Mommy cuz
机器人，叫它爸爸妈妈，因为
the kid wouldn't really know the
孩子其实并不了解
difference and I sat here with a child
区别在于，我和一个孩子坐在这里。
psychotherapist psychologist who said
心理治疗师兼心理学家说
that in those first three years it's so
在那最初的三年里，情况就是这样
critical for the primary caregiver to be
对于主要照护者而言，至关重要的是
around and that the man and the woman
周围，​​还有那男人和女人
caus the baby to release different types
导致婴儿释放不同类型的
of hormones based on their gender yeah
是的，激素水平会根据性别而变化。
so you almost can't the robot all that's
所以你几乎无法让机器人做这一切。
true but here's the thing currently we
没错，但目前的情况是这样的：
Outsource them to nannies for a big
把这些工作外包给保姆，这样可以省一大笔钱。
chunk of the day if you're wealthy
如果你有钱，一天中的大部分时间就花在这上面了。
enough people often hire a Night Nurse
很多人经常会雇佣夜间护士。
somebody who comes in and helps out in
进来帮忙的人
the at night time too if you've got the
晚上如果你有的话，也可以。
cash and so when I hire those people I
现金，所以当我雇佣这些人时，
can't be positive they're going to be
不能肯定他们会……
kind to my children I can't be positive
对我的孩子好，我无法肯定
they know every possible disease my kid
他们知道我孩子可能患的每一种疾病。
could get and and all the rest I would
可以得到，以及其他所有我会得到的。
rather hire this incredible robot who's
宁愿雇用这个了不起的机器人，他
super cuddly who has an encyclopedia of
超级可爱，而且拥有一部百科全书
medical knowledge who memorizes every
医学知识渊博，能记住所有细节
detail about my kid and knows exactly
对我的孩子了如指掌，而且非常了解。
what the the the pitch of that cry is
那声哭喊的音调是多少？
you could put whatever scent on them you
你可以给它们涂上任何你喜欢的香味。
want you could make it Mom or Dad you
希望你能做到，爸爸妈妈。
can make it even smell like you if you
如果你这样做，甚至可以让它闻起来像你。
want to why not have that person help
为什么不让那个人帮忙呢？
you out you know the our ancestors engag
你出去，你知道我们的祖先参与
in what in what's called aloe parenting
在所谓的芦荟育儿中
all the time and what that meant was the
一直以来都是如此，而这意味着……
men are out hunting probably gone for
男人们可能都出去打猎了
most of the day the females need to form
一天中的大部分时间，雌性都需要形成
these tight bonds with each other
他们之间有着如此紧密的联系
because it's hard work with a bunch of
因为这是一项艰苦的工作，而且需要很多人……
little kids and predators who want to
小孩子和想要……的捕食者
eat them you need eyes on them all the
吃掉它们，你需要时刻盯着它们。
time but you also need to be digging up
时间固然重要，但你也需要不断挖掘。
tubers of whatever variety you're trying
无论你尝试的是哪种块茎
to eat and so they ried on each other
为了吃饭，他们互相试探。
parenting is not a solo operation which
育儿不是一项单人活动，
is Mom and Dad it's this I know it's
是爸爸妈妈，我知道是他们。
cliche but it takes a village kind of
虽然老套，但确实需要全村之力。
thing so why not hire out this robot who
所以为什么不雇佣这个机器人呢？
is like perfect in every way you know
你知道，他简直完美无瑕。
they're not going to abuse your kid you
他们不会虐待你的孩子。
know they're never going to do anything
我知道他们永远不会采取任何行动。
wrong they're always going to be kind
错了，他们总是会很友善的。
when your kid ask for the 10 millionth
当你的孩子问你要第1000万个时
time but why they're going to keep
时间，但他们为什么要保留
giving them answers they don't mind
给他们答案，他们并不介意。
right why not have the perfect parent
没错，为什么不能拥有完美的父母呢？
when you're not there because um the
当你不在那里的时候，因为……
parent releases certain hormones in the
父母会释放某些激素
child by by their touch the oxytocin
婴儿通过触摸释放催产素
robots don't release oxytocin not
机器人不会释放催产素。
yet why not have a robot that mimics all
为什么不造一个能模仿一切的机器人呢？
that and would cause the kid to do that
那样做会导致孩子那样做。
too because you don't want to replace
也因为你不想替换
parenting is one of the it's one of the
育儿是其中之一，它是其中之一
nicest things that we humans ever do
我们人类做过的最美好的事
it's some of my Fondest Memories and I
那是我最美好的回忆之一，而且
don't want to give those away but I
我不想把那些东西送人，但是
wasn't with my kid 247 and it would have
我不是24小时都陪着我的孩子，而且本来会……
driven me nuts if I were it's kids are
如果我是孩子，我肯定会疯掉的。
are wonderful and boring and horrible
既精彩又无聊又可怕
and so why not when you Outsource and we
所以，为什么不选择外包呢？
all do we have since time began we've
自古以来，我们拥有的一切……
we've relied on others to help take care
我们一直依靠他人帮忙照顾家人。
of our kids why not make it the perfect
为什么不为我们的孩子打造一个完美的家呢？
Nanny rather than the that'll have to do
保姆而不是那个不得不做的事
Nanny because it's all I can afford I
因为我只能负担得起保姆。
just uh it's it's a strange feature to
嗯，这真是一个奇怪的功能。
think about because it feels also like a
想想看，因为它感觉也像是一个
slippery slope where we might start
我们可能会从滑坡谬误中开始
having kids and then giving them
生孩子，然后给他们
completely robot parents could do if you
如果你完全是机器人父母，你可以做到
wanted to I'd still rather that then you
我仍然宁愿那样，而不是你
abuse your kids and be a terrible parent
虐待孩子，做一个糟糕的父母
yourself which we know is happening all
你自己，我们都知道这一切正在发生
the time don't you think a better answer
你不觉得现在应该有更好的答案吗？
is just not to have the kids that is the
就是不想生孩子而已。
best answer but you can't stop people
最佳答案，但你无法阻止人们
from deciding to have kids and we know
从决定要孩子到我们知道
when we look at abusive parents for
当我们审视虐待型父母时
example and the kids if they're so bad
举例子，还有孩子们，如果他们那么糟糕的话
that their kids literally get taken away
他们的孩子真的会被带走
what do they do they move to a new town
他们会做什么？他们会搬到一个新的城镇。
and they have more and so you know that
他们还有更多，所以你知道的。
you're subjecting these children to
你正在让这些孩子遭受
these horrible environments but there's
这些环境糟透了，但还有
nothing you can do about it I would way
我对此无能为力。
rather that those parents who think they
而不是那些认为自己是父母的人
want kids for whatever reason then have
无论出于何种原因想要孩子，那就生吧。
the robot there to look out for them and
那里的机器人负责照看他们。
make sure that kid's well taken care of
确保孩子得到妥善照顾。
do you believe that do you believe
你相信吗？你相信吗？
that's going to be that's going to
那将会是，那将会是
happen so if you've just had a baby
如果你刚生完宝宝，这种情况就可能发生。
right yeah I've got a one and a half
对，我有一个半
year old one and a half year old would
一岁半的孩子
you allow a robot to I I love the
你允许机器人……我爱……
nannies I have but every single one of
我请过保姆，但每一个都是
them when you start is a risk you don't
当你开始的时候就选择它们，这是一种你不想承担的风险。
know right these are just they've been
我知道，这些就是他们一直以来的样子。
hired by the daycare they're probably
他们很可能是受雇于日托中心的。
really good but if you had the perfect
真的很好，但如果你拥有完美的话
robot Nanny well then you would never
机器人保姆，那你永远不会
worry at
担心
all and in marriage uh this graph that I
所有以及婚姻中的这一切，呃，这张图表，我
saw in your book shows that the
你书中的内容表明
percentage of Americans who are very
非常
happy or not too happy as a function of
快乐或不太快乐取决于
marital status quite clearly shows that
婚姻状况清楚地表明
if you want to be happy you should be
如果你想快乐，你就应该
married and if you want to be not too
已婚，如果你不想太
happy you should be separated so here's
很高兴你们分开了，所以这是……
the data if when people get married on
数据统计的是人们结婚的时间
average they get no
平均而言，他们没有
happier so if you get married and then I
如果你结婚了，我会更开心，然后我
look at 10 years later on average you're
十年后，平均而言，你会……
going to be exactly as you are now now
将会和你现在的样子一模一样
how does that average work out well in
这个平均值如何才能很好地发挥作用呢？
lots of different directions because I'm
有很多不同的方向，因为我
I'm putting everybody together now we've
我现在把大家都聚在一起。
got these amazing data sets for from
我从……获得了这些惊人的数据集
Germany for example where we track
例如，我们在德国进行追踪
people for so many years that we we know
人们如此之久，以至于我们都知道
what they were like before they even met
他们相遇之前的样子
their partner much less married them and
他们的伴侣更不用说和他们结婚了
so we see how happy they are and we see
所以我们看到他们有多开心，我们看到
how it changes over time and so for
随着时间的推移而如何变化，等等
example couples who get divorced they
例如，那些离婚的夫妇
actually their happiest year was the
事实上，他们最快乐的一年是……
year before their marriage so they met
他们结婚前一年就认识了。
their partner they got happier happier
他们的伴侣让他们更快乐。
and then they already started going
然后他们就开始走了
downhill before they even got married
他们还没结婚就开始走下坡路了
okay couples who were going to stay
好的，那些打算留下的夫妇
together their happiest year is the
他们共同度过的最幸福的一年是
marriage year itself not the year before
结婚当年，而不是前一年。
it so that's a good sign if you're
所以，如果你是这种情况，那是个好兆头。
happier when you're walking down the
当你沿着……行走时会更快乐
aisle than you were last year this
比去年同期要多。
marriage has a much better chance of
婚姻更有可能……
lasting now if you look at those
如果你看看那些，就会发现它们现在依然存在。
marriages the ones who last they go in
那些长久的婚姻，他们就此结婚。
three directions you've got the really
你已经朝三个方向走了。
bad ones where they stay together for
糟糕的是，他们会一直待在一起
economic or religious or whatever
经济的、宗教的或其他任何方面
reasons they're miserable they don't
他们不知道自己痛苦的原因
like each other and they're way less
他们彼此喜欢，而且他们之间的感情也淡了很多。
happy than before they met thankfully
他们比相遇之前更快乐了，这真是太好了。
they're relatively
它们相对来说
if we look at the ones who are average
如果我们看看那些平均水平的人，就会发现他们都很优秀。
they're a little bit happier these are
他们看起来更开心一些。
among couples who stay together they're
在那些一直在一起的伴侣中，他们是
a little bit happier for the first few
头几天稍微开心一点
years of their marriage than they were
他们结婚的年数比他们结婚的年数要多。
before they met and then they slowly
在他们相遇之前，他们慢慢地
settle down to about where they were so
他们安顿下来，回到了之前待的地方。
it's it's not plus or minus it's
它不是加号或减号，它是
basically where they were if you look at
基本上，如果你看一下他们当时的位置……
the really lucky folks they get happier
真正幸运的人会更快乐。
every single year for almost 10 years so
几乎每年都是如此，持续了近十年。
their the year of their marriage was
他们的结婚年份是
happier than before they met and the
他们比相遇之前更快乐了，而且
next year's happier still and it just
明年会更快乐，而且就是这样
keeps working its way up and
它不断向上移动，
so when you aage all that together
所以当你把所有这些加在一起的时候
getting married doesn't make you happy
结婚并不会让你快乐。
it's a it's a zero so how could it be
它是零，怎么可能是零呢？
that marriage is a zero and I think the
婚姻毫无价值，我认为
answer to that question is that people
这个问题的答案是人们
who don't marry it's not the fact that
不结婚的人，这并不是事实
they didn't marry that's the problem
他们没结婚，这就是问题所在。
it's that they're overweighting autonomy
问题在于他们过分强调了自主性。
and overweighting it is probably what
而超重可能就是原因。
they're doing everywh else in their life
他们生活中还在做其他各种各样的事情
as well so when they're making decisions
所以当他们做决定时也是如此。
about what to do with their friends
关于如何与朋友们相处
about whether they live with somebody
关于他们是否与某人同住
else or live alone all those decisions
否则，或者独自生活，所有这些决定
they keep going with autonomy rather
他们继续保持自主性
than going with connection now that
比现在通过连接更合适
doesn't necessarily mean they're going
但这并不一定意味着他们会离开。
to be unhappy but it makes on average it
虽然不快乐，但平均而言，它使它变得不快乐。
means that they're about half as likely
这意味着他们的可能性大约只有原来的一半。
to be very happy as somebody who would
像那样感到非常快乐
go and get married so the it's the
去结婚吧，这样就……
individualism yes that's causing their
个人主义，没错，这就是导致他们的原因。
unhappiness that's causing them not to
导致他们不愿……的不快乐
marry yep that's what I believe and
结婚？是的，我也是这么想的。
people that are less individualistic are
不那么个人主义的人
getting married and that's why and and
结婚，这就是原因。
so it's just a different kind of person
所以，这只是另一种类型的人而已。
who's doing that in the same sense
谁在做同样的事情
interestingly if you look at divorce we
有趣的是，如果你看看离婚……
can also see that the people who are
还可以看到那些人
going to get divorced were also less
打算离婚的人也较少。
happy before they even met their partner
在遇到伴侣之前，他们就已经很幸福了。
so on average people tend to stay
所以平均而言，人们往往会留下来
together in marriages we don't know why
我们一起步入婚姻，却不知为何
that is but my guess is that happier
也就是说，但我猜想那样会更快乐。
people just tend to be happier about
人们往往会更快乐
everything and so they're less like they
一切，所以他们不太像他们
they find ways to make their marriage
他们会想方设法维系婚姻。
work even if it's no better than the
即使效果不如预期，也要继续工作。
marriage of the less happy
不太幸福的婚姻
Folks at my company flight Studio which
我公司 Flight Studio 的同事们
is part of my bigger company flight
这是我所在公司更大航班的一部分
group we're constantly looking for ways
我们团队一直在寻找各种方法
to build deeper connections with our
与我们建立更深层次的联系
audiences whether that's a new show a
无论这是一档新节目，观众都会喜欢它。
product or a project it's why I launched
这就是我推出产品或项目的原因。
the conversation cards I've relied on
我一直依赖的对话卡片
Shopify before who's a sponsor of
Shopify之前是谁的赞助商？
today's podcast and I'll be using them
今天的播客，我将使用它们
again for the next big launch which
再次为下一次重大发布做准备，
we'll hear about soon and I use them
我们很快就会听到消息，我会使用它们。
because of how easy it is to set up an
因为设置起来非常容易
online store that reaches all of you no
一家能够触达你们所有人的在线商店
matter where you are in the world with
无论你身处世界何处
Shopify the usual pain points of
Shopify常见的痛点
launching products online Disappear
在线推出产品后消失
Completely no matter the size of your
完全无论你的尺寸大小
business Shopify has everything you need
Shopify 企业版拥有您所需的一切
to make your business go to the next
让你的企业迈向下一个阶段
level and better connect with your
提升水平，更好地与你的
customers all over the world to say
世界各地的顾客都这么说
thank you to all of you for listening to
感谢各位的收听。
my show we're giving you a trial which
我的节目正在给你一次试播，
is just $1 a month you can sign up by
每月只需​​ 1 美元，即可注册
going to to shopify.com
前往 shopify.com
Bartlet that's shopify.com Bartlet or
巴特利特，那是 shopify.com 巴特利特或
find the link in the description
在描述中查找链接。
below and what about things like ADHD
下面还有像多动症之类的疾病呢？
and neurod Divergence is there an
神经多样性是否存在？
evolutionary basis for why why that
进化论基础解释了为什么会这样
occurs yes so the um neurod Divergence
是的，所以，嗯，神经分歧
is a complicated one the
这是一个复杂的问题。
um it seems to be much more common now
嗯，现在这种情况似乎越来越常见了。
when we look at the epidemiological data
当我们查看流行病学数据时
it seems to be associated with high
它似乎与高有关
toxin environments so if you live in in
所以，如果你生活在有毒的环境中，
areas where there's lots of pollutants
污染严重的地区
people are more likely to be neurod
人们更有可能患有神经衰弱症。
Divergent but I think neurod Divergence
分歧，但我认为神经分歧
has always been with this I think it's
一直以来都是这样，我觉得是这样。
just become more common now why would it
现在这种情况变得越来越普遍，为什么会这样呢？
become more common with these various
随着这些因素变得越来越普遍
toxins I don't know my guess is that the
毒素我不知道，我的猜测是……
brain is a social organism the human
大脑是人类的社会性有机体
brain is we've evolved connection is our
大脑是我们进化而来的，连接是我们
most important need and it requires all
最重要的需求，它需要所有
sorts of different parts to work right
各种不同的部件需要协同工作才能正常运转。
which means that that if you break the
这意味着如果你打破了
brain in any way you're going to break
无论如何，你的大脑都会崩溃
your sociality because it's so
你的社交能力，因为它如此
implicated in so many different areas
牵涉到许多不同领域
and if these um toxins that we're
如果这些毒素是我们所……
exposed to cause any damage to the brain
暴露于会对大脑造成任何损害的环境中
I think you're particularly likely to
我认为你特别有可能
end up with social problems because the
最终导致社会问题，因为
brain is a social organ and so that's
大脑是社交器官，所以……
why I think autism rates are R Rising
为什么我认为自闭症发病率正在上升
but of course I don't know I'm only
但我当然不知道，我只是
guessing based on the data I've seen now
根据我目前看到的数据进行猜测
in the case of neurod Divergence I think
就神经多样性而言，我认为
they've always played a really important
他们一直扮演着非常重要的角色。
role in humanity and the reason for that
在人类社会中的作用及其原因
is that you know humans are super
你知道人类是超级的
Innovative species but if you ask
创新物种，但如果你问
yourself or your friends how often have
你或你的朋友多久会……
you ever invented anything the answer is
你发明过什么东西吗？答案是……
almost always never
几乎从不
and and that's because we solve our
那是因为我们解决了我们的
problems socially when something goes
当某些事情发生时，社会上就会出现问题。
wrong we go to our friends we talk to
错了，我们去找朋友聊天
them we try to work together to figure
我们尝试共同努力找出答案
out our problems and we've always been
我们解决了所有问题，我们一直都是
that way hunted gatherers do that and
狩猎采集者就是这样做的。
neurod Divergent people are less likely
神经多样性人群不太可能
to do that because they're less socially
这样做是因为他们不太善于社交。
connected and so probably most of the
已连接，因此可能大部分
great inventions of humanity were
人类的伟大发明是
created by neurodivergent people now
由神经多样性人群创作
those of us who are not neurodivergent
我们这些非神经多样性人群
immediately go wow I'd like one of those
立刻惊呼：哇，我也想要一个！
and so we're really good at spreading
因此，我们非常擅长传播。
that by virtue of our social networks
凭借我们的社交网络
but I think we've always relied on
但我认为我们一直以来都依赖于
neurodivergent people to create the
让神经多样性人群创造
amazing innovations that the technical
技术创新令人惊叹
things that that make our lives so easy
那些让我们的生活如此轻松的事物
now ADHD is a a different ball wax we
现在，多动症的情况就完全不同了。
know it's highly heritable we know a lot
我们知道它具有很高的遗传性，我们了解很多。
of the genes are we also suspect that it
基因也是我们怀疑的。
didn't it wasn't even a noticeable thing
难道不是吗？这甚至都不是什么引人注目的事。
in a hunter gather right you know what
在狩猎采集时代，你知道吗？
ancestor ever tried to get you to pay
祖先是否曾试图让你付钱
attention to something that you were
关注你所关注的事物
bored with but if you're ADHD it's crazy
无聊，但如果你有注意力缺陷多动障碍，那就太疯狂了。
hard to pay attention when you're bored
无聊的时候很难集中注意力。
but it's perfectly easy to pay attention
但集中注意力却非常容易。
when you're interested you just don't
当你感兴趣的时候，你就不会……
have the kind of dorsal lateral
具有背侧侧向的类型
prefrontal cortex that ows you to force
前额叶皮层让你不得不强迫你
yourself to attend to things and for our
你自己去处理事情，为了我们
ancestors you're loaded with energy
祖先们，你们能量充沛
you're probably a great Hunter and so
你可能是一位很棒的猎人，所以
it's it's a modern problem that you have
这是你遇到的一个现代问题。
to sit still and listen problem which
静静地坐着倾听这个问题
our ancestors were never asked to do I
我们的祖先从未被要求这样做。
wonder if it will still be the case when
不知道这种情况是否还会持续下去
we have all the robots in the AI doing
我们有所有人工智能机器人在做
everything for I'm betting not I'm
我赌的一切，不是我
betting that you could decide to learn
我打赌你可能会决定学习
or not learn now why would you even
或者现在不学，你为什么要学？
learn your multiplication tables if you
如果你愿意，就去学习乘法表吧。
don't need to you can just ask your
不需要，你可以直接问你的
phone what the answer is and so why tons
电话里问答案是什么，所以为什么会有这么多人
of the schooling that we go through is
我们所接受的教育是
Superfluous in this world where a AI can
在这个人工智能可以实现的时代，这显得多余。
do everything that we can do do you
尽我们所能，你呢？
think we're going emerge with um
我觉得我们会和……一起出现
technology more deeply it's very
技术更深层次来说非常
possible you could easily imagine like
有可能，你很容易就能想象到，比如
if there's a feature about yourself that
如果你身上有某种特质，
you don't like I suspect it'll be hard
你不喜欢的话，我怀疑这会很难。
to genetically engineer it and the
通过基因工程改造它
reason I think it would be hard to
原因我认为很难……
genetically engineer it is that most of
通过基因工程改造，大部分
our genes have more than one effect and
我们的基因具有不止一种作用，
most of our traits are caused by more
我们的大多数特征都是由更多因素造成的。
than one gene so you can't just tweak
不止一个基因，所以你不能只是简单地调整
one Gene and become the person you
一个基因，让你成为你想成为的人
wanted to be it's going to have other
想要成为它将有其他
effects that you may not want so the the
可能产生你不希望出现的效果
upshot is that
结果是
why not you know have a little mind
为什么不呢？你知道，你得有点心思。
module that you either attaches to your
你可以将模块连接到你的
head or goes inside it even or you know
头或者进去，甚至你知道
we already are treating people with this
我们已经在用这种方法治疗患者了。
there's some kinds of depression that
有些类型的抑郁症
just are untreatable and for some of
有些疾病无法治疗，而且对某些人来说……
those people they literally insert an
他们真的插入了
electrode into their brain and stimulate
将电极插入他们的大脑并刺激
this particular region and and the
这个特定地区和
people who experience it say it's like
经历过的人说，这就像……
my world was in black and white and
我的世界是黑白的，
suddenly it became in color well why not
突然间它变成了彩色的，为什么呢？
have that for knowledge that you can
拥有这种知识，你就能……
access you know I could spend my huge
你知道我可以花掉我的巨款
amounts of time studying Greek or I
学习希腊语的时间或我
could shove one of the goes in and now I
可以把其中一个塞进去，现在我
can go to Greece and speak with the
可以去希腊和……交谈
locals right without my phone telling me
当地人就在我手机没通知我的情况下就告诉我了
what they're saying you mentioned
他们说的就是你提到的那些话。
depression that what's the evolutionary
抑郁症是什么？进化论
basis for humans getting depressed and
人类患抑郁症的原因和
anxious because presumably that's that's
焦虑是因为大概就是这样。
not productive for our survival not so
对我们的生存来说并非有益
remember that that with every generation
记住，每一代人都是如此。
with sexual reproduction you're going to
通过有性生殖，你将……
have people who have things that maybe
有些人可能拥有一些东西
Evolution wouldn't like remember earlier
进化论不会记得更早的事情
we talked about homosexuality that if
我们谈到了同性恋，如果
you have more gay genes women like you
你身上有更多像你这样的同性恋基因，女性也喜欢你。
more but then if you have too many you
越多越好，但如果你太多了……
don't like them in return right so
不喜欢他们，对吧？
that's a case where a little little bit
那是一个稍微有点儿……的情况。
is a good thing evolutionarily and a lot
从进化角度来看，这是一件好事，而且很多方面都是如此。
is a bad thing evolutionarily because
从进化角度来看，这是一件坏事，因为
you're not going to have Offspring not a
你不会有后代，不是吗？
moral judgment just a judgment based on
道德判断只是基于……的判断
what evolution cares about well with
进化论关心的是什么？
anxiety that makes perfect sense right
这种焦虑完全可以理解，对吧？
so animals that can't Envision the
所以那些无法想象的动物
future have no anxiety all they feel is
未来没有焦虑，他们只感到……
fear in the moment oops there's a lion
当时很害怕，哎呀，有头狮子！
I'd better run as fast as I possibly can
我最好拼命跑。
and then as soon as they've run away oh
然后他们刚一逃走，哦
no lion life is co everything's
没有狮子的生活是共生的，一切都是。
copesthetic I'll go back to eating grass
假肢 我还是回去吃草吧
and being happy whereas if I'm a human
如果我是一个人类，我会感到快乐
running away from a line be oh my God
逃离警戒线，我的天哪
that was really scary I wonder when
那真是太可怕了，我想知道什么时候
there's another line coming now the
现在还有另一条线路。
biggest gift that Evolution gave us is
进化给予我们的最大礼物是
the capacity to simulate the future
模拟未来的能力
Evolution doesn't give any gifts without
进化不会无缘无故地给予任何礼物。
costs you pay a price for every one of
每一项都需要付出代价。
them and the capacity to simulate the
它们以及模拟它们的能力
future also comes with the realization
未来也伴随着这样的认识而来。
it is first of all it's not always going
首先，它并非总是如此。
to be good and second of all it's always
首先要善良，其次，它总是
going to end badly once you understand
一旦你明白这一点，结局就会很糟糕。
life you understand I'm going to die
你明白，我终将死去。
someday and the other animals don't have
总有一天，其他动物却没有
that realization they can't project
他们无法将这种认识投射出去。
themselves forward in time the way we
他们自己随着时间的推移而前进，就像我们一样
can so does that mean that Evolution
所以，这是否意味着进化论
tells us that the cure for anxiety is to
告诉我们，治疗焦虑的方法是
stop thinking about the future
别再想未来了。
effectively if you didn't think about
如果你没有考虑到这一点，那就不会有效了。
the future you would not be anxious if
如果未来你不会感到焦虑，
you could get yourself to be mindful in
你可以让自己在以下方面保持专注：
the moment and set aside the future your
把握当下，暂时放下未来。
anxiety will disappear because it's all
焦虑会消失，因为这一切都是空想。
future based I was something that really
我曾经是那种着眼于未来的人，这真的
um I found quite interesting as well in
嗯，我也觉得挺有意思的。
your book I think it was in chapter nine
你的书，我记得是在第九章。
where you talk about
你在哪里谈论
religion and the fact that people that
宗教以及人们……这一事实
are associated with religious
与宗教有关
participation are typically more happy
参与者通常会更快乐
than those who are not the effect is
比那些没有这种影响的人更甚。
remarkable and so you can look at it in
非常出色，所以你可以这样看待它
two different ways is one of just the
两种不同的方式只是其中之一
effect of believing right so lots of
相信正确会产生很多影响
people worry about a life without
人们担忧没有生活的生活
meaning you know people of religion have
意思是你知道宗教人士有
solve that problem because religion
解决这个问题是因为宗教
gives your life meaning there is a point
赋予你生命意义，这其中必有缘由。
if you believe any of the religions that
如果你信仰任何一种宗教，
exist you're part of this NeverEnding
存在，你是这永无止境的一部分
chain Etc and it doesn't they can be
连锁等等，但它不会，它们可以是
wildely different religions but they all
截然不同的宗教，但它们都
hold this notion that there's there's
坚持认为存在着……
something before and something after now
之前和之后的事情
you can look at the effect of that by
你可以通过以下方式来观察其影响：
saying all right let's select only
好吧，我们只选择
people who never go to church so we
那些从不去教堂的人，所以我们
won't we'll take the sociality part out
我们是不是应该把社交性部分去掉？
of it and then we'll look at people who
然后我们会看看那些人
pray versus people who don't pray and we
祷告的人与不祷告的人，我们
can do this with these National samples
可以用这些国家样本来完成这项工作。
um where we say let's look at the
嗯，我们说，让我们看看……
General Social Survey and in fact
综合社会调查和事实
anybody wants to can get online and look
任何人都可以上网查看。
at the General Social Survey and answer
在综合社会调查中回答
any question that's available in that
任何可以在该范围内提出的问题
it's a remarkably remarkable publicly
这是一个非常了不起的公开场合
available data set which I used
我使用的可用数据集
repeatedly in this book and praying
本书中反复提及并祈祷
actually makes you happier if you among
实际上，如果你身处其中，你会更快乐。
people who don't go to church they're
不去教堂的人
not praying and in my mind that's that's
不祈祷，在我看来，就是这样。
life has meaning versus it doesn't
生命有意义还是没有意义？
people who have religion have meaning
有宗教信仰的人具有意义
people don't often don't sometimes they
人们不经常不，有时他们
do but they often don't but there's a
会，但他们通常不会，但有一种
social component to religion as well and
宗教也包含社会因素。
I think it's way more important and so
我认为这重要得多，所以
now you can you can't do it quite as
现在你可以，但你不能完全做到。
cleanly now you want people who go to
现在干净利落地，你想要去的人
church and you want to look at the
教堂，你想看看
effect of going to church and there the
去教堂的影响以及那里
data are remarkable the effect of going
数据非常显著，去
to church is huge it's like you're like
去教堂意义重大，就像你……
twice as likely to be happy if you go to
如果你去……，幸福的可能性会是原来的两倍。
church regularly than if you never go to
经常去教堂比从不去教堂要好得多。
church at all now I don't think going to
我现在根本不想去教堂了。
church would have made our ancestors any
教会本可以使我们的祖先……
happier at all why does it make us
为什么这会让我们更快乐？
happier well the way to answer that
更快乐，回答这个问题的办法就是……
question is to then dive a little deeper
接下来的问题是如何更深入地探讨这个问题。
into the data and so what I did is I
将数据输入系统，所以我所做的就是……
separated people by whether they're poor
按贫穷程度将人们分开。
or whether they're rich now remember
或者他们现在是否富有，请记住这一点。
earlier we talked about how the fact
我们之前讨论过这个事实
that poor people live in these tight
穷人就住在这些拥挤的地方。
interdependent networks because they
相互依存的网络，因为它们
count on each other all the time they
他们一直互相依靠。
borrow things from each other they rely
他们互相借东西，互相依赖
on each other to keep the boat afloat
他们互相依靠，使船不沉没。
and so they have they get together poor
于是他们聚到了一起，变得很穷。
people get together with their neighbors
人们与邻居们聚会
much more often than rich people right
比富人更常发生这种情况
rich people don't do that so what that
有钱人不会那样做，那又怎样？
means is that if now if you think that
意思是，如果你现在认为
God wants you to go to church if because
上帝希望你去教堂，如果……
remember we're talking about religion
记住，我们谈论的是宗教。
now then you're going to go to church
那么，你现在要去教堂了。
even if you don't necessarily want to
即使你未必想要
see the people there even if you don't
即使你不在那里，你也能看到那里的人们。
necessarily feel a need for them but
未必会觉得需要它们，但
you're going to be forced into
你将会被迫
socializing so it's sort of like this
社交活动大概就是这样
experiment that's being played on you
这是在你身上进行的一项实验。
whether you believe in or not whe if you
无论你是否相信，如果你
believe you should go to church that's
相信你应该去教堂。
kind of coming from on high it's not
感觉像是来自上层，不是这样的
because you necessarily want to
因为你必然想要
socialize and we see that the effects of
社交活动，我们看到其影响
going to church are they have bigger
去教堂的人更多
happiness effects on Rich than on poor
幸福感对富人的影响比对穷人的影响更大。
because poor people are getting a lot of
因为穷人得到了很多
the benefit already of that social of
社会福利已经带来的益处
socializing whereas rich people have
社交，而富人则有
separated themselves from others and so
他们与他人隔离开来，因此
those rich people who go to church
那些去教堂的有钱人
several times a week are like twice as
每周几次就相当于两倍
likely to be very happy as rich people
富人可能会非常幸福
who never go to church at all so rich
那些从不去教堂的富人
people need to go to church yeah or you
人们需要去教堂，是的，否则你
know whatever they call Church they need
他们要知道，无论他们称之为教会，他们都需要什么。
to go somewhere where they're
去他们所在的地方
socializing regularly in person why do
为什么应该定期进行面对面的社交活动？
we want religion because it's quite
我们想要宗教，因为它相当
clear that there's something within us
很明显，我们内心深处有某种东西。
that wants to believe you see this I I
那个想相信你看到这个的人
think we're seeing a little bit at the
我觉得我们已经看到了一些端倪。
moment where we're seeing a return to
我们看到回归的时刻
religious belief in some degree I know
我知道自己在某种程度上拥有宗教信仰。
that it's you know it might not just be
你知道，这可能不仅仅是……
the religious belief that we think of it
我们所认为的宗教信仰
might be spirituality or horoscopes or
可能是灵性、星座运势或其他方面。
whatever it you know it might be but
不管你知道它是什么，但
there's a seems like there's a real
似乎真的有
surge of it especially amongst young men
这种现象在年轻人中尤为普遍。
yeah that's a great question people talk
是的，这是个好问题，大家都在讨论。
about in Psychology what what they refer
关于心理学中他们指的是什么
to well not just in Psychology but in
不仅在心理学领域，而且在
psychological terms as a god-shaped
心理学术语，如同神形
whole there's a hole in your psyche that
你的心灵深处有一个空洞，
can only be filled by God whatever God
只有上帝才能充满一切。
is for you
是给你的
and I think lots of people have that
我认为很多人都有这种感觉。
hole but not everybody and why do I
洞，但不是每个人都这样，为什么我
think lots of people have it well
我认为很多人都过得很好。
remember those prayer data we talked
还记得我们讨论过的那些祈祷数据吗？
about people who pray are happier on
据说祈祷的人更快乐
average than people who don't and so if
平均而言，比不这样做的人要好，所以如果
you have a god-shaped hole but you don't
你有一个神形的洞，但你没有
believe that's going to make you unhappy
相信那会让你不开心
whereas if you have that need for that
而如果你有那种需求的话
and you do believe that's going to make
而且你确实相信那会……
you happy it's like anything else what
你很高兴，这和其他事情一样吗？
do you think the meaning of life is I
你认为人生的意义是什么？
think it's devoid of meaning and so if
认为它毫无意义，所以如果
life is truly devoid of meaning then
那么，人生就真的毫无意义了。
what do you do and the only answer to me
你做什么工作？我唯一的答案就是这个。
is you make the best of this meaningless
你是否充分利用了这毫无意义的一切
thing that you can and how do you do
你能做什么，以及你是怎么做的
that well you you be aware of what we've
你应该清楚我们已经做了什么
evolved to do and we've evolved to
进化是为了做到这一点，我们也进化到了这一点。
connect and so if connection is the most
连接，因此如果连接是最重要的
important thing I can do as a human and
作为一个人，我能做的一件重要的事情
I believe it is then you be kind to each
我相信那时你就会善待每个人。
other because that's facilitating
其他原因是为了方便
connection you believe life is devoid of
你认为生活中缺乏的联系
meaning yeah people won't like that I
意思是，是的，人们不会喜欢那样。
know I don't like it I don't like the
我知道我不喜欢它，我不喜欢它
fact that I don't think life has meaning
事实上，我认为人生没有意义。
when people search for meaning they they
当人们寻找意义时，他们
get happier which suggests that they
变得更快乐，这表明他们
find it I've never actually taken the
我发现我实际上从未服用过
time to reflect and search for meaning
是时候反思和探寻意义了。
okay so but maybe it's the the pursuit
好吧，但也许关键在于追求本身。
of something then that's creating the
然后，某种东西就创造了
happiness versus them finding H meaning
幸福与他们寻找H的意义
maybe we don't know you so you just said
也许我们不认识你，所以你才这么说。
that when people search for meaning they
当人们寻找意义时
get happier yeah so that could imply one
变得更快乐，是的，所以这可能意味着一个
of two things that they end up finding
他们最终发现的两件事。
it or that it's the search itself or a
它，或者说它是搜索本身，或者是一个
little both it's usually a little of
两者都很少，通常只有一点点
both but we don't know with certainty
两者皆有，但我们无法确定。
there's not enough good data on this
这方面的可靠数据还不够。
problem because lots of people search
因为很多人都在搜索，所以存在问题。
for meaning and in the end you can also
为了意义，最终你也可以
decide that well there isn't meaning and
认定这没有意义，
I'm a small Cog in a big machine and I'm
我只是大机器里的一颗小齿轮，而我
a pointless small Cog in a big machine
大机器中一个毫无意义的小齿轮
but it's all I've got and so you know
但这是我全部的家当，所以你知道的
Richard Dawkins and unweaving the
理查德·道金斯和解构
rainbow says we're the lucky ones
彩虹说我们是幸运儿
because we're going to get to die now
因为我们现在就要死了
what he really means by that is we first
他真正的意思是我们首先
we get to live and almost nobody gets to
我们得以活着，而几乎没有人能做到这一点。
live right you think of the 100 million
好好生活，想想那1亿
sperm that I'm making every day they
我每天产生的精子
don't go anywhere they never get a
不要去任何地方，他们永远不会得到
chance and but I made three humans I did
机会，但我创造了三个人类，我做到了。
my part I only did the small part but I
我只做了我那一小部分工作，但我
was played a role in making three humans
在三个人类的形成过程中发挥了作用
who then got lucky and got to live out
然后他们运气好，得以住进外面。
of all the other sperm that came out
所有其他射出的精子
that day they're the one that made it
那天，是他们做到了。
into the egg and they get a chance at it
进入蛋中，它们就有机会了。
and we just happen to be really lucky I
我们碰巧非常幸运。
believe as humans that the solution that
作为人类，我们相信解决方案是
Evolution landed us on was a kind one we
进化最终带给我们的结局是一个仁慈的结局。
have the kindest solution in my mind to
我心中已想出最仁慈的解决办法。
solving life's problems so you look at
解决生活中的问题，所以你看着
this one of my favorite birds in
这是我最喜欢的鸟类之一。
Australia is the cucura cucur lay two
澳大利亚是 cucura cucur 两岁
eggs and then they weigh a little bit
鸡蛋，然后它们会稍微重一些。
and then they lay a third and Australia
然后他们铺设了第三层，澳大利亚
is very drought prone so some seasons
该地区极易发生干旱，因此某些季节……
are good and some are bad if the
有些是好的，有些则是坏的，如果
season's good that third egg has a
这个季节很好，第三个鸡蛋有……
decent chance of making it to adulthood
有相当大的机会活到成年
because there's so much food being
因为食物太多了
brought back to the nest if it's not
如果不是，就把它带回巢穴。
good that third egg never makes it and
幸好第三个蛋没能孵化出来。
why doesn't it make it well the two
为什么它不能使两者相处融洽
older siblings peck it to death and
哥哥姐姐们把它啄死
they've got a adaptation on their beak a
它们的喙上有一种适应性特征。
little hook that allows them to kill
用来杀死它们的小钩子
their little sibling more easily so
他们的弟弟妹妹更容易做到这一点
they've literally evolved to kill their
它们实际上已经进化到会互相残杀的地步了。
little sibling when times are tough
小弟弟在艰难时期
what have we evolved to do when times
我们进化到什么程度才能应对时代挑战
are tough to band even closer together
他们很难更加紧密地团结在一起。
and to work together and to cooperate
共同努力，互相合作
that's what got us to where we are and
正是这一点让我们走到今天。
it was all sorts of interesting things
真是各种各样有趣的事情。
that got us there was cognitive things
让我们走到这一步的是认知方面的事情。
like division of labor you know cers
就像劳动分工一样，你知道的。
don't do that because they're inherently
不要那样做，因为它们本质上是
mean it's the only way they can solve
这意味着这是他们解决问题的唯一方法。
the problem humans solve that problem
人类解决这个问题
very differently now admittedly we did
现在情况确实大不相同了，我们确实如此。
our share of infanticide too but mostly
我们也有一部分杀婴行为，但大部分
what we do is cooperate work together
我们所做的就是合作共事。
have division of labor and we go from
我们有劳动分工，然后我们从
being this like you know when we first
就像你知道我们最初那样
left the trees must have been really
留下的树木一定非常……
rough every was eating us for dinner and
粗暴的一切都让我们晚餐饱餐一顿。
now it's the shoes on the other foot
现在角色互换了。
we're the apex predator on this planet
我们是这个星球上的顶级掠食者。
but doesn't our evolutionary history
但我们的进化史难道不是如此吗？
tell us that we ban together in tough
告诉我们，我们要团结起来，共克时艰。
times yes but we band together to attack
确实有几次，但我们会团结起来反击。
the others yeah we do it's not look
其他人，是的，我们这样做，看起来不像。
there's there's never something that's
从来没有什么东西是
done just for the niceness of it
纯粹是为了好玩才这么做的
Evolution doesn't care about nice at all
进化根本不在乎善良与否
what's really nice though is that our
不过，真正令人欣慰的是，我们的
solution our our way of becoming deadly
解决方案，我们变得致命的方式
and every animal that survives becomes
所有幸存的动物都变成了
deadly or avoids being eaten in another
致命的或避免被其他生物吃掉
way now it turns out that once you band
现在看来，一旦你组建了乐队
together and as even by hom rectus once
一起，甚至像直肠人一样
so our ancestors one and two million
所以，我们的祖先一两百万
years ago when they band together they
多年前，当他们团结起来的时候
are already the deadliest force in this
已经是这方面最致命的力量了。
planet we've got good evidence that
我们有充分的证据表明，在这个星球上，
they're eating huge animals like
它们吃的是体型巨大的动物，比如
mammoths so it's your ability had to
猛犸象，所以这是你的能力。
have division of labor to plan to say
有劳动分工来计划说
all right you chase that Mammoth and
好吧，你去追那头猛犸象吧。
we'll put this trap here you know do
我们会在这里设下这个陷阱，你知道的。
things at other animals simply can't
其他动物根本做不到的事情
they can't do that they can't make a
他们做不到，他们做不到
scenario in their mind and then enact it
在脑海中构思场景，然后付诸行动。
and so it was that mental ability that
因此，正是这种心理能力
turned us into these apex predators but
把我们变成了这些顶级掠食者，但是
it doesn't take long as an apex predator
作为顶级掠食者，它不需要太长时间就能胜任。
who can work together with division of
能够与部门合作的人
labor to realize all right there's only
努力实现这一切，好吧，只有
one Predator left on this planet who has
地球上只剩下一个铁血战士了，他
a chance of killing me and that's other
有可能要了我的命，还有另一件事。
humans or if you know if it's prehuman
人类，或者如果你知道它是否是人类之前的生物。
other homoerectus and you're saying that
其他直立人，你的意思是……
with like America versus China and
就像美国与中国之间的对抗一样
America versus Mexico and whatever it
美国对墨西哥，以及其他种种
might be the nationalism yeah so
可能是民族主义吧。
remember I referred to us earlier as
还记得我之前提到我们时是……
being tribal and I talked about how
我谈到了部落文化，以及如何
chimpanzees are 600 times more
黑猩猩是它们的600倍。
aggressive within the group but equally
在群体内部具有攻击性，但在群体内部则不然。
aggressive between so we've evolved in a
彼此之间充满攻击性，所以我们进化成了一种
world to be totally tribal to just look
世界完全是部落式的，只是看看
out for ourselves because that other
我们为自己着想，因为其他
group might kill us they may be nice we
这群人可能会杀了我们，他们也可能对我们很好。
may get along but they might be vicious
他们或许相处融洽，但也可能互相残杀
and so we need to be prepared to be
因此，我们需要做好准备。
vicious in return thankfully though we
幸好，我们遭到了恶毒的报复。
didn't evolve where we know where
并非在我们所知的地点进化而来
they're vicious we evolved where we just
它们很凶猛，我们进化到了现在的地步。
don't know it may be good and it may be
不知道，它可能好，也可能不好。
bad so we give our groups the benefit of
不好，所以我们给我们的团队带来好处
the doubt but we very quickly become
怀疑，但我们很快就会变成
tribal and negative toward them I was
我对他们抱有部落主义和负面态度。
sat here um yesterday
昨天我坐在这里。
with the wonderful gentleman who I'm a
和我在一起的，是一位很棒的绅士
big fan of called Robert Green who wrote
我是罗伯特·格林的忠实粉丝，他写道
the book about power mhm 48 Laws of
关于权力的书，嗯，48条法则
Power what have you learned about power
权力，你对权力有什么了解？
as it relates to our evolutionary past
就我们进化史而言
and who ends up getting power in the
以及最终谁会获得权力。
world so Evolution doesn't care about
世界，所以进化并不关心
morality right it's aoral it's not
道德是对的，它是口头的，它不是
immoral it just doesn't care and what
它不道德，它根本不在乎，还有什么？
that means is might is Right humans are
这意味着强权即真理，人类是
the only ones who understand possession
只有那些理解占有的人。
and I say this is mine and you're like
我说这是我的，你就说
no no it's mine and we can argue about
不不，这是我的，我们可以争论。
the actual ownership of it but for an
它的实际所有权，但对于一个
animal there there's never an argument
那里的动物从来不会争吵
if you made the kill and I'm bigger than
如果你成功猎杀了目标，而我比你更大
you I take it from you now in human
我现在以人类的身份从你那里接受它
groups power is achieved by no human is
群体权力并非由任何人取得
strong enough on their own to have power
他们自身实力足够强大，能够掌握权力。
bys every human goes to sleep and when
每个人都会睡觉，当
when you go to sleep the weakest of
当你入睡时，最弱的
humans in your group can kill you easily
你队伍里的人很容易就能杀了你。
and so to be powerful you you part of it
所以，要想拥有权力，你就是其中的一部分。
is to be tough and scary but part of it
既要强悍又要吓人，但这只是其中的一部分。
also to be kind and to look out for
也要友善待人，互相照顾。
people who are on your side so that you
那些站在你这边的人，这样你
have a network of people who care about
拥有一个关心此事的人员网络
you and what about body language in this
你，还有，这其中的肢体语言呢？
as it relates to power is there anything
就权力而言，有什么问题吗？
that we can learn from humans and other
我们可以从人类和其他方面学习。
animals about
关于动物
what powerful body language is or UNP
什么是强有力的肢体语言？或者说，什么是统一国民党（UNP）
powerful or powerless body language
强势或无力的肢体语言
looks like it's super easy to look in
看起来很容易就能查看。
other animals because because they can't
其他动物，因为它们不能
talk they appease they got ways of
他们用言语安抚人心，他们有办法
shrinking themselves and says no no
他们缩小了身形，说不，不
don't beat me up this whatever you want
别打我，随便你。
is yours and humans mimic some of that
这是你的，而人类模仿了其中的一些。
we shrink ourselves when when we want to
当我们想要缩小自己时，我们就会缩小自己。
not be intimidating we Elevate ourselves
我们不会咄咄逼人，而是提升自我。
we open ourselves when we want to be
我们想敞开心扉的时候就会敞开自己
powerful and intimidating but in humans
强大而令人畏惧，但在人类中
almost all humans almost all the time
几乎所有人类几乎总是
power doesn't emanate from our physical
力量并非源于我们的肉体。
presence but from what we're capable of
存在，但仅限于我们所能达到的程度
of in some societies you know America
在某些社会里，你知道美国
comes to mind you demonstrate your power
我想到的是你展现出的力量
by showing your wealth by showing what
通过展示你的财富来展示什么
you can do by being very in your face I
你可以通过非常咄咄逼人的方式来做到这一点。
can I'm great at this you know I'm we're
我可以很擅长这个吗？你知道，我们……
number one kind of thing many cultures
许多文化中排名第一的事物
don't like that many the more
不喜欢这样，越多越好。
collectivist your culture is the the
你们的文化是集体主义的
more frowned upon that is and the less
也就是说，这种做法越不被认可，就越不被接受。
likely you are to do it even if you are
即使你……，你也很有可能要这样做。
the powerful and then you get to
强大的力量，然后你就能……
cultures where the only person who ever
在某些文化中，唯一一个曾经……
puts himself down as the really powerful
他自诩为真正强大的人。
because they can afford to say no no I'm
因为他们有钱说不，不，我是
I'm nobody you don't want to B with me
我不是那种你不想和我在一起的人
and the second they say that in those
其次，他们说，在那些
cultures like oo this person runs the
像 oo 这样的文化，这个人经营着
show around here and so in a lot of
这里到处都有展示，所以很多地方都是如此
cultures the richest person is the one
文化中最富有的人是……
who dresses the most modestly the most
谁的穿着最朴素
powerful person is because that's what
强大的人之所以强大，是因为这就是……
the culture understands but it's always
这种文化能够理解，但总是
you have to follow the cultural rules
你必须遵守文化规则
and a we're number one Society that's
我们是排名第一的社团。
not going to work for you everybody's
这对每个人来说都不适用
just going to think you're nobody and so
你会觉得自己微不足道，所以
the rules of power vary dramatically by
权力规则因人而异，差异巨大。
where you are but you can always see
无论你身在何处，你总能看到
that somebody who is relaxed and looks
一个放松且看起来
comfortable is probably
舒适可能
relatively high powered person in that
相对而言，他是一个权力较大的人。
circumstance I've always wondered why
我一直很想知道为什么会出现这种情况。
billionaires who have more sort of
拥有更多类型的亿万富翁
objective
客观的
power end up not wearing designer
权力最终没有穿名牌服装
clothes and being more understated and
穿着打扮要更加低调
wearing just the same out for every day
每天都穿同样的衣服出门
and they don't wear the designer Brands
他们也不穿名牌服装。
and have Louis Von yeah the the thing is
还有路易·冯，是的，问题是
that we use those Brands to compete for
我们利用这些品牌进行竞争
status but they're already at the very
地位，但他们已经处于最……
top of deep they won their competition
他们顶住了压力，赢得了比赛。
and anybody who knows them knows that
任何认识他们的人都知道这一点。
and their act they're also especially as
他们的行为也尤其如此
you start to get rich all the fancy
你开始变得富有，拥有所有花哨的东西。
Brands and then as you get even richer
品牌，然后随着你变得越来越富有
and you've been that way longer you it
而且你已经那样待了很久了。
becomes less important to you because
因为这件事对你来说变得不那么重要了。
you've got status in other ways and
你在其他方面也拥有地位，
maybe it's a counter signal at that
也许这是一种反向信号
point so maybe if he was if he had a
所以，也许如果他有……
Louis Vuitton bag he would actually be
他实际上会是一个路易威登包
lowering himself to the status CLA he's
他自降身份，沦为CLA（高级文职人员）
just a regular millionaire he's not the
他只是个普通的百万富翁，不是那种人。
multibillionaire that he is you've
尽管他是一位亿万富翁，但你已经……
studied um the hadza tribe you you
研究过哈扎部落，你
mentioned them repeatedly only
只反复提到过他们
indirectly I've never been there yeah
间接来说，我从来没去过那里，是的。
what is the most interesting thing
最有趣的事情是什么
you've learned about them as it relates
你已经了解了它们与此相关的内容。
to happiness and purpose and living a
追求幸福、目标和生活
good life that you might pass to all of
美好的生活，你或许可以传递给所有人。
us that are listening well autonomy is
我们这些认真倾听的人，自主权是
was really rare for our ancestors they
对于我们的祖先来说，这真的非常罕见。
evolve to want both they they need
逐渐演变成想要两者兼得，他们需要
connection to survive and to be part of
与生存和融入建立联系
the collective that will you know go on
你知道，这个集体将会继续下去。
the hunt and do all the things that is
狩猎以及做所有那些事情
necessary for living every single day
日常生活必需品
but they also need autonomy to choose
但他们也需要自主选择的权利。
where they're going to their real Niche
他们要去哪里才能找到真正的自己的利基市场
is going to be what their best prospects
这将是他们最有前途的前景。
are how to stand out in the group
如何才能在群体中脱颖而出
everybody has to be H to gather but you
每个人都必须是H才能聚集在一起，但你
could still be the best arrow maker or
仍然可能是最好的箭矢制造者，或者
Storyteller or whatever make make
讲故事的人或者其他什么人
yourself valuable to the group so you
你对团队有价值，所以你
need autonomy so can decide where you
需要自主权，这样才能决定你在哪里
have best prospects and decide what you
拥有最佳前景并决定你
want to do and put your efforts into the
想做并且愿意为此付出努力
domains that matter to you that where
对您来说重要的域名
you think you'll succeed but for
你认为你会成功，但实际上……
ancestors true autonomy was rare because
祖先们真正享有自治权的情况非常罕见，因为
if you guys even though we all decide by
即使我们都决定了，你们也会这么做。
consensus and you guys say you want to
达成共识，你们说你们想要
go south and I want to go north I can't
我想往南走，但我想往北走，我不能。
just go north when you go south or I'm
当你往南走的时候，就往北走，或者我是
going to be Lon food I've got to
我要去伦敦吃东西了。
compromise or persuade you with my you
用我的你来妥协或说服你
know what what I want to do which means
我知道自己想做什么，这意味着
that opportunities for True autonomy
实现真正自主的机会
were really rare for our ancestors the
对我们的祖先来说，这真的非常罕见。
problem is now we don't need connection
问题是现在我们不需要连接了。
anymore we can survive just fine without
我们不再需要它也能很好地生存下去。
it so we have opportunities for autonomy
这样我们就拥有了自主的机会。
all the time cities are an example
城市一直以来都是这样的例子。
they're full of opportunities for
它们充满了机会
autonomy and humans are moving there in
自主性和人类正在向那里发展
droves every time that we get a choice
每次我们有机会选择时，都会成群结队地涌来。
between connection and autonomy I fear
我担心，在连接和自主之间会存在问题。
that we're choosing autonomy it's a form
我们选择自主，这是一种形式
of miswan him because for our ancestors
因为他的祖先而对他怀有深深的怨恨。
they rarely could get that choice where
他们很少有机会做出这样的选择。
they could really pick either and when
他们其实可以选择其中任何一个，而且是什么时候
they had it they wanted to jump on
他们有这个东西，他们想跳上去。
autonomy so now I think that we're
自主性，所以现在我认为我们是
constantly choosing to do our own thing
我们始终选择做我们自己的事
rather than to connect and that's
而不是为了建立联系，那就是
steadily making us unhappy and our our
不断地让我们感到不快乐，而我们的
hunt to gather friends who still exist
寻找并召集那些仍然存在的朋友
on this Earth don't do that that's the
在这个世界上，别那样做，就是这样。
one thing that you can learn from the
你可以从中学到的一件事是
hza they're constantly thinking about
他们一直在想着
each other and then thinking about well
彼此交流，然后思考……
what do I want and kind finding a
我想要什么，以及如何找到一种……
compromise that's much closer to balance
更接近平衡的妥协方案
in that regard uh men need women more
在这方面，男人更需要女人。
than women need men as it relates to
比起女性，女性更需要男性。
connection yes and no so we all need to
有联系，也有没有，所以我们都需要……
connect but I believe women need it more
联系，但我认为女性更需要它
than men largely for the reasons we were
比男性更多的是因为我们……
talking about earlier where women need
早些时候谈到女性需要
to get more help parenting so they need
为了获得更多育儿方面的帮助，他们需要
to form these tight bonds so people will
为了形成这些紧密的联系，人们会
help them but of course men need
帮助他们，但男人当然也需要帮助。
connection too and women provide men
也存在联系，女性为男性提供……
with a lot of the closest connection
与许多最亲密的关系
that they have CU I read that marriage
他们有CU，我读到过那段婚姻
is more beneficial for men's longevity
更有利于男性延长寿命
than it is for women's it is it's not a
比起女性，这不是一个
huge difference so if you look at people
差别很大，所以如果你观察人们
in their mid-60s where now longevities
他们六十多岁，现在正值长寿时期
in the offing right men will live an
在不久的将来，合适的人将会过上幸福的生活。
extra two years if they're married and
如果他们已婚，则额外延长两年。
women will only live an extra year and a
女性只能多活一年多。
half if they're married so women do more
如果她们已婚，那么女性的工作量会增加一半。
for men than men do for women but both
对男性而言，比男性对女性而言，但两者
are getting something out of it and
从中获得了一些东西，
that's not a huge difference and it's
这差别并不大，而且
that they're giving us more emotional
他们给了我们更多情感上的慰藉
support typically than we're well also I
通常情况下，我们的支持也很好。
mean think about how slovenly and
想想看，这有多邋遢和
disgusting we are they're probably
我们真恶心，他们可能也一样。
helping us with our hygiene they're
他们帮助我们保持卫生。
probably helping in a variety of ways
可能在很多方面有所帮助
but yes I think emotional support really
是的，我认为情感支持真的非常重要。
matters and I think that you need to
很重要，我认为你需要……
have something to live for and kids
有活下去的理由，还有孩子
provide us with that grandkids provide
给我们提供孙辈们提供的东西
us with that connection provides us with
这种联系为我们提供了
that nobody wants to die alone that's a
没有人想孤独地死去，这是……
miserable thought these these hads of
这些痛苦的想法
tribes that we keep talking about do
我们一直在谈论的那些部落
they do they stay together in
他们会在一起。
marriages it turns out so they're
事实证明，婚姻就是这样。
they're their best well what the person
他们发挥出了最佳水平，嗯，这个人怎么样？
I regard as a premier ethnographer is
我认为一位杰出的民族学家是
Frank Marlo he would live with the hodza
弗兰克·马洛，他会和霍扎人一起生活。
and write about them and he estimated
并把它们写下来，他估计
from his life experience with them that
根据他与他们的生活经历，
about 20% of them stay married for life
他们当中约有20%的人终生保持婚姻关系。
so one and five which is not high very
所以一和五，这并不高，非常
low now if you think about it why is
现在价格这么低，仔细想想为什么呢？
that such a high divorce rate well
如此高的离婚率……
Hunter gathers don't institutionalize
狩猎采集者不会制度化
marriage the way that agriculturalists
以农业主义者的方式结婚
do when agriculturals get married that's
当农民结婚时，那就是
a financial Arrangement it didn't matter
财务安排无关紧要
in the same way to our hunted gather ANC
就像我们这些被猎杀采集的非国大一样。
SS when that's no longer nice they moved
当这种做法不再合适时，他们就搬走了。
out and chose somebody
出去，然后选择了某人
else and so it's low it's it's they're
否则，所以它很低，它是，它们是
serial monogamists they don't you know
连续单配偶者，他们不知道
hza tend not to have more than one wife
hza通常不会娶多个妻子
at a time it happens but it's rare does
这种情况偶尔会发生，但很少见。
our evolutionary par suggests that
我们的进化论观点表明
humans are serial monogamist I believe
我认为人类是连续单配偶制者。
humans evolved to be serial monogamists
人类进化成了连续一夫一妻制者。
who cheat a little bit now why do I
谁现在稍微作弊一下？我为什么要这么做？
think we also cheat a little bit because
我觉得我们也会稍微作弊一下，因为
if we're purely monogamous men would not
如果我们实行纯粹的一夫一妻制，男人就不会
need testicles as large as they are a
需要睾丸和它们一样大
gorilla is is not monogamous it has a
大猩猩不是一夫一妻制，它有……
Herm of several females but it doesn't
雌雄同体，由几只雌性组成，但它并不
no other male gorilla can approach those
其他雄性大猩猩都无法接近它们
females because he will physically
因为他会身体上对女性产生影响
attack them and so he knows that he's
攻击他们，所以他知道自己是在攻击他们。
the only one having sex with them and he
唯一一个和她们发生性关系的人，他
has very small testicles and in fact
他的睾丸非常小，事实上
they're inside his body they're not at
它们在他体内，它们不在
risk of damage a chimpanzee who um the
对一只黑猩猩造成损害的风险，嗯……
their mating system is lots of male
它们的交配系统是雄性很多。
chimps have sex with lots of females so
黑猩猩会和很多雌性交配，所以
who knows who his father has these
谁知道他父亲拥有这些东西。
enormous testicles because part of his
巨大的睾丸，因为他的一部分
job is to wash out I know it doesn't
工作是清洗，我知道它不会。
sound nice wash out the guy who was
听起来不错，把那个人冲走
there before him so maybe his sperm will
在他之前，所以也许他的精子会
be the one that inseminates her wash out
成为让她流产的人
what do you mean by wash out like
你说的“像冲刷一样”是什么意思？
literally pumped so much sperm into her
真的往她体内注入了好多精液
that the previous guy who just had sex
就是之前那个刚做完爱的家伙
with her his sperm is literally washed
和她在一起时，他的精子就真的被洗掉了。
out as if you're in there with a hose I
就好像你拿着软管在里面一样。
know it doesn't it's not it's not anyway
我知道它不是，它不是，反正它不是。
so if we were ancestrally purely
所以如果我们祖先纯粹是
monogamous we'd have little gorilla
一夫一妻制的话，我们会生个小猩猩
testicles and we don't we ours are way
睾丸，我们没有，我们的是方式
bigger than theirs which suggests that
比他们的更大，这表明
we did a little bit of washing out of
我们稍微清洗了一下。
our own which suggests we were
我们自己的，这表明我们是
monogamous but we're also sneaking
我们是一夫一妻制，但我们也在偷偷摸摸地……
around at the same
差不多在同一时间
time so cheating might might be a
所以作弊可能是暂时的
natural part of well natural doesn't
自然的一部分，自然的，并不
mean good I'm not saying it's a good
我的意思是好的，我不是说它就是好的
thing right but I'm saying it's what our
没错，但我的意思是，这是我们
ancestors did so my guess is when they
祖先们确实这样做过，所以我猜想当他们
could get away with it you know there
你知道，那样做或许能逃脱惩罚。
they are in the cave there's this couple
他们就在山洞里，那里有一对夫妇。
who aren't a couple but nobody else is
他们不是情侣，但其他人都不是。
around both of them have reasons to do
他们俩都有理由这样做。
it males want to cheat because it gives
男性想要出轨是因为它能给他们带来好处。
them a greater chance of having
他们更有可能拥有
Offspring they otherwise wouldn't have
他们原本不会有的后代
females can't have an infinite number of
女性不可能拥有无限数量的……
kids like males can because they could
孩子们喜欢男孩，因为他们可以。
have sex with 20 guys they're still only
和20个男人发生性关系，他们仍然只是
going to have one kid the orangutang has
那只猩猩要生一个孩子了
like pretty similar DNA to us is it the
就像我们的DNA非常相似一样，是吗？
orangutang which which monkey is it that
猩猩，是哪一种猴子？
well chimps are the closest to us the
黑猩猩是与我们关系最近的动物。
chimp and then gorillas and then
先是黑猩猩，然后是大猩猩，然后
orangutans but they're all great apes so
猩猩，但它们都是大型猿类，所以
they're all pretty close to us can
它们都离我们很近。
chimps talk no so if they if I'm a chimp
黑猩猩不会说话，所以如果我是一只黑猩猩的话。
and I I I leave the tree for a while and
我暂时离开那棵树
then my Boy comes over and he has sex
然后我儿子过来，我们就发生了性关系。
with my
我的
wife I can't then find out that he did
妻子，我不能就此发现他确实这么做了。
that no there's no one telling you now
不，现在没人告诉你。
they do sign language lots of things
他们用手语做很多事情
that they're interest in doing immediate
他们有兴趣立即采取行动。
communication but it's if you think
沟通，但前提是你认为
about sign language it's really good for
关于手语，它真的很好。
saying you know there's something behind
你说你知道背后肯定有事。
you it's really good for saying I'm
你说这真的很好，因为我是
going to punch you in the face if you
如果你这么做，我就揍你脸。
don't give me your food whatever but
别把你的食物给我，随便什么都行。
it's not good for saying you know
这么说不好，你知道
yesterday I had sex with your wife how
昨天我和你老婆发生了性关系
do they communicate that they're they're
他们是否表达了他们是他们是
terrible at communicating that kind of
沟通这类问题的能力太差了。
things that are separated by space or by
被空间或物体分隔开的事物
time they just simply can't communicate
他们之间根本无法沟通
and so but they can't think about it
所以，但他们无法去想这件事。
either and so our homus is the first
两者皆可，因此我们的人类是第一个。
animal on this planet who think about
地球上会思考的动物
separate SE things separate by space and
用空格分隔的SE事物
time and so my guess is our complex
时间，所以我猜我们的复杂
communication began with them it made me
与他们沟通让我开始与他们交流。
think of my dog my dog does something he
想想我的狗，我的狗做了某件事……
does a poo in the in the house I come
它在屋里拉屎了吗？我来了
home an hour later I tell him all he
一个小时后回到家，我把一切都告诉了他。
doesn't know why you're upset yeah that
不知道你为什么生气，是啊。
Poo's that happened an hour ago he
一小时前发生的那件事
doesn't know what the problem is but he
他不知道问题出在哪里，但他
can't think about the past and the
无法回想过去和
future in terms and Link it to it's the
就未来而言，并将其与它联系起来。
we know from psychology that if you want
我们从心理学中得知，如果你想
to punish an animal for pooing which is
惩罚动物排便，即
effective if you do you don't you
如果你这样做有效，你就不会。
shouldn't rub the nose in things that
不应该把鼻子伸进那些东西里
aren't nice but punishment is very
惩罚并不友好，但非常有效。
effective if you punish them for pooing
如果惩罚他们随地大小便，效果会很好。
you're a bad girl you do it right away
你是个坏女孩，你马上就做了。
they'll stop pooing in your house you
它们就不会再在你家拉屎了。
punish them an hour later they go I
惩罚他们一小时后，他们去了
don't know what you're talking about
我不知道你在说什么
when I come home and say my dog's pooed
当我回家说我的狗拉屎了
in the house or something or he's done
在家里或者其他地方，或者他已经做完了
something naughty he's hiding yeah
他藏着什么不可告人的秘密呢。
because he now knows that when you find
因为他现在知道，当你发现
a poo in the house he gets in trouble
他在家里拉屎，结果惹上麻烦了。
when you find a torn up Furniture he
当你发现一件破损的家具时
gets in trouble he knows that that's an
遇到麻烦时，他知道那是……
association dogs are really really good
协会的狗狗们真的非常棒
about learning associations and so all
关于学习联想等等
that he doesn't you know when he tears
他不知道他什么时候会哭
it up first of all he poor self-control
首先，他自控力很差，这让他很沮丧。
because it's a dog but second he can't
因为这是一条狗，其次他不能
think about uh-oh in the future Steven's
想想未来史蒂文的糟糕情况
going to come home and he's going to be
他要回家了，他将会……
pissed but now when you do come home and
很生气，但现在当你回家的时候
he's like looking over the torn couch
他就像在看着那张破旧的沙发。
he's like uhoh I'm in trouble and so he
他就像“糟了，我遇到麻烦了”，然后他就
knows for while what's
一段时间以来都知道是什么
coming okay so he doesn't actually know
他没事，所以他其实并不知道
that it was that I didn't want him to
那是因为我不想让他……
tear up the couch or whatever but he
撕碎沙发什么的，但他
does know that when the couch is torn up
知道当沙发被撕破时
and I come home that I'm going to be
我回到家，心想我接下来要做什么。
like [__] all the yeah and you're
就像他妈的所有“是啊”一样，而你
going to yell at him and he also knows
我要冲他大吼，而且他也知道。
that if he does in front of you you'll
如果他在你面前这样做，你就会
yell at him and if he poops in front of
冲他大喊大叫，如果他当着你的面拉屎……
you you'll yell at him so he knows all
你会对他大吼大叫，让他知道一切
those things um but he can't think about
那些事，嗯……但他不能去想。
the future so take a take an animal way
未来，所以要采取一种动物的方式
smarter than a dog a monkey or even a
比狗、猴子甚至……都聪明
chimp let's get way smarter chimps can't
黑猩猩，让我们变得更聪明，黑猩猩做不到。
plan for tomorrow the way a human can so
像人一样为明天做计划
I if if you feed a chimp or a monkey or
如果你喂一只黑猩猩或猴子，或者
any of these animals as much food as
这些动物都能获得充足的食物
they want but only one meal a day they
他们一天只想吃一顿饭。
don't like that because they like to eat
他们不喜欢那样，因为他们喜欢吃
several meals a day just like we do but
像我们一样，一天吃好几顿饭，但是
they'll never go I'm going to stash some
他们永远不会走，我要藏一些。
of my food because I'm going to get
我的食物，因为我要去拿
hungry at 5:00 p.m. today because I'm
下午5点饿了今天因为我是
only fed at 2
只在2点喂食
it never occurs to them day after day
他们日复一日地从未想到这一点。
after day to stash it when they're full
白天用完后，把它们藏起来。
they'll literally throw it at each other
他们会真的互相扔东西。
because they don't they can't think they
因为他们不这样认为，所以他们无法思考。
they can't think about a world that has
他们无法想象一个拥有……的世界
unfelt needs all they can think about is
他们满脑子想的都是自己未被满足的需求。
the world where their needs are the same
在这个世界里，他们的需求是相同的。
as they are right now and because we can
就像他们现在这样，而且因为我们可以
project our mind into the future we know
将我们的思绪投射到我们已知的未来。
there's going to be a world with all
将会有一个拥有所有这一切的世界
sorts of unfelt needs I'll be hungry
一些未被察觉的需求，我会感到饥饿
again I'll be cold I'll be whatever but
我又会感到寒冷，我会怎样怎样，但是
but some animals store food don't they
但有些动物会储存食物，不是吗？
they do but they do it they do it um
他们确实会这么做，他们确实会这么做，嗯
automatically they don't go oh it's
他们不会自动说“哦，是……”
going to be like for example squirrels
就像松鼠那样
who bury nuts well do that if they'd
那些善于埋坚果的人，如果他们愿意的话，就会这样做。
never been through a winter so they
他们从未经历过冬天，所以他们
don't go uh oh I was cold last winter I
别走，哦哦，我去年冬天很冷。
better store some nuts cuz there weren't
最好储存一些坚果，因为之前没有。
many around they just have evolved to
许多周围的人都已经进化成这样了
store nuts when the weather starts to
天气开始转凉时，要储存坚果。
get cold or whatever their signal is cu
冷了或者不管他们的信号是什么
cuz my my dog Pablo he's never been
因为我的狗帕布罗从来没有……
around I mean he has been around other
我的意思是，他一直在和其他人接触。
dogs of course but I don't I only have
当然有狗，但我没有，我只有
one dog so he's only ever lived uh with
他只有一条狗，所以他一直都和它住在一起。
me and I wondered the first time I got a
我和我很好奇我第一次得到……
bone like from the the shop and I gave
从店里买的骨头形状的东西，我给了
it to him he like played with it a
他很喜欢玩这个。
little bit but then he picked it up and
稍微有点，但他后来把它捡了起来。
buried it in the couch yeah and I'm like
把它埋在沙发里了，对，然后我就想
what the hell are you doing like and
你到底在干什么？
then I give him another bone and he
然后我又给了他一根骨头，他
picks it up and buries it in the couch
他捡起它，把它埋在沙发底下。
and then I end up like lifting up the
然后我就就像举起了……
couch and there's all these bones buried
沙发，还有埋在里面的骨头
in there I'm like how that's an evolved
我在想，这算是一种进化吗？
behavior that he doesn't understand the
他无法理解的行为
purpose of but he knows he wants to do
目的是为了……但他知道他想这样做。
and so let me give you an example from
那么，让我举个例子吧。
from another animal system where we've
我们从另一个动物系统中了解到……
studied it really closely so Mir cats do
仔细研究过，所以米尔猫确实如此。
you know Mir cats those cute little
你知道米尔猫吗？那些可爱的小家伙。
things like oh yeah I think from the
诸如“哦，是的，我想是从……”之类的
movies um Mir cats eat uh scorpions and
电影里，米尔猫吃蝎子，还有
so they need to teach their ba they're
所以他们需要教他们的孩子，他们是
they're very good Hunters they need to
他们都是非常优秀的猎人，他们需要……
teach their babies to kill something
教他们的孩子杀生
that could kill them and so if when they
那可能会要了他们的命，所以如果当他们
have tiny babies they kill the Scorpion
它们生下的幼崽很小，它们会杀死蝎子。
and give it to it dead and then the baby
然后把它给死的，再给婴儿
eats the Scorpion once it's weaned from
断奶后吃掉蝎子
milk because of course they're mammals
因为它们是哺乳动物，所以当然要产奶。
when the babies get a little bit bigger
当宝宝们再大一些的时候
they break the Stinger off and throw the
他们把毒刺弄断并扔掉
Scorpion to it alive so the baby can
蝎子把它活活咬住，这样婴儿就可以……
practice killing the Scorpion and then
练习杀死蝎子，然后
when the baby's bigger still it's almost
当宝宝再大一些的时候，几乎
ready to go out on its own they throw it
准备独自外出时，他们把它扔了出去。
Al live scorpion like you kill it and
就像你杀死一只活蝎子一样
eat it because it's got to learn how to
吃掉它，因为它必须学会如何……
do that like it seems rough but it's got
这样做虽然看起来很粗糙，但它确实有效。
to learn that if you play the sounds of
要学会如果你播放声音
a little baby to us to the mother or the
对我们来说，一个小婴儿对母亲来说，或者
whoever's bringing the food cuz it's not
不管是谁带食物来，因为不是
always mothers it'll kill the Scorpion
总是母亲会杀死蝎子
and throw it in there even if the who
即使是谁，也要把它放进去。
it's throwing into are juveniles who
它把那些未成年人扔了进去
could kill it themselves and worse yet
它们可能会自己杀死自己，更糟糕的是
if you have babies and you play Juvenile
如果你有孩子，而且你玩少年组
sounds it'll throw the live scorpion to
听起来它会把活蝎子扔出去
the baby who's going to kill the baby
那个会杀死婴儿的婴儿
because all it knows is when I hear that
因为它只知道当我听到那句话的时候
sound I do x to the Scorpion your dog is
听起来我做x到蝎子你的狗是
doing the same thing when given bone
给骨头时也做同样的事
chew on it for a little while then bury
嚼一会儿，然后埋掉
it for later because I don't know if
留着以后再说，因为我不知道是否
I'll have them later now it doesn't know
我稍后会拿到它们，它现在还不知道。
do that I don't know if I'll have it
那样做，我不知道我是否能做到。
later but it's evolved to solve that
后来才发展到可以解决这个问题。
problem
问题
as you guys know whoop is one of my show
你们都知道，Whoop 是我的节目之一。
sponsors it's also a company that I have
赞助商，这也是我拥有的一家公司。
invested in and it's one that you guys
你们投资了，而且你们也投资了。
ask me about a lot the biggest question
问我很多问题，最大的问题
I get asked is why I use whoop over
经常有人问我为什么我用 Whoop 而不是其他平台。
other wearable technology options and
其他可穿戴技术选项和
there is a bunch of reasons but I think
原因有很多，但我认为
it really comes down to the most
归根结底，最重要的是
Overlook yet crucial feature it's
忽略了它的关键特性
noninvasive nature when everything in
非侵入性，一切都在
life seems to be competing for my
生活似乎在争夺我的……
attention I turn to whoop because it
我转而关注欢呼声，因为它
doesn't have a screen and will armed the
没有屏幕，并且会启动
CEO who came on this podcast told me the
来参加这个播客节目的CEO告诉我……
reason that there's no screen
原因是没有屏幕
because screens equal distraction so
因为屏幕会分散注意力，所以
when I'm in meetings or I'm at the gym
当我开会或在健身房时
my whoop doesn't demand my attention
我的呼喊声并不需要我关注。
it's there in the background constantly
它一直都在背景中。
pulling data and insights from my body
从我的身体中提取数据和见解
that are ready for when I need them if
如果我随时需要它们，它们就准备好了。
you've been thinking about joining whoop
你一直在考虑加入 Whoop
you can head to join. whoop.com
您可以前往加入。 whoop.com
CEO and try whoop for 30 days risk-free
CEO 和 Whoop 用户可免费试用 30 天。
and zero commitment that's join.
无需任何承诺即可加入。
woop.com
woop.com
CEO let me know how you get on I've
CEO，请告诉我你的进展如何。
invested more than a million pound into
投资超过一百万英镑
this company Perfect Ted and they're
这家公司叫 Perfect Ted，他们是
also a sponsor of this podcast I
我也是本播客的赞助商之一。
switched over to using matcher as my
改用匹配器作为我的
dominant energy source and that's where
主要能源来源，那就是
perfect Ted comes in they have the
完美的泰德进来了，他们有
matcha powders they have the matcha
他们有抹茶粉
drinks they have the pods and all of
他们有各种饮料，包括胶囊饮料等等。
this keeps me focused throughout a very
这让我能够全程保持专注。
very long recording day no matter what's
无论如何，录音日都非常漫长。
going on and their team is obsessed with
正在进行中，他们的团队对此非常着迷
quality which is why they Source their
质量是他们采购原材料的原因，所以他们注重品质。
ceremonial grade matcha from Japan so
来自日本的仪式级抹茶
when people say to me that they don't
当人们对我说他们不
like the taste of matcha I'm guessing
我猜是喜欢抹茶的味道吧。
that they haven't tried perfect head
他们还没试过完美头部
unlike lowquality matcha that has a
与低品质抹茶不同，低品质抹茶含有……
bitter grassy taste perfect headed is
苦涩的草味，完美的头部是
smooth and naturally sweet and without
口感顺滑，天然香甜，且不含
knowing it you're probably a perfect Ted
知道这一点，你可能就是个完美的泰迪熊。
customer already if you're getting your
如果您已经是客户，那么您就拥有了您的
match at places like blank Street or Joe
在像布兰克街或乔这样的地方进行比赛
in the juice but now you can make it
果汁里，但现在你可以自己做了
yourself at home so give it a try and
你自己在家就能做，所以不妨试一试。
we'll see if you still don't like matcha
我们看看你是否还是不喜欢抹茶。
so here's what I'm going to do I'm going
所以，我打算这么做：我要走了
to give you 40% off our matcher if you
如果您符合以下条件，我们将为您提供我们匹配器40%的折扣：
try it today head to perfect ted.com and
今天就去试一试吧，访问 perfect ted.com
use code
使用代码
steven4 or if you're in a supermarket
steven4 或者如果你在超市
you can get it at tesos or Holland and
你可以在 Tesos 或 Holland 买到它。
Barett or in the Netherlands at Albert
巴雷特，或者在荷兰是阿尔伯特
Heine and those you in the US you can
海涅和你们这些在美国的人可以
get it on
开始吧
Amazon it's a really interesting um such
亚马逊真是一个非常有趣的……
an interesting subject matter because
这是一个有趣的话题，因为
you know I I spend so much time talking
你知道我花了很多时间说话
to people about our Evolution and what
向人们讲述我们的进化以及什么
it tells us about our future and who we
它告诉我们未来会怎样，以及我们是谁。
are and you're I mean you're the guy
是，你是，我的意思是，你就是那个人
you're the guy that knows more about our
你是最了解我们的人。
evolutionary past than I think anybody
比我认为任何人的进化史都更远
I've ever met so I'm so curious to know
我从未见过这样的人，所以我很好奇。
if there's just anything else that
如果还有其他什么事的话……
someone like me should be aware of
像我这样的人应该意识到这一点
from all the work you've done in
从你过去所做的所有工作来看
studying evolution any study any story
研究进化论，任何研究，任何故事
that was particularly pivotal for you
那对你来说尤其关键。
and your thinking that shaped you that
以及塑造你的那种思维方式。
we haven't yet talked about we we've
我们还没谈到我们……
talked a fair bit about how money
他们谈了不少关于金钱的话题。
doesn't make you as happy as you think
它并没有你想象中那么让你快乐。
it would but it does help it it it does
确实如此，但如果真是这样，那确实会有帮助。
help make you happy and we've talked
想办法让你开心，我们已经谈过了。
about how important you know money is a
了解金钱的重要性
a proxy for State it's how important
作为国家代理人，它的重要性如何？
that was in our ancestral Society but
那是在我们祖先的社团里，但是
you have to remember that our ancestral
你必须记住，我们的祖先
societies were very small and so it was
社会规模很小，所以……
feasible that I could be the best at
我有可能成为最优秀的
something in my group I could be the
我所在团队中的某件事，我可能是其中之一。
richest I could be the best arrow maker
如果我再富有，我就能成为最好的箭矢制造者。
the best Storyteller you name it there's
你能想到的最棒的讲故事的人都在那里。
something I've got a shot at nobody can
这是我唯一有机会做到的事，别人都做不到。
be the best at anything anymore you
你不再需要在任何方面做到最好了
can't even be the richest I mean
甚至连最富有的人都算不上，我的意思是
tomorrow Elon Musk made some amount this
明天埃隆·马斯克赚了不少钱
year that's like so astronomical it's
那一年简直太不可思议了。
hard to even imagine and so
简直难以想象，所以
the there's always going to be people
总会有人
who have more than you do and so the
那些比你拥有更多东西的人，所以
problem with money is that it's
金钱的问题在于……
partially a status game it's partially
它既是地位游戏，又是
about buying a nicer car and a nicer
关于购买一辆更好的车和更好的
house and those things actually tend not
房子和那些东西实际上往往不会
to make us happy but but
为了让我们开心，但是
interestingly spending our money on
有趣的是，我们把钱花在了……
doing things tends to make us much
做事情往往会让我们变得更好。
happier which is surprising because it
更快乐了，这很令人惊讶，因为
feels like spending money on activities
感觉像是在活动上花钱
is kind of wasteful I always felt like
我一直觉得这有点浪费。
when I was young and broke that if I had
当我年轻又穷困的时候，我曾想过，如果我有
money it was hedonistic and wasteful to
金钱是一种享乐主义和浪费的行为。
spend it skiing whereas it was sensible
把钱花在滑雪上是明智之举。
to spend it on a new couch because I
打算把钱花在新沙发上，因为我
need a couch and then I'll have that
我需要一张沙发，然后我就能拥有它了。
couch for a very long time whereas the
沙发长时间处于……
ski day is over in a day but it turns
滑雪日虽然只有一天，但却会变成……
out that if you have disposable income
这表明，如果你有可支配收入的话。
it makes you a lot happy when you spend
当你花钱的时候，你会感到非常快乐。
it on things to do rather than things to
它关注要做的事情，而不是要做的事情。
have and we don't know exactly why that
确实有，但我们并不确切知道原因。
is yet but I suspect that the reason is
尚未确定，但我怀疑原因是
is the things to have are a status game
拥有这些东西是一种身份象征。
and that status game is impossible to
而这种地位博弈是不可能的
win right because there's just too many
赢得胜利，因为机会太多了。
humans on the planet and I'm going to
地球上的人类，而我即将……
open up my Instagram tomorrow and find
明天打开我的Instagram，你会发现
that somebody else has a better car or
别人有辆更好的车，或者
whatever it is that I just bought and
无论我刚刚买的是什么，
now I mine looks kind of dumpy whereas
现在我的看起来有点臃肿，而
that ski holiday actually becomes part
那次滑雪假期实际上成为了一部分
of yourself it becomes this memory
你自己变成了这段记忆
that's self that that that you think
那是你自己的想法。
back on and that you you're happy when
回来后，你就会感到快乐
you think about it and especially if you
你仔细想想，尤其是如果你
do it with friends and so the advice I
和朋友一起做，所以我的建议是……
would give is you know if you're trying
你知道，如果你在尝试的话，就会给你答案。
to especially if you're successful and
尤其是如果你成功了的话
you're trying to find a way to to not
你试图找到一种方法来避免
feel like all that success was a lot of
感觉所有这些成功都源于很多
effort and not really worth it is to use
费力而且不值得使用
your money in ways to enhance your
用你的钱来提升你的价值
experiences in life rather than to
人生经历比……
enhance your things so what are the if I
提升你的物品，那么如果我
had to force you I don't like doing this
我不得不强迫你，我不喜欢这样做。
but if I had to force you to give
但如果我不得不强迫你放弃
me a summary of the top five things that
请给我总结一下最重要的五件事。
are most correlated to my happiness in
与我的幸福感最相关的因素是
your opinion
你的意见
are most likely to increase my
最有可能增加我的
probability of living a happy filled
过上幸福充实的生活的概率
life you have to give me five okay what
生活啊，你得给我五分钟，好吗？
are those five things Families First
这五件事是“家庭优先”吗？
okay the F we evolved in families um not
好吧，我们是在家族中进化的，嗯，不是。
just small families but extended
只是小家庭，但关系很密切
families and it you may not get along
如果家庭成员关系不好，你们可能相处不来。
with your family and then you want to
和家人在一起，然后你想
find a proxy family or you want to
找个代理家庭，或者你想……
create one of your own so I'm not
你自己创建一个，这样我就不会……
telling you you need to get along with
告诉你你需要和睦相处
that jerk of an uncle of yours or your
你那个混蛋叔叔，或者你的
hopeless parents or whatever but I'm
不管是无能的父母还是别的什么，反正我是
saying spend time with your family and
说要多花时间陪伴家人，
if it's not the family you want want
如果不是你想要的家庭
trade him in for a new one but we
把他换成新的，但是我们
evolved to have the close confines
进化是为了适应狭小的空间
regular contact constant contact with
定期联系，保持持续联系
family and so if you can't do it in
家庭，所以如果你不能在……中做到这一点
person because they're far away or you
因为对方距离很远，或者你
know the financial means whatever you
了解财务手段，无论你
just do it every day on the phone anyway
反正每天都用手机做就行了。
find a reason to chat regularly with
找个理由定期聊天
family ideally eat with family eating
家人最好一起用餐。
was a key moment for ancestors they got
对他们的祖先来说，这是一个关键时刻。
together around the fire they if it was
他们围坐在篝火旁，如果那是
a successful hunt they're cooking up
他们正在策划一场成功的狩猎。
their meal together and they're eating
他们一起吃饭，正在吃
it together there's bad habit of a lot
它们加在一起就形成了很多坏习惯。
of families to just watch TV together
一家人一起看电视
and there's nothing wrong with TV but
电视本身并没有错，但是
you should also talk together because we
你们也应该互相交流，因为我们
evolve to be storytellers we evolve to
我们进化成讲故事的人
share stories with each other they're
他们互相分享故事
super important for us so trust me when
这对我们来说非常重要，所以请相信我
I say those momentary desires to do your
我说的是那些一时兴起想做的事
own thing will pale in in in comparison
与自己的东西相比，它就黯然失色了。
to the long-term benefits of continually
从长远来看，持续性的好处是
getting together these rituals of of
将这些仪式聚集在一起
eating together and having conversation
一起吃饭聊天
together is hugely important okay number
在一起非常重要，好的数字
two number two is it's also going to be
第二点是，它也将如此。
connection and and it
连接和它
sounds silly but it's like when when
听起来很傻，但就像……
you're trying to plan your day and you
你正试图计划你的一天，而你
you've got this list of things you want
你列了一张你想要的东西的清单。
to do and you got a list of things your
待办事项清单上列着你需要做的事情。
friends are doing you can't always do
朋友们正在做你无法总是做到的事。
what your friends are doing but if if
你的朋友在做什么，但是如果
you can get yourself to sacrifice what
你可以让自己牺牲什么
you really preferred and do what they're
你真的很喜欢并且会去做他们想做的事。
doing and and they're going to
正在做，而且他们将要
eventually do the same for you of course
当然，最终也会为你做同样的事。
too give up some of that autonomy in
也要放弃部分自主权
order to reestablish some of that
为了重新建立其中一些
connection and and the reason I say this
联系以及我这么说的原因
is when we look at married couples even
当我们审视已婚夫妇时，即使
they're spending less time together when
他们在一起的时间越来越少了
we look at friends they're spending less
我们观察朋友们的消费情况，发现他们花的钱更少。
time together I think we need to go back
我觉得我们需要回去，好好享受这段时光。
to this
对此
world when I think when I think about
当我想到世界的时候，当我想到……
doing that I'm just going to be
那样做，我就会……
completely honest no you should be
完全诚实？不，你应该诚实。
because if it doesn't work it doesn't
因为如果不行，那就没用。
work no no when I think yeah so I'm just
工作不行不行，我想，是啊，所以我就……
trying to put myself in the in the head
试着把自己代入到头脑中
of the person that's hearing that and a
听到这句话的人，以及一个
lot of entrepreneurs and audience that
很多企业家和受众
are like very buil busy building their
他们就像非常忙碌的建设者一样，正在建造他们的
startup they've got jobs that are
初创公司里有很多工作机会
demanding of them that they're striving
要求他们努力奋斗
and they're striving away from a life
他们正努力摆脱那种生活
that they didn't like towards a life
他们不喜欢那种生活方式。
that they hope they will so that that's
他们希望如此，所以就是这样。
requiring them to give so much time and
要求他们投入大量时间和精力
energy to like separate themselves from
能量就像把自己与……分离
the crowd so when they hear that they
人群听到这个消息时，
need to spend more time with their
需要花更多时间陪伴他们
partner many of them will be
他们的很多合作伙伴都将是
thinking but then my business will fail
我这样想着，但我的生意就会失败。
and I agree with them I when I'm giving
我同意他们的观点，当我给予的时候。
this generic advice I'm not tailoring it
我没有给出任何针对性的通用建议。
to that person and I completely agree
同意那个人的观点，我完全同意
with that person's life choice When
和那个人的生活选择有关
We're Young we're autonomy machines and
我们年轻，我们是自主机器，
that takes precedence especially if you
这一点尤其重要，如果你
have a big dream that you think you
你有一个远大的梦想，你认为
could get to you're this entrepreneur
可能会让你成为这样的企业家
and especially trying to get away from
尤其是试图摆脱
something that wasn't much like
某种不太像的东西
materially you just didn't have enough
物质上你根本不够用。
to really get by whatever the case might
无论如何，都要真正度过难关
be LeBron James thring basket after
勒布朗·詹姆斯投篮后
basket after basket trying to become the
一篮又一篮地试图成为
person he wants to be look how well it
他想成为的那种人，看看他做得多么出色
works for what's the cost the cost is is
适用于什么情况？成本是多少？成本是……
paid at the time you're going to be
在你即将……的时候支付。
lonely when you do that but if you're if
这样做的时候你会感到孤独，但如果你是……
you're loving what you're doing and if
你热爱你正在做的事情，而且如果
you think it as a real chance will I say
你认为这是一个真正的机会吗？我会这么说。
pay that loneliness price when you're
当你……时，就要付出孤独的代价。
young don't pay it every single day
年轻人不需要每天都付钱。
please go out with your friends on
请和你的朋友们出去玩吧
Friday night and talk with your fellow
周五晚上和你的同伴们聊聊
entrepreneurs and do things that still
企业家们会做那些仍然……的事情
allow you to be connected so you're not
让你保持连接，这样你就不会
suicidal by the time you get there but I
等你到了那里，你可能已经想自杀了，但我
totally get that autonomy push it's what
完全理解这种追求自主性的做法，就是这样。
makes us a success I I I do think I'm
这使我们成功，我确实认为我是
bullshitting myself a little bit because
我有点自欺欺人了，因为
I go could I spend another hour with my
我可以再陪我一个小时吗？
partner a day or another two three hours
一天或两三个小时的伴侣
a week in my business would be fine of
在我这里待一周就足够了。
course I could but there's like you said
当然可以，但就像你说的。
there's an inherent striving which can
其中蕴含着一种可以……的奋斗精神
be out of whack and and the problem is
失衡了，问题是……
that if if what you really want to do
如果你真的想做这件事的话
right now is work yeah I I say when
现在是工作，是的，我说的是什么时候
you're young do it
你还年轻，去做吧
because you can you can let your
因为你可以让你的
connections Fray try not to let them
弗雷试图不让他们与外界联系。
disappear and then you can rebuild them
消失，然后你可以重建它们
when you now have got there but the key
当你到达那里时，关键在于
is you got to get there you have to set
你必须到达那里，你必须设定目标
yourself in an answer in advance and
提前在答案中写下你自己
here's the reason I say that I have
这就是我这么说的原因。
found myself waiting for a bus longer
我发现自己等公交车的时间更长了。
than it would have taken me to walk and
比我步行所需的时间要长得多
so once I do that a few times I realize
所以，当我这样做几次之后，我就意识到
oh the bus schedule's erratic I can do
哦，公交时刻表很不规律，我可以接受。
the walking I'm going to wait X minutes
步行 我要等 X 分钟
and then I'm going to walk our problem
然后我将逐步解决我们的问题。
is that we keep setting new bar for
我们一直在不断设定新的标准。
oursel if we don't make that that plan
如果我们不制定那个计划，我们自己就完了。
in advance oh I'll just give it another
哦，我先再试一次。
minute oh I'll just give it another
稍等片刻，我再试一次。
minute or I'll just push this business
一分钟，否则我就直接推进这笔生意。
for another year I'll just push it for
再坚持一年吧。
another year and you can find yourself
再过一年，你就会发现自己
doing it forever you may not succeed you
你一直这样做，可能永远不会成功。
may have a miserable life where all you
可能会过着悲惨的生活，你所有的一切都……
did was work and you kept pushing it for
你所做的就是努力，而且你一直在推动它。
another year and it never got there and
又过了一年，它还是没能到达那里。
so my recipe is when you start something
所以我的秘诀就是当你开始做某件事的时候
you give yourself an end date you say
你说，你给自己设定一个截止日期。
what would it mean for me to be a
对我来说，成为一名……意味着什么？
success and so you can have an end date
成功之后，你就可以设定一个结束日期了。
that's both good and bad how much money
这既是好事也是坏事，到底有多少钱。
do I have to make and now I won how much
我需要做什么？我现在赢了多少钱？
time do I get do I give without making
我有多少时间？我付出又有什么意义？
any money and therefore I lost and you
任何钱，因此我都输了，你
should set those two things in advance
应该提前安排好这两件事。
because once you're in it I promise you
因为一旦你投入其中，我向你保证
you're going to move the
你要移动
bar number three yes if you're this hard
第三条酒吧，如果你这么硬的话，是的。
driving entrepreneur who's putting that
这位企业家正在为此努力。
aside I'm dead serious when I say get a
抛开其他不说，我说“弄一个”可不是开玩笑。
dog a cat whatever your preferred animal
狗、猫，或者你喜欢的任何动物
is and the data show that having a pet
数据显示，养宠物
actually makes people quite happy and I
实际上，这让人非常开心，而且
very mindfully did it when I was a brand
当我还是个品牌的时候，我非常用心去做这件事。
new assistant professor you know in this
你认识的这位新来的助理教授
American System I'm going to either get
美国体系，我打算要么接受
tenured and promoted after seven years
七年后获得终身教职并晋升
or I'm going to get fired so I knew that
否则我就要被解雇了，所以我知道这一点。
I was a work machine for seven years
我做了七年的工作机器
everything else was going to take second
其他一切都要等到第二步。
place but my dog wouldn't care dogs are
地方，但我的狗不在乎，狗是
amazing um and maybe one day as you were
太棒了，嗯，也许有一天，就像你一样。
talking I was thinking maybe people are
说话的时候我在想，也许人们是
going to get robots someday and that's a
总有一天我们会拥有机器人，那是一种
sad fure think about but just like a
悲伤的毛皮想到，但就像
robot generally to be their friend which
机器人通常会成为他们的朋友
is quite Grim number four
第四名相当惨烈
so when you ask yourself well what made
所以，当你问自己是什么造就了这一切时，你就会明白我的意思了。
our our ancestors happy there's a lot
我们的祖先很高兴有很多东西。
of seemingly pointless sitting around
看似毫无意义的闲坐
and doing doing nothing together and the
一起什么也不做，以及
problem with our world today I believe
我认为，当今世界存在着一个问题。
but don't know I don't have good data on
但我不知道，我没有这方面的可靠数据。
this is Bill's intuition is that we can
比尔的直觉是，我们可以
always be doing something there's a t
总是要做点什么，总会有一件事。
zillion actually very good shows on TV
电视上其实有很多非常精彩的节目。
and I suspect that what we giving up
我怀疑我们放弃的是什么
when when doing that is is random
这样做的时候是随机的
chitchat with friends now when I used to
现在我和朋友们闲聊，而以前……
walk by construction sites 20 years ago
20年前路过建筑工地
you'd see all these guys eating their
你会看到这些人都在吃他们的
lunch together and and just shooting the
一起吃午饭，然后就拍些照片。
[__] right just having a good time when
妈的，玩得真开心
I walk by construction sites today
今天我路过了一些建筑工地。
during lunch I see most of the guys on
午餐时间我看到大部分男生都在……
their phone not even talking to the guy
他们的手机甚至都没跟那个人通话。
right next to them they're still sitting
他们就坐在他们旁边。
in a line at the construction site but
在建筑工地排成一列，但
they're not engaged with each other and
他们之间没有互动，
those guys are not as tight and their
那些家伙关系没那么密切，而且
job is not going to be as good and so I
这份工作不会像以前那么好了，所以我
would say be present be be present in
会说要出席，要出席在
idle conversation times it it doesn't
闲聊时间，它不会。
seem as interesting as it is it's super
看起来很有趣，而且确实很棒
important and number five last but not
重要且第五点是最后但并非
least I would say and this is going to
至少我会这么说，而且这将会……
sound a little bit redundant but but we
听起来有点多余，但是我们
all have lifestyle goals that we Su and
我们苏和所有人都有各自的生活方式目标
they could be getting more fit they
他们可能会变得更健康
could be learning a foreign language
可能是在学习外语
they could be learning to paint they
他们可能正在学习绘画
could be anything like that the data
数据可能类似于上述任何内容。
show very clearly you're way more likely
非常清楚地表明你更有可能
to achieve those lifestyle goals if you
为了实现这些生活方式目标，如果你
commit to doing them with somebody else
承诺与其他人一起完成这些事情
because they'll push you and you'll push
因为他们会逼你，你也会逼他们。
them people join gyms every year that
每年都有很多人加入健身房。
they attend five times and never go back
他们去了五次，之后再也没有去过。
and so you want to whenever you want to
所以你想什么时候做都可以。
make a change in your life try to use
改变你的生活，尝试使用
connection to make that change more
建立联系以促成这种改变
effective because not only will it make
有效的原因不仅在于它能使
the change more effective but it'll
这种改变更有效，但它会
overall in the long term make you a
从长远来看，这会让你成为一个
happier person and on that point about
更快乐的人，以及关于这一点的
Health Fitness and lifestyle goals um I
健康、健身和生活方式目标嗯
found out that you are a senior
发现您是位长者。
scientist at a company that I'm an
我在一家公司担任科学家
investor in called whoop they also are
投资者被称为 Whoop，他们也是
sponsor of the podcast I should probably
我应该赞助这个播客。
say but you're a senior scientist there
比如说，但你是那里的资深科学家。
that's well I'm a contractor I don't
好吧，我是个承包商，我没有
work directly for them but they've
直接为他们工作，但他们已经
contracted me to to work with them
他们与我签订了合同，让我为他们工作。
that's right and what is it you're doing
没错，那你到底在干什么？
at whoop I have the coolest job in the
我在 Whoop 有一份超酷的工作。
world so I work as part of the
所以我作为世界的一部分工作
performance science team and what we're
绩效科学团队以及我们所做的事情
tasked to do is just look at all the
任务就是查看所有
data that whoop collects and ask the
Whoop收集并询问的数据
question how could we do it better what
问题：我们如何才能做得更好？
are things that are people are doing
是人们正在做的事情
that really help them let them know how
这真的能帮助他们了解如何
much it's helping them what are people
它对他们有多大帮助？人们是什么？
do things that people are doing that
做人们正在做的事情
maybe aren't helping them let them know
也许这样做并不能帮助他们了解情况。
that it's not helping and more so let's
这样做没有帮助，而且我们更应该这样做。
you know sleep is not well understood
你知道，睡眠问题还没有被充分理解。
exercise is not well understood this
人们对这种运动的理解还不够透彻。
relationship to eating is not well
与饮食的关系不太好
understood you'll have learned that from
明白了，你会从中学到这一点
lots of guests prior previously on the
之前有很多客人
show and so I get this really cool job
参加节目后，我得到了这份非常棒的工作。
where we just dive into our data all the
我们直接深入研究所有数据
time to try to answer these fundamental
是时候尝试回答这些基本问题了。
questions and what are some of the cool
问题以及一些很酷的
questions you've asked that have
你提出的问题已经
garnered interesting answers thus far so
目前为止已经收集到了一些有趣的答案。
these aren't published data yet and so
这些数据尚未公布，因此
what that means the caveat on them is
这意味着其中的注意事项是：
that we could be wrong right I could be
我们可能错了，对吧？我可能错了。
telling you stuff that I'm going to send
告诉你一些我要寄的东西
it to a journal and they're going to
把它写进期刊，他们打算
laugh in my face and saying you're
当面嘲笑我，还说你是
forgetting the fosic effect that total
忘记了总的磷酸盐效应
that's total nonsense right that could
那完全是胡说八道，对吧？
happen so going with you have to
所以，如果发生这种情况，你就得跟着去。
understand the caveat here that these
这里需要注意的是，这些
are raw data that we've just discovered
这是我们刚刚发现的原始数据。
that we haven't vetted yet in the
我们尚未在……中进行审查
scientific Community but let me give you
科学界，但让我告诉你
an example one of the quite remarkable
一个相当引人注目的例子。
things that we're finding is at woop is
我们在woop上发现的东西是
that exercise amplifies other behaviors
这种锻炼会放大其他行为。
and so if I do something that's good for
所以如果我做了对……有好处的事情
me even if it's got nothing to do with
即使这跟我无关，我也……
exercise and I exercise that day it's
那天我锻炼了。
better for me if I do something that's
如果我做一些对我更有利的事情，那就是
bad for me and even if it's got nothing
对我不好，即使它什么都没有
to do with exercise it's worse for me on
就运动而言，我的情况更糟。
a day that I exercise give me an example
我锻炼的那一天，请举个例子。
yeah so if I drink we know that alcohol
是的，所以如果我喝酒，我们都知道酒精
every every drink every alcoholic drink
每一杯酒，每一杯酒精饮料
that I have raises my resting heart rate
它会提高我的静息心率
by I think it's about a beat beat and a
我觉得它跟节拍和……有关
half if I remember right and lowers my
如果我没记错的话，一半，而且降低了我的
HRV by uh like three points if I
如果我 HRV 提高大约 3 个点的话
remember right I could be getting those
记住，我可能会得到那些
numbers a little bit off but it's that
数字有点偏差，但就是这样。
kind of magnitude and every drink just
某种程度，而且每杯饮料都如此
it's this linear effect up to at least
这种线性效应至少在一定程度上是存在的。
10 drinks that we see that in our data
我们在数据中看到了10种饮品
with thousands and thousands of people
成千上万的人
if you have those drinks on days that
如果你在那些日子里喝那些饮料的话
you're basically sedentary you did
你基本上是久坐不动的，你确实如此。
almost nothing their effect is smaller
几乎没有什么能比这更甚，它们的影响更小。
than if you have those drinks on days
如果你在那些日子里喝那些饮料的话……
where you exercised so I could exercise
你在哪里锻炼，这样我也可以锻炼
in the morning then I drink Y and the
早上我喝Y，然后
impact of the drink is worse yeah
是的，这种饮料的影响更严重。
because I EXC you exercised and the same
因为我非常欣赏你锻炼，而且也一样。
holds for good things I know it's
我知道这其中蕴含着美好的意义。
ridiculous I don't understand the
荒谬至极，我不明白。
physiology at all but this is what we're
虽然我们完全不了解生理学，但这就是我们正在做的。
seeing so drink and don't exercise
既然如此，那就喝酒，别运动。
exactly on days that you're going to
正好在你打算去的那些日子里
misbehave and probably not just alcohol
行为不端，而且可能不仅仅是酒精。
that's just one of the ones I've
这只是我拥有的其中一个例子。
analyzed on days that you're going to
分析日期取决于您将要去的地方
misbehave be relatively sedentary now
现在行为不端，相对来说比较久坐不动
the thing is it also works the other way
问题是，反过来也一样有效
so if you like if you sometimes wear
所以如果你喜欢，如果你偶尔会穿
blue light blocking glasses late in the
蓝光阻隔眼镜在后期
evening or you dim the lights late in
傍晚或深夜，你调暗了灯光。
the evening you're conscientious about
你认真对待的那个夜晚
getting ready for bed that has a bigger
准备睡觉，床更大
posit positive effect on your recovery
对你的康复有积极影响
on days that you exercise even though
即使在你锻炼的日子里
blue light and exercise have nothing to
蓝光和运动无关
do with each other so it doesn't seem to
彼此配合，所以看起来不像是
matter what the behavior is if it's
无论行为是什么，只要它是……
positive it has a bigger positive effect
积极的一面是，它具有更大的积极影响。
on days you exercise more if it's
如果你在运动量较大的日子里……
negative it has a bigger negative effect
负面影响更大
on days you exercise more interesting
锻炼的日子更有趣
which is super cool I have no idea why
这太酷了，我也不知道为什么。
we we're obviously going to write it up
我们当然会把它写下来。
and tell the world about it and when we
并告诉全世界，当我们
do maybe I made a mistake and we'll
也许我犯了个错误，我们会
discover what I did wrong and what I
找出我做错的地方以及我
just told you isn't true but for now I
刚才跟你说的不是真的，但现在我
believe that's true so if I'm having
我相信这是真的，所以如果我有
a bit of like a naughty day you know if
有点像放纵的一天，你知道吗？
I'm like breaking all my rules don't
我好像要打破我所有的规则，别这样
exercise
锻炼
interesting and then if I'm having a
有趣，然后如果我正在经历……
great day like I'm I'm eating really
今天真是美好的一天，我吃得好开心。
really healthy and everything's going
身体非常健康，一切都很顺利。
I'm sleeping well here's the thing
我睡得很好，事情是这样的。
eating might be the exception the data
饮食或许是数据的一个例外
also show that if you like imagine you
也表明，如果你喜欢想象你
stuff your face full of fatty foods and
狼吞虎咽地吃大量高脂肪食物
all that kind of stuff exercise is
所有这些锻炼都是
exactly what you should be doing now
这正是你现在应该做的
after you ate use the fuel you you
吃完饭后，你利用了你体内的能量。
process don't just store it and so
处理过程不仅仅是存储它，所以
food is something we need too much food
我们对食物的需求量太大了。
is obviously a bad thing but I don't
这显然是件坏事，但我并不这么认为。
count food in the naughty Behavior list
将食物计入淘气行为清单中
and so I I haven't actually Everybody
所以，我其实并没有……
Eats every day and I don't have good
每天都吃饭，但我吃得不好。
data on how much they've eaten but what
数据包括他们吃了多少东西，但是什么
I what our data do suggest is that going
我们的数据表明，去
for a walk even just a walk like zone
即使只是散步，比如在区域内散步。
two is fabulous even Zone one is good
二区很棒，一区也不错。
going for a walk doing stuff after you
出去散步，做些事情，然后……
eat helps you just feel better and and
吃东西能让你感觉更好，而且
I'm guessing here that what you saw in
我猜你在这里看到的是……
the data is you you could look at
你可以查看这些数据。
someone who is drinking alcohol every
一个经常喝酒的人
day for example
例如，白天
and then you could see on the days that
然后你就能看到那些日子里的情况了。
they exercised as well the impact of the
他们也锻炼了这种影响
alcohol on their biomarkers was more
酒精对其生物标志物的影响更大
significant yes and what we what we have
是的，意义重大，我们拥有什么。
is fortunately we got thousands and
幸运的是，我们得到了成千上万个。
thousands of people so big data sets who
成千上万的人，所以大数据集
log alcohol relatively often they don't
他们不太经常记录饮酒情况
drink every day and I can even show you
每天喝水，我甚至可以给你看。
what the pattern looks like people don't
人们看不出这种模式是什么样子
drink much Monday Tuesday Wednesday
周一、周二、周三喝很多酒
Thursday they have a drink or two you
星期四他们会喝一两杯。
know Friday more Saturday and Sunday
周五了解更多关于周六和周日的信息
more and then go back but they also
更多，然后再回去，但他们也
exercise at different points across the
在不同时间点进行锻炼
weekend so some people those two things
周末，所以有些人会做这两件事。
happen hit at the same time and
同时发生并受到攻击
sometimes they they don't and what I try
有时候他们不这样做，而我尝试过
to do in these analyses what we all try
在这些分析中，我们都要努力做到我们都在尝试做的事情。
to do in these analyses is look within
这些分析要做的就是审视内部。
person because if you're the kind of
人，因为如果你是那种人
person who exercises when you drink and
喝酒时锻炼的人
I'm not well who knows what else differs
我身体不舒服，谁知道还有什么不同之处。
between us so what I really want to know
我们之间，所以我真正想知道的是
is what does Steven look like when he
史蒂文长什么样？
drinks two drinks on days that he also
他每天喝两杯酒
exercis the same as usual less than
锻炼方式与往常相同，但少于
usual more than usual we want to make it
我们比平时更想做到这一点
all against what you usually do and
这一切都与你通常的做法截然相反
there we see these effects very clearly
在那里，我们可以非常清楚地看到这些影响。
are there any other cool answers you've
你还有其他很棒的答案吗？
discovered in your time at weep you know
你在哭泣的时候发现的你知道
if you look at how much sleep people
如果你看看人们的睡眠时间，就会发现他们睡眠时间的长短。
need the argument is everybody needs the
论点是每个人都需要
same basically on average right but some
平均而言基本相同，对吧，但有些
people need a little less and some
人们需要的少一些，还有一些
people need a little more I think men
我认为人们需要多一些男性。
need less sleep than
需要的睡眠时间比
women I don't know that yet but there's
我还不认识女性，但确实有。
lots of reasons to think that first of
有很多理由认为，首先……
all hunted gathers when you look at the
当你审视所有狩猎采集者时……
data they've gathered with actograph
他们利用活动记录仪收集的数据
where they where they put a motion
他们在哪里提出了动议
capture on hunted gathers the men sleep
猎物被捕后，人们聚集在一起睡觉
about 20 minutes less than the women do
比女性少用大约20分钟
now that's not significant in their
现在这对他们来说并不重要。
samples because they have small samples
因为样本量小，所以需要进行样本抽样。
of un gathers when we put these thing on
当我们把这些东西放上去的时候，它们就会聚集在一起。
zillions of people we see men sleep
我们看到无数男人睡觉
about 20 minutes less than women do when
比女性少大约20分钟
you put the whoop on yeah and so we see
你把欢呼声加进去，然后我们就看到了
the exact same thing they see but it's
他们看到的是完全一样的东西，但那又是……
wildly statistically significant our
具有极强的统计学意义
data set because it's so huge 20 minutes
数据集非常庞大，需要20分钟。
is a lot now here's the thing if men
现在有很多事情，关键在于男人
don't need as much sleep as women why is
为什么男性需要的睡眠时间比女性少？
that the case so recently now this hot
最近这个案子非常火爆。
off the press I can't promise you I'm
刚印出来，我不能向你保证我会
doing it right but I believe I am our
我正在努力做好，但我相信我是我们的
data suggests men sleep more impactfully
数据显示男性睡眠质量更好。
more effectively than women that for
比女性更有效
every hour of sleep that a man gets he
一个人每睡一个小时，他
gets a little more bang for the buck on
花同样的钱，能获得更多收益
his recovery than women get I have no
他的康复比女人得到的更多，我没有
idea why that might be it could be they
或许这就是原因。
have bigger slow ways when they're in
当它们处于……时，它们会以更大的速度前进。
slow way sleep it could be a thousand
慢速睡眠可能是一千
different things I don't know but what
我不知道的是其他一些事情，但是……
what my data suggests is that men get
我的数据显示，男性更容易获得
more bang for the buck out of every hour
每一小时都物超所值
sleep and as a consequence they sleep
睡眠，结果他们就睡着了
about 20 minutes less that's right off
大约少20分钟，没错。
the press I I can't even promise you
媒体，我甚至无法向你保证
that holds up if I it holds up I've
如果我没记错的话，那也成立。
looked at it in two samples but I could
我看了两个样本，但我可以
be making a mistake I I want to play
犯错 我想玩
with it more I am I was just I just did
有了它，我更像我，我刚才就是我做了
some research as you explaining that
正如你解释的那样，一些研究也表明
also really interesting finding or
也是非常有趣的发现或
hypothesis um on the previous one which
假设是前一个假设，
is about why if I if I drank alcohol on
是关于如果我喝酒的话……
a day when I exercised it would cause my
我锻炼的那一天会导致我的
biomarkers to have a reflect a worse
生物标志物反映出更糟糕的情况
sort of state and it says on days when
某种状态，上面写着在某些日子里
you both drink alcohol and exercise the
你们俩都喝酒，也都锻炼。
com the combined psychological stresses
综合心理压力
can lead to alterations in your
可能导致你的身体发生改变
biomarkers reflecting increased
反映增加的生物标志物
oxidative stress liver strain
氧化应激引起的肝脏损伤
dehydration and inflammation
脱水和炎症
in contrast on days when you consume
相反，在你食用食物的日子里……
alcohol without exercising these effects
饮酒而不产生这些影响
might be less pronounced resulting in
可能不太明显，导致
different biomarker profiles this is
这是不同的生物标志物谱。
super possible yeah it's it's very
完全有可能，是的，非常有可能。
possible that could be the mechanism uh
这或许就是其机制。
the it could be all about hydration and
这可能都与补水有关。
so all you got to do is be doubly
所以你只需要加倍努力。
conscientious about hydrating and then
认真做好补水工作，然后
problem solved but here's the thing
问题解决了，但还有一点。
every negative thing I've looked at has
我所看到的每一个负面因素都……
gotten worse when it's um when you
当情况变得更糟的时候，嗯，当你
exercise and every positive thing I've
锻炼以及我所做的每一件积极的事情
looked at it's gotten better so it may
看起来情况有所好转，所以可能
be as simple as as something very
可以像某件非常简单的事情一样简单
specific with alcohol and exercise but
具体来说，与酒精和运动有关，但
it may be there's a broader principle at
或许存在一个更广泛的原则。
play and so somebody out there who's
玩游戏，所以总会有人在外面玩。
super smart like triers came along and
像尝试者这样超级聪明的人出现了，
lined up how every animal mating system
排列出每种动物的交配系统
worked he says look here's how it works
他说，这招管用。你看，它是这样运作的。
females make the larger sex cell they
雌性会产生较大的性细胞。
typically then put more effort into it
通常情况下，他们会投入更多精力。
so males compete for females and then lo
所以雄性会竞争雌性，然后……
and behold you see that across the
瞧，你会看到，在……的另一端
animal kingdom and the rare exceptions
动物王国及其罕见例外
where males put more effort now the
现在男性投入了更多精力
females compete for the males so you
雌性之间会争夺雄性，所以你
know somebody's going to come along
我知道会有人过来。
super smart and they'll hear what I just
他们非常聪明，而且他们会听到我刚才说的话
said and they go I know the answers to
他们说，然后他们就走了，我知道答案
that but I don't know and the beauty is
但我不知道，而美在于……
that when a when I hear a scientific
当我听到一个科学的声音时
explanation that Nails it I immediately
解释说，钉子立刻就……
go Oh that's it and I wish I thought of
哦，原来是这样，我真希望我早点想到。
it but at least I can see that they'
虽然如此，但至少我能看到他们
they've got the answer when I you know
他们知道答案，你知道的。
didn't is there anything else one last
没有了，还有最后一个问题吗？
thing from your work as a senior
你作为资深人士的工作经历
scientist at whoop that is intriguing to
Whoop公司的一位科学家，这很有意思
you or any hypothesis you have that
你或你提出的任何假设
you're discovering from the data well so
你正在从数据中发现很多东西，所以
we're seeing lots of nice evidence of a
我们看到了很多确凿的证据表明……
couple different things first of all
首先是两件事。
there's a lot of little things that help
有很多小事都能有所帮助。
a lot and I'm a big believer in lots of
很多，而且我非常相信很多
little things helping a lot but they
小事也能起到很大的作用，但它们
have to suit you because we also find
必须适合您，因为我们也发现
huge individual variability on how well
个体差异巨大，表现也各不相同。
they work so reading in bed on average
它们确实有效，所以平均而言，在床上阅读是可行的。
actually not only helps you sleep fall
实际上，它不仅能帮助你入睡。
asleep more regularly but even helps you
睡眠更规律，甚至对你也有帮助
sleep longer I suspect but don't know
我怀疑她睡得更久，但我不确定。
that you're clearing your mind of the
你正在清空你的思绪。
day's
天
worries that probably works for some
这种担忧可能对某些人来说有效。
people but some people probably works
有些人可能工作
the opposite like now they get caught up
正好相反，现在他们被卷入其中了。
in the novel they're reading and they
在他们正在读的小说里，他们
can't sleep so you have to be super
睡不着，所以你必须超级厉害
thoughtful about what works for you CBD
认真思考哪些CBD产品适合你
works really well but it actually works
效果非常好，而且确实有效
for some people really well and for
对某些人来说真的很好，而且
others it even has a negative effect you
对其他人来说，它甚至会产生负面影响。
know our samples are big enough that we
我们知道我们的样本足够大，因此我们
can see across the board we find things
可以看出，我们在各方面都发现了一些东西。
like uh a weighted blanket um blue light
就像……一条加重毯……蓝光
blockers in the evening dimming your
晚上使用遮光罩可以调暗您的灯光
lights in the evening those are big they
晚上那些灯光很大
have big effects across the course of
在整个过程中产生重大影响
the night by big I mean like 15 20
我说的“大夜晚”是指像15到20晚那样。
minutes and more sleep more time and REM
睡眠时间更长，快速眼动睡眠也更多
and slow wave you add all those things
慢波，你把所有这些加进去。
together it ends up being a lot wow the
加在一起，结果真是令人惊叹。
final thing that we find is a lot of
最后我们发现的是很多
people have sleep worries you know they
人们都有睡眠问题，你知道的。
worry they won't sleep well and the
担心他们睡不好觉
downside of that is that if you have
缺点是，如果你有
sleep worries what ends up happening is
睡眠问题最终导致的结果是
they they get produced by your poor
它们是由你贫穷的人生产的。
sleep like I think GE I'm gonna have
睡得像我想GE一样，我将会拥有
trouble falling asleep because lo and
因为lo而难以入睡
behold I did but then when we analyze
我确实做到了，但当我们分析时……
the data we've run these surveys where
我们开展这些调查所获得的数据是：
we ask what was your worry going into
我们问你进入这个阶段最担心的是什么
the night and and when you woke up in
夜里，当你醒来的时候
the morning how did it go and what role
早上情况如何？你扮演了什么角色？
did your worries play Etc and when we
你的担忧是否发挥了作用等等，以及当我们
disentangle it we see that the worries
理清思路后，我们发现这些担忧
start to cause their own problems they
他们开始自找麻烦
the worries themselves make it harder to
担忧本身会使事情变得更难。
sleep and so if you could find ways to
睡眠，所以如果你能找到方法
Short Circuit those worries again things
再次消除那些担忧
like reading in bed whatever it is to
就像在床上看书一样，不管是什么
get your mind elsewhere it's going to be
把注意力转移到别的地方，事情会……
beneficial is there much data on coffee
有很多关于咖啡的数据，这对咖啡有益吗？
and the impact that that has coffee
以及这对咖啡的影响
actually overall is not bad you don't
其实总体来说还不错，你不会的
want to do it too late in the day and
想在一天中最晚的时候做这件事，而且时间太晚了。
some people can I have friends who can
有些人可以，我有一些朋友可以。
drink a coffee at dinner and go right to
晚餐时喝杯咖啡，然后直接去
sleep so it's not everybody but some
睡眠问题并非人人都会遇到，但有些人确实会遇到。
people after 2 p.m. it can be pretty
下午2点以后的人它可以很漂亮
disrupted for some people and what we'd
对某些人来说，这造成了干扰，而我们……
also advise is when you're eating try to
另一个建议是，当你吃饭时尽量
restrict that to daylight hours that
仅限白天进行
seems to make a big difference it's you
似乎这会产生很大的影响，是你。
know your body you're trying to get
了解你想要拥有的身体
parasympathetic dominance when you go to
当你去……时，副交感神经占主导地位
sleep and if you've got food in there
睡觉，如果里面有食物的话。
your body's working hard to digest it
你的身体正在努力消化它。
and that makes it difficult
这就造成了困难。
what's the most important thing in your
你认为最重要的是什么？
book The Social Paradox when finding
读《社会悖论》这本书时发现
what you want means losing what you need
你想要的东西意味着失去你真正需要的东西。
that we haven't talked about that is
我们还没谈到的是……
important for someone who's listening
对于正在听的人来说，这一点很重要
that wants to improve their life and
想要改善自己生活的人
increase their probability of Happiness
提高他们获得幸福的概率
so the last thing I would say is that we
最后我想说的是，我们
haven't covered is that all right so I'm
还没提到，这样可以吗？所以我……
arguing you need to increase your
认为你需要增加你的
sociality and I'm arguing that your
社交性，而我认为你的
socialness you need to be more social
社交能力：你需要更善于社交。
more connected and I'm arguing that
联系更加紧密，我认为
we're too autonomous but that's a big
我们过于自主，但这却是一个很大的问题。
ask and I remember reading this article
问了，我记得读过这篇文章。
in the New York Times about this guy he
《纽约时报》上关于这个人的报道
wrote an opad piece about her he decided
他决定写一篇关于她的文章。
to reconnect with all of his old friends
与他所有的老朋友重新建立联系
and so he's calling them up and finding
所以他给他们打电话，然后发现
them and they're getting together and
他们聚在一起，
then he ends up by saying am I going to
最后他问：“我要……”
keep this up every week no I just don't
每周都这样做？不，我做不到。
have time and and that's really really
有时间，而且这真的非常非常重要
an important lesson that we lead these
我们领导这些团队的重要教训是：
busy lives that are not the same as
忙碌的生活与此不同
Hunter gathers we have so many things
狩猎采集者拥有很多东西
that we can do and are meant to be doing
我们能做到而且应该做到的事
that we can't just introduce social and
我们不能仅仅引入社交和
social connection and into our life
社会联系融入我们的生活
willy-nilly or we won't keep it up we
不管怎样，否则我们不会坚持下去。
have to be Socratic and know yourself
必须具备苏格拉底式的思维方式，并且了解自己。
and know your weaknesses and know what
了解自己的弱点，并知道什么
you're going to sustain and what you're
你会坚持下去，而你就是
not and from from from my perspective
不，而且从我的角度来看
that means two things one trying to say
这意味着两件事，其中一件是想表达的。
well whenever I do something alone that
每当我独自做某事的时候
I'm doing something I enjoy like maybe
我在做一些我喜欢的事情，比如……
the crossword puzzle or running or
填字游戏或跑步或
whatever your thing is is there a way to
无论你的兴趣是什么，有没有办法……
do that with others don't you know match
对其他人也这样做，你不知道吗？
my connection need with my autonomy need
我的联系需求与我的自主需求
I want to do that that's my autonomy
我想做这件事，这是我的自主权。
speaking but are there others who want
我正在发言，但还有其他人想发言吗？
to do what who I can do with so in my
我能和谁一起做我所能做的事情，所以在我的
case I love to do the New York Times
我喜欢做《纽约时报》的案例
puzzle my sister lives in London so we
我姐姐住在伦敦，所以我们……
reconnect in a way that we just weren't
以一种我们以前从未有过的方式重新建立联系
doing before because we're both busy but
因为我们俩都很忙，所以之前就做了，但是
we're both doing the puzzle anyway so
反正我们俩都要拼这个拼图，所以
why not do that if you have to decide to
如果必须做出决定，为什么不这样做呢？
do something every single time you do it
每次做这件事的时候都做点什么。
you just won't do it you want to
你就是不愿意做你想做的事。
surrender control of that
放弃对该项的控制权
decision-making process to either your
决策过程，无论您选择哪一方
past or to the environment Itself by
过去或对环境本身
which I mean in the same way that we say
我的意思是，就像我们说的那样
I'll brush my teeth after breakfast we
我早餐后会刷牙。
don't say I wonder if I should brush my
别说我在想我是否应该刷牙
teeth today we just know I eat breakfast
如今，我们都知道我吃早餐，牙齿也变得很漂亮。
then I brush you want to do the same
然后我刷牙，你也想这样做吗？
thing oh after after breakfast I'll call
早餐后我会打电话
my sister and we'll do the puzzle
我和我妹妹会一起拼拼图
together you want a set rule so you
你们想要制定一套规则，所以你们
don't have to decide to do it and then
不必先决定是否去做，然后
these things become habit and so what I
这些事情会变成习惯，那又怎样呢？
want what I want to argue is that people
我想论证的是，人们
should reintroduce Connection by trying
应该尝试重新引入连接。
not to do things alone but they should
不要独自行动，但他们应该
do it in the easiest way possible in the
用最简单的方式完成这件事
way that's most likely become habitual
这很可能已经成为一种习惯。
and that doesn't actually add more time
而且这实际上并不会增加更多时间。
to their busy day and it's surprisingly
在他们忙碌的一天中，这令人惊讶
doable William thank you we have a
可行，威廉，谢谢你，我们有
closing tradition on this podcast where
本播客的结尾传统是……
the last guest leaves a question for the
最后一位客人留下了一个问题。
next guest uh oh not knowing who they're
下一位客人，呃哦，不知道他们是谁。
leaving it for
留着
and so this question is going to come
所以这个问题即将到来。
out of left field probably yeah you're
出乎意料，大概是吧？
given the chance plus the power to do
如果有机会并且有能力去做……
one thing to save Humanity plus make
拯救人类的一件事加上
everyone happy what would that be if I
大家都开心了，如果我……那会是什么样子？
had one chance to do one thing to save
只剩一次机会做一件事来拯救自己
Humanity to save Humanity I would and
为了拯救人类，我愿意这样做。
I'm magic right I can make it whatever I
我是魔法师，对吧？我可以把它变成任何我想要的样子。
want if you want um I would make sure
如果你想的话，我会确保
that there's perfect
那里有完美
Justice because if there's perfect
正义，因为如果存在完美的话
Justice then everybody who misbehaves
正义将降临到所有行为不端的人身上。
does Wrong by somebody else it knows
它对别人做了错事，它知道
that they're going to get that there'll
他们会得到那个。
be consequences for that behavior
该行为将承担相应后果
because I think that the one thing that
因为我认为有一件事
humanity is not going to get its way out
人类终将无法摆脱困境。
of is people being horrible to other
就是人们对待他人很残忍。
people but if there's perfect Justice
但如果存在完美的正义，人们就会明白。
everybody who's horrible to somebody
所有对别人很坏的人
else is going to get their and it
否则就会到达那里，而且
doesn't I don't mean Justice when you
难道我指的不是正义吗？
die I mean Justice in real time they're
我的意思是，在现实生活中，他们正在走向正义。
going to stop doing that and people will
停止这样做，人们就会
just be better to each other what what
彼此善待一点，怎么样？
would be the cost of that because that's
那就是成本，因为那是
always a cost right the the cost of that
总是有成本的，对吧？那就是成本。
is that well look you can't get away
是这样的，你逃不掉的。
with anything anymore I I get away with
现在我做什么事都能逃脱惩罚
a lot of little things like I speed all
很多小事，比如我加速所有
the time and I do it because I know I
时间到了，我这么做是因为我知道我
can get away with it um and I like doing
可以侥幸逃脱惩罚，嗯，而且我喜欢这样做。
that and but but I think that perfect
那个，但是，但是我觉得那很完美
Justice would have the advantage that
正义将拥有以下优势：
it's harm to others see in the past we
过去我们目睹了对他人造成的伤害
we cared about property crimes a lot and
我们非常重视财产犯罪，
not so much harm to others I would want
我希望不要对他人造成那么大的伤害。
in this world that it's that perfect
在这个如此完美的世界里
Justice comes with harm to others okay
正义的实现往往会对他人造成伤害，这没问题。
but with Justice there's a subjective
但正义是有主观性的
element right to what is just because if
元素右于什么，仅仅因为如果
you look back through history what we
回顾历史，我们
thought true absolutely right and so the
认为这是完全正确的，所以
cost might be getting hit missing the
成本可能会因为错过而受到影响
Mark we might we might as a human
马克，我们或许会，我们或许会作为一个人
population today come up with a
当今人口提出了
consensual decision about what Justice
就正义问题达成共识的决定
is that a thousand years from now they
那是一千年后的事吗？
look back and they're utterly appalled
回首往事，他们感到无比震惊。
that that was what we were doing which
这就是我们当时正在做的事情，
is what we look we look back at 200
这就是我们回顾200年的情况。
years and go Justice what the [__] yeah
多年过去，正义何在？真是见鬼了！
what the hell was that thank you so much
那到底是什么鬼东西？非常感谢！
William thank you for writing an
威廉，谢谢你写了这篇文章。
incredible book um your first book here
这本书太棒了，嗯，这是你的第一本书。
called the social leap was a Smash Hit
这部名为《社交飞跃》的剧集一炮而红。
and it's an extraordinary book but this
这是一本非凡的书，但是……
book is exceptional and it's
这本书非常出色，而且
exceptionally timed
时机绝佳
I think that has to be said because
我觉得必须说明这一点，因为
where the world is at the moment it
世界目前所处的位置
feels like we're all we're drifting to
感觉我们就像在漂流，最终都会到达某个地方。
some degree it feels like we're drifting
某种程度上，感觉我们像是在随波逐流。
from the the the island where our tribe
来自我们部落所在的岛屿
are and we're getting further and
是的，而且我们正在取得进展，
further away from knowing exactly what
离确切知道什么越来越远了
it is to be human um I think we're
身为人类，嗯，我想我们是
feeling the consequences of that if you
如果你感受到了后果，你就会明白
look at a lot of the data we're feeling
看看我们感受到的很多数据。
we had the Mental Health crisis around
我们当时正经历着一场心理健康危机。
the world the increase in suicidal
世界范围内自杀率上升
ideation and suicide the increase in
自杀意念和自杀倾向的增加
purposelessness the increase in opioid
无目标感；阿片类药物滥用增加
addictions and things like that and I I
成瘾之类的东西，还有我
don't think anybody would could could
我不认为任何人会这样做。
make the case in a way that's founded on
以基于以下事实的方式提出论点：
what we're seeing that we're any closer
我们看到的情况是，我们离目标更近了一步。
to being human or whatever that means
成为人类，或者说，这意味着什么？
than we've ever been and this book I
比以往任何时候都更甚，而这本书我
think helps us to of course correct it
思考当然有助于我们纠正它。
helps us to understand it turns the
帮助我们理解它如何转变
lights on and as it says on the front it
灯亮着，正如正面所说……
helps us to understand that there's this
这有助于我们理解存在这种情况。
important balance between autonomy and
自主性和重要平衡之间
connection and we need both of them but
连接，我们需要两者兼备，但是
we need to get the balance correct and
我们需要把平衡调整好，
many of us including myself no deep
包括我在内的许多人都没有深入研究过这个问题。
inside that maybe we're not getting that
也许我们内心深处并没有明白这一点。
balance correct and this is why this
平衡正确，这就是为什么
book is so wonderful because it's
这本书太棒了，因为它……
confronting in the nicest possible way
以最友好的方式进行沟通
and in an important way so I highly
而且从某种重要意义上来说，我非常……
recommend everybody give it a read it's
推荐大家读一读，它……
called the social Paradox when finding
当发现时，它被称为社会悖论。
what you want means losing what you need
你想要的东西意味着失去你真正需要的东西。
by William Von
威廉·冯
hippo thanks Stephen I really enjoy
河马谢谢斯蒂芬，我真的很喜欢
chatting with you about it I can't wait
我迫不及待地想和你聊聊这件事。
I can't wait for people to read it and
我迫不及待地想让大家读到它。
to send me lots of messages thank you so
非常感谢你给我发了这么多信息。
much appreciate you thank you totally my
非常感谢，真的非常感谢。
pleasure this has always blown my mind a
这真是太棒了，一直让我惊叹不已。
little bit 53 % of you that listen to
略有不同，53% 的人听过
the show regularly haven't yet
该节目通常还没有播出。
subscribed to the show so could I ask
我订阅了该节目，所以可以问一下吗？
you for a favor if you like the show and
如果你喜欢这个节目，就请你帮个忙吧。
you like what we do here and you want to
你喜欢我们在这里做的事情，并且你想……
support us the free simple way that you
您支持我们的方式很简单，而且完全免费。
can do just that is by hitting the
做到这一点的方法就是点击
Subscribe button and my commitment to
订阅按钮以及我对订阅的承诺
you is if you do that then I'll do
如果你那样做，那我也会那样做。
everything in my power me and my team to
我和我的团队将竭尽全力
make sure that this show is better for
确保这个节目对……更好
you every single week we'll listen to
我们每周都会听你的节目。
your feedback we'll find the guests that
您的反馈将帮助我们找到合适的客人
you want me to speak to and we'll
你想让我跟谁谈谈，我们……
continue to do what we do thank you so
请继续做我们正在做的事情，谢谢。
much
很多
[Music]
[音乐]
oh
哦